<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'><title>Frank's Movie Log</title><subtitle>I'm not a great writer. Maybe not even a good one. But with practice I can be better.</subtitle><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/feed.xml' rel='self' /><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com' /><updated>2016-10-31T21:09:52-04:00</updated><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com</id><author><name>Frank Showalter</name></author><entry><title>67. Torso (1973) ★★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/torso-1973//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/torso-1973/</id><updated>2016-10-31</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/torso-1973/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Y_IbflpaJ_iIgxd1thi7OTYEH7xp1iHj-4VSR24Zf_hdegkTj4DiKnlsPbZDUSWau43K9mlO7qXu=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Torso&lt;/em&gt; executes a generic plot with panache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film takes place in scenic Perugia, Italy. A masked killer strangles two female university students, sparking a manhunt. Another student thinks she recognizes the murder weapon, leading to threatening phone calls from the killer. Alarmed, she retreats to a cliff-side villa with four girlfriends, including an American exchange student, played by Suzy Kendall. The killer, of course, follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It plays as a mystery, inviting us to guess the killer’s identity. The script proffers a myriad of suspects, painting almost every male character as possessive, misogynistic, or perverted. The few that appear normal feel suspect by comparison. I admit, it fooled me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mystery aside, what I enjoyed most about &lt;em&gt;Torso&lt;/em&gt; was its style. There’s a scene where the killer tracks a girl through a swampy marsh. The lighting, camerawork, and editing create a kind of kinetic claustrophobia. The more she runs, the more her world shrinks. Even as the tension held me rapt, the sheer craft made me smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it gets better. The last act sees Kendall locked in a bedroom. She slides a piece of newspaper under the door, hoping to catch the key as she forces it out of the lock. I won&amp;#39;t spoil what happens, but I will say this scene caps twenty-some dialog-free minutes that serve as a master class in suspense. They&amp;#39;re so good, I forgave the finale, which sees the killer reveal his identity and explain his psychosis via some awkward and disappointing exposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only problem with &lt;em&gt;Torso&lt;/em&gt; lies with its heroines. I liked how the film paints them as strong, independent women. Fleeing to a remote outpost wasn&amp;#39;t the smartest move, but it was refreshing to see them do something besides run to the nearest man for protection. If only the script had provided them with distinct personalities. Aside from Kendall’s character, they felt interchangeable and never endeared themselves. It’s a common problem with mysteries. We learn more about the various red herrings than about the protagonists.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>66. The Pit (1981) ★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-pit-1981//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-pit-1981/</id><updated>2016-10-24</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-pit-1981/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/RWu-i9XAIElgsPF4HpQlnhdTYfxFpZP8rncZVWqoLYegY2CFhA4z3m181oKEfq5twCg1-2PXioSr=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pit&lt;/em&gt; careens between laughable and disturbing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We meet Jamie, a twelve-year-old boy transitioning to adolescence. He’s noticed girls and nudie-books, but still clings to his teddy bear. When his parents take a trip, Jamie develops a crush on the live-in babysitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a reasonable set-up for a coming-of-age comedy, but the script takes a different direction. Jamie’s teddy bear urges him to do things. Bad things, like watch his babysitter while she sleeps, or terrorize a neighbor into stripping nude as he snaps Polaroids, or frame a man for murder, or feed people to a pit of trolls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way the movie lumps the titular pit in with Jamie’s other deviations is part of its quirky charm. The troll effects look cheap, and the entire premise of luring people into a giant hole in the woods is silly. It’s as though the filmmakers knew they couldn’t make these bits scary, so they opted for weird. It works. Instead of a forgettable monster movie we get oddball schlock. And I love how obnoxious the film paints Jamie’s victims. Early on, Jamie, looking lonesome, approaches an older boy and girl. Jamie says little more than “Hi,” before the older boy punches him in the face. No reason, the boy’s just mean. When Jamie feeds him to the trolls, we’re not sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s another movie lurking beneath the inanity. A much darker one. Bits and pieces surface, like Jamie alluding to his mother molesting him, or the aforementioned scene where he watches his babysitter sleep. These scenes transcend the schlock and convey a genuine sense of unease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end, &lt;em&gt;The Pit&lt;/em&gt; is unlike anything I’ve seen. It’s not a good film, but its off-beat nature intrigues. You laugh as Jamie wheels an old biddy into the pit, then feel your skin crawl as he hits on his babysitter. It’s a wild ride.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>65. Phantasm (1979) ★★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/phantasm-1979//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/phantasm-1979/</id><updated>2016-10-17</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/phantasm-1979/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/IVL-n1s23XRh7rcJSbW0dd8L3wFqy6hiU7HbYF-bJg6XfZgWI7JOTI0XLhTRis5qXDs_3X5ShVAz=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was still watching Saturday morning cartoons and struggling with cursive writing when I first saw &lt;em&gt;Phantasm&lt;/em&gt;. It traumatized  me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s told from a kid’s point-of view. A boy who’s put away his toys but hasn&amp;#39;t yet discovered girls. His parents died a few months earlier in a car crash. Now, he follows his older brother everywhere. In the process, he uncovers some strange goings-on involving the local mortician, played by Angus Scrimm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love how writer-director Don Coscarelli avoids traditional plot tropes. When no one believes him, the kid breaks into the mortuary. After evading a lethal flying ball, he escapes with a gruesome piece of evidence. The next morning, he shows his older brother, who takes a single look and says, “Okay, I believe you.” A lesser film would see the boy lose the evidence during his escape, or have the older brother dismiss it with some awkward rationalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t reveal any more of the plot, as much of the film&amp;#39;s joy comes from the unexpected directions it takes. It plays like a surreal nightmare. Scenes feel disjointed. We often sense we’re missing something. These seeming plot holes only add to the film’s unrelenting sense of unease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it’s often lumped in with the slasher pictures that dominated early 80s horror, &lt;em&gt;Phantasm&lt;/em&gt; stands apart. It’s equal parts science fiction and dark fantasy. Take out the brief nudity and iconic chrome ball, and you&amp;#39;d have a PG-13 film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But about that ball. Those with squeamish stomachs may find it rough. As a special effect, it’s a collision of imagination,  exploitation, and blood. Lots of blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That ball pushed my younger self over the edge. I had nightmares for weeks. So much of the film, from the stark white mortuary interiors to Scrimm himself, looks unsettling. It sounds unsettling too, with an ominous, disconcerting score that adds to the film&amp;#39;s impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching it now, &lt;em&gt;Phantasm&lt;/em&gt; plays like a remake of the film I saw as a child. Scenes tug at memories of a more brutal experience. One that carved itself into my malleable psyche and sewed the seeds of my predilection for nihilistic, nightmarish horror. &lt;em&gt;Phantasm&lt;/em&gt; may not be perfect, but it made an impression.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>64. Mars Attacks! (1996) ★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/mars-attacks-1996//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/mars-attacks-1996/</id><updated>2016-10-10</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/mars-attacks-1996/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/UaIryK7fdz3ppPVenyCpIZH8N_igIhz5H5gSo31rmY4OQilJabolh4ji7z45AKK3ztNCGlMDiHOQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mars Attacks!&lt;/em&gt; could have been awful but settles for mediocre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film jumps between several storylines as aliens from Mars attack Earth. We follow the President and his staff, a pair of television personalities, a family in rural Kansas, a sleazy Las Vegas developer, and a washed up heavyweight boxer. Jack Nicholson leads an all-star cast as both the President and the Vegas developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The studio advertised the film as spoofing 1950s science-fiction pictures, but it doesn’t play that way. Among the cast, it&amp;#39;s telling that amateur actor and former NFL fullback Jim Brown seems the most comfortable. He plays the boxer reduced to dressing as a pharaoh for an Egyptian-themed casino. When the Martians attack, Brown heads out to reunite with his ex-wife (Pam Grier) and kids. He gets some help from Tom Jones, who plays himself. There’s a wonderful scene where Brown asks Jones, “Do you know how to fly a plane?” to which Jones replies, “Of course! You got one?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sort of goofball casting matches the goofy sci-fi premise.  Brown and Jones both seem aware of their shortcomings as actors, and their stiff performances are genuine and entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a glimpse of the movie I suspect director Tim Burton wanted to make. He seems less interested in spoofing the genre than recreating it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not a bad idea, but no one told the big-name cast. Few appear to enjoy the material. Most convey a sense of condescension, their performances screaming “I’m overacting on purpose!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did they have a choice? Unlike Brown and Jones, the rest of the cast can’t pretend they’re amateurs. And playing it straight wouldn’t have helped. Pam Grier plays her role with such conviction, her scenes feel spliced in from a different film. Martin Short plays his role as though he were in an overt comedy, to similar effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least they got the Martians right. The 1950s films featured serious monsters cobbled together with silly effects. Here, we get cartoonish villains brought to life with no visible wires, seams, or zippers. In my favorite scene, the Martians laser a national monument, catch the falling debris with their flying saucer, and redirect the rubble onto a fleeing tour group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, &lt;em&gt;Mars Attacks!&lt;/em&gt; underwhelms. It’s a rare movie that would be much better were it much worse.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>63. Riders of Destiny (1933) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/riders-of-destiny-1933//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/riders-of-destiny-1933/</id><updated>2016-10-03</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/riders-of-destiny-1933/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/XQ2i0QG1HLggAkzMOlhIq5OtUnqD7MgY0WHbIdKxNDMyCEzlFNnQ5iKW-qG8I2CKbWqMvUPaEj1U=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riders of Destiny&lt;/em&gt; is not a good movie, but it is an important one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It opens with John Wayne on horseback, strumming a guitar and singing a solemn ballad. The voice isn&amp;#39;t Wayne&amp;#39;s, and it&amp;#39;s clear he won&amp;#39;t win any lip-sync awards. After his introduction, Wayne evades some bad guys in a scene that tries for slapstick but fails. Soon, he’s embroiled in a water-rights dispute between some ranchers and a shady businessman. Suffering from laughable dialog and stilted pacing, the film works best when it cuts to the action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overseen by Yakima Canutt, the stunts pack a raw, visceral energy. One, a horse and rider diving off a cliff into a lake, proved so impressive, the studio recycled it for later productions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was John Wayne&amp;#39;s first film for Monogram Pictures. Over the next two years, Monogram would cast Wayne as the lead in 16 productions, all westerns. They were quick and cheap shoots, wrapping in a week with budgets of around ten-thousand dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these films, Wayne began crafting his on-screen image. During production, he bonded with the stuntmen over drinks and card games. Many were real cowboys. Wayne’s desire to emulate their physicality and mannerisms formed the foundation of his iconic posture, gait, and cadence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;#39;t recommend &lt;em&gt;Riders of Destiny&lt;/em&gt;, but for John Wayne fans it&amp;#39;s an opportunity to watch the fledgling actor workshop a persona that would become legend.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>62. The Witch (2015) ★★★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-witch-2015//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-witch-2015/</id><updated>2016-09-26</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-witch-2015/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ucvDLbqgo5JvXCTKiEugYUB1ayTWCbri8PrvJj7L0cD9COZ8cgaw1okLe7N8a8vb93R21wm8LbjT=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witch&lt;/em&gt; gets better with each viewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without revealing too much, the story follows a Puritan family exiled from their plantation in 17th century New England. Alone in the wild, they establish a small farm outside a looming forest. Tragedies beset them. As the stress mounts, they turn against one another, unaware of the horror lurking in the woods nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film requires active listening. Writer-director Robert Eggers sourced his dialog from documents and diaries written during the film’s period. The resulting English sounds a step removed from our own, packed with thees and thous and unfamiliar inflections. Those expecting to sit back, tune out, and be entertained may find themselves frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Eggers rewards our attention. The film’s credibility astounds. The production built a working farm and lit it with near-natural light sources. Eggers scoured Canada for a forest that could pass for New England woodland. The remote location he chose doubles well enough, yet still seems alien and ominous. It’s an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cast helps. Everyone impresses, but Anya Taylor-Joy astounds. Her performance as a teenage girl coming of age on a puritanical farm feels both original and authentic, and  she delivers it with startling ease. The only thing I didn&amp;#39;t buy were her teeth. Like the rest of the cast, they were too perfect. In a lesser picture, I wouldn&amp;#39;t have noticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a film of jump-scares or gory set pieces. The story unfolds with a grim, nihilistic inevitability. Take out the supernatural elements and you still have a riveting drama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what makes &lt;em&gt;The Witch&lt;/em&gt; so special. It works as a horror movie. It works as a drama. It works as a fable. It works as an indictment of patriarchal societies. Like all great films, it rewards subsequent viewings. Whether you&amp;#39;re savoring the attention to detail, or exploring the subtext, the film satisfies. As of this writing, I’ve seen it twice. That&amp;#39;s not nearly enough.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>61. Ride Him, Cowboy (1932) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/ride-him-cowboy-1932//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/ride-him-cowboy-1932/</id><updated>2016-09-19</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/ride-him-cowboy-1932/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/E-QB2xmfRBF3cjt4GWqiNxjZOqiPaHo5_wbatcoAr0x6dppxSllTDAwdazWYBsjB_T2p5RAE_LGY=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Ride Him, Cowboy&lt;/em&gt;, a town puts a horse on trial for attempted murder. This may not be the film&amp;#39;s most ridiculous scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the second production, following &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/haunted-gold-1932/&quot;&gt;Haunted Gold (1932)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, under a six-picture contract John Wayne signed with Warner Bros. It’s a remake of &lt;em&gt;The Unknown Cavalier (1926)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Warner Bros. acquired First National Pictures a few years prior, they inherited the rights to several silent westerns starring Ken Maynard. These were popular, A-list productions featuring Maynard’s impressive stunt work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warner Bros. sought to remake the Maynard silents with sound, recycling as much footage as possible, reshooting only the close-ups and interiors. All they needed was an actor who matched Maynard’s build. Enter Wayne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayne plays a wandering cowboy who tries to apprehend a mysterious outlaw known as The Hawk, only to end up framed for the outlaw&amp;#39;s crimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening sequence reveals The Hawk&amp;#39;s identity, so there&amp;#39;s no mystery. It also telegraphs the finale by introducing someone who can identify The Hawk. Granted, said person lies comatose but, as the doctor says, “He&amp;#39;ll be fine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This absurdity continues to the aforementioned horse trial, through Wayne&amp;#39;s introduction, and to his framing. This consists of The Hawk dropping Wayne&amp;#39;s monogrammed harmonica after raiding a homestead. That&amp;#39;s all the town needs to lynch Wayne. As they say, “We&amp;#39;ve got incontrovertible proof.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, despite the inanity, or perhaps because of it, the script surprises. When the female lead finds herself surrounded by The Hawk&amp;#39;s gang, she isn’t captured. Instead, she displays surprising wit and actually rescues Wayne. It&amp;#39;s only &lt;em&gt;later&lt;/em&gt; that she’s captured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for Wayne, he&amp;#39;s still learning. You catch glimpses of his iconic persona, such as his reaction shots during his sham trial, but they&amp;#39;re rare.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>60. Don't Breathe (2016) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/dont-breathe-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/dont-breathe-2016/</id><updated>2016-09-12</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/dont-breathe-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/cnJFclunmZzTHZWFiGRCRo8T4ynvtLaB4yQ8JD-U0rjmRXJkL6YSZI1cjPVD5EynpbcsiMaQb87M=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more I think about &lt;em&gt;Don&amp;#39;t Breathe&lt;/em&gt;, the less I like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story sees a trio of teens burgle a blind man&amp;#39;s dilapidated Detroit home. But the mark proves resourceful, and soon the kids are fighting to escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting the kids into the house takes forever. We sit through pages of clunky exposition meant to endear the kids to us. It does not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once inside, we’re treated to the film’s lone highlight. The kids&amp;#39; initial encounter with the blind man crackles with palpable tension. I gasped aloud when one character revealed his presence via a creaky floorboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the plot kicks in, shuffling the characters from one set piece to another with no relatable behavior or convincing motivation. It&amp;#39;s lazy writing run amok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time passed, I grew restless. The script ignores the obvious. The man is blind. Grab a hammer, hide behind a door, and brain him. None of the teens try it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sense of humor might have saved the movie. But it piles one outlandish plot twist upon another without even a wink toward its own inanity. Even worse, the twists turn downright ugly, proving &lt;em&gt;Don&amp;#39;t Breathe&lt;/em&gt; would rather push our buttons than tell a compelling story.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>59. Haunted Gold (1932) ★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/haunted-gold-1932//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/haunted-gold-1932/</id><updated>2016-09-05</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/haunted-gold-1932/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/P47rhaXRp-REMXOMjCAtfRLrjETjpyxTOAZPehjXp1xY9gEh7RjAsmPFA0ZmlVKyzcds9tQD52qQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I like John Wayne, but I struggled with &lt;em&gt;Haunted Gold&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first movie produced under a six-picture contract Wayne signed with Warner Bros. It&amp;#39;s a remake of &lt;em&gt;The Phantom City (1928)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Warner Bros. acquired First National Pictures a few years prior, they inherited the rights to several silent westerns starring Ken Maynard. These were popular, A-list productions featuring Maynard’s impressive stunt work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warner Bros. sought to remake the Maynard silents with sound, recycling as much footage as possible, reshooting only the close-ups and interiors. All they needed was an actor who matched Maynard’s build. Enter Wayne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayne plays a cowboy investigating an abandoned mine. It’s a dull, talky story involving half-shares in mines, frame-ups, betrayals, and a mysterious Phantom. One assumes Maynard&amp;#39;s version had more life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayne&amp;#39;s performance is stiff and unsure, lacking even a glimpse of his signature laconic persona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there’s Blue Washington as Wayne’s sidekick. It’s an unfunny and demeaning role that sees him referred to as “boy” by Wayne and “watermelon mouth” by the villains. It makes a bad movie even worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warner Bros. may have known they had a turkey on their hands. They shot and released two more Maynard remakes with Wayne, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/ride-him-cowboy-1932/&quot;&gt;Ride Him, Cowboy (1932)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Big Stampede (1932)&lt;/em&gt;, before releasing this stinker.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>58. Suicide Squad (2016) ★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/suicide-squad-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/suicide-squad-2016/</id><updated>2016-08-29</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/suicide-squad-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/L01xxwaB8vaZvOMiNDzVOC1Zpc_5Q9yvh2aiaLXA780phd7z09v35NeuYvOXmIbQFnaQ1bb4PzKn=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;d think an ancient demon threatening armageddon would be hard to forget, but &lt;em&gt;Suicide Squad&lt;/em&gt; proves otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot concerns a group of incarcerated super-villains made to form a super-powered Delta Force. Will Smith plays Deadshot, an assassin who never misses. Margot Robbie plays Harley Quinn, a former psychiatrist whose super-power is finding The Joker attractive. Viola Davis plays Amanda Waller, the puppet-master who sells the project to the Washington brass. The rest of the cast fall somewhere between underwritten and extraneous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dirty Dozen (1976)&lt;/em&gt;, this ain&amp;#39;t. Deadshot won&amp;#39;t kill women or children. Harley&amp;#39;s just a brat in love with a psycho. &lt;em&gt;The Bad News Bears (1976)&lt;/em&gt; had more edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the Batman cameo disappoints. In &lt;em&gt;Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice (2016)&lt;/em&gt;, Batman erupted from the shadows to cripple thugs with brutal efficiency. Here, he floats down well-lit side streets to tap super-villains on the shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only characters packing genuine menace are Waller and The Joker, neither of whom is on the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Joker is hardly in the film. Jared Leto mashes up Heath Ledger&amp;#39;s intensity in &lt;em&gt;The Dark Knight (2008)&lt;/em&gt; with Jack Nicholson&amp;#39;s flamboyant camp in &lt;em&gt;Batman (1989)&lt;/em&gt;. The resulting performance is awful, but at least it holds your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest is forgettable. There&amp;#39;s a scene eighty-some-minutes in where the squad rescues Waller. I thought the movie over. But I&amp;#39;d forgotten the film&amp;#39;s antagonists, a pair of supernatural entities bent on world destruction or some-such. Instead of the end-credits, I faced forty more minutes of contrived plot and overwrought CGI, most of which I&amp;#39;d forgotten before I left the theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>