<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'><title>Frank's Movie Log</title><subtitle>Quality reviews of films of questionable quality.</subtitle><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/feed.xml' rel='self' /><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com' /><updated>2017-01-09T23:44:57-05:00</updated><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com</id><author><name>Frank Showalter</name></author><entry><title>76. Ocean's Thirteen (2007)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/oceans-thirteen-2007//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/oceans-thirteen-2007/</id><updated>2017-01-09</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/oceans-thirteen-2007/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/N1GXNivZJRmLglTe06LVDoQAEn4eYPzkQUlYco-FITaalte9snfo0fofGvggjw3MIJkOF8cjffsN5c12GkBKXEa8cgxfpkPXByyNcP6trSTVnVRthNlEQl8ZwLZJm9GFk5tudw=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ocean&amp;#39;s Thirteen&lt;/em&gt; resurrects the caper picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a caper? It&amp;#39;s a film centered on an elaborate ruse perpetrated by lovable rogues. The genre peaked with &lt;em&gt;The Sting (1973)&lt;/em&gt;, then gave way to the grittier heist genre. But while heists get bloody, capers are rarely life-and-death scenarios. Today, the caper picture lies largely forgotten, save the occasional farcical comedy. But director Steven Soderbergh proves the old genre has legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This film&amp;#39;s lovable rogues come together to avenge their mentor (Elliott Gould) who&amp;#39;s been double-crossed by casino mogul Willy Bank (Al Pacino).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get even, the group plans to rob Bank&amp;#39;s casino. The film&amp;#39;s joy lies in how they go about it. The casino&amp;#39;s security system offers only a three-and-a-half minute window. To circumvent this obstacle, the group will rig the games to pay out to everyone. The group needn&amp;#39;t win, just for the casino to lose. So, for three-and-a-half minutes, everybody wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, folks don&amp;#39;t leave when they&amp;#39;re running hot and if they stay, they&amp;#39;ll just lose back their winnings. The thieves&amp;#39; solution to this dilemma provides another of the film&amp;#39;s quirky surprises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lesser film might drag under such plotting, but &lt;em&gt;Ocean&amp;#39;s Thirteen&lt;/em&gt; breezes along, thanks to its all-star cast. Opposite Pacino, George Clooney and Brad Pitt star as the lead thieves with Matt Damon as their de facto lieutenant. Bernie Mac, Don Cheadle, Casey Affleck, Scott Caan, Carl Reiner, and Eddie Izzard round out the crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The performers relish the script&amp;#39;s rapid-fire dialogue. Peppered with invented slang and meta references, it&amp;#39;s the film&amp;#39;s biggest treat, and holds up to repeat viewings. The first scene between Clooney and Pacino, with Clooney echoing Pacino&amp;#39;s dialog from &lt;em&gt;The Godfather (1972)&lt;/em&gt; always makes me smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my favorite scene is audacious. It opens with Pitt and Clooney strolling along the Las Vegas Strip, reminiscing. They stop and Clooney gestures off-camera, saying, “I remember when this used to be the Dunes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pitt looks down the street, “The Sands was there, and the Desert Inn…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut to a close-up. Both men stand lost in their memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clooney says, “They built them a lot smaller back then.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pitt, still looking where The Sands once stood, says, almost to himself, “They seemed pretty big.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another beat, then Clooney says, “Towns change,” and Soderbergh cuts to a wide shot reveal of the Bellagio dwarfing Clooney and Pitt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this scene. Such self-indulgence should elicit a groan, but between the crackerjack editing and sheer charisma of his stars, Soderbergh gets away with it. It&amp;#39;s a caper-within-a-caper and I fall for it every viewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: A-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>75. Christmas Evil (1980)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/christmas-evil-1980//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/christmas-evil-1980/</id><updated>2017-01-02</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/christmas-evil-1980/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/W4n2LDAivPJHkQwsVwtvBLtsDJbv21Qdlcj7d51hbsdsiLzulgwy6__BQutqCKcqU9KKOpXbWoARqY4Y-eYS7NfroX9MgkdA1YFAMHCHYeLlBakPx1wb792KLYf0GRgi8kAu5A=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christmas Evil&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;#39;t the sleazy Santa slasher you&amp;#39;d expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film opens on Christmas Eve. A young boy named Harry wanders downstairs and spies his father, dressed as Santa, fondling his half-naked mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I know, I said the film wasn&amp;#39;t sleazy. Stay with me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward thirty years and Harry (now played by Brandon Maggart) has developed an obsession with Santa. His shabby apartment overflows with Christmas knick-knacks and Santa artwork. He spies on the neighborhood children and catalogs their activities in large tomes dedicated to the naughty and nice. He even works in a dingy toy factory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Christmas Eve night, Harry dons his handmade Santa costume. At first, he&amp;#39;s overjoyed as he delivers toys to children in a mental hospital. But then his attention turns to the naughty and his mood darkens. A chance confrontation turns violent and bloody. Harry flees, unsure what went wrong. He finds solace in a neighborhood Christmas party where he&amp;#39;s the delight of the local children. But soon he&amp;#39;s alone again, and the high of the party gives way to another dangerous low. More violence follows, spiraling out of control and leading to an outrageous finale that I dare not reveal, but which casts the film as a bittersweet fable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admit, I went in expecting a cheesy bit of exploitation but I came out impressed. I liked the film&amp;#39;s production. There&amp;#39;s nary a soundstage in sight. Everything is location-based, including the New Jersey exteriors. The worn, lived-in interiors give the film a documentary veneer and added authenticity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most of all, I liked the film&amp;#39;s willingness  to tell a different kind of story. It hit me during the third act, which sees Harry fleeing a mob of torch-wielding neighbors, that writer/director Lewis Jackson wasn&amp;#39;t making a slasher picture at all, he was making a monster movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the similarities to &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein (1931)&lt;/em&gt;. Both serve as cautionary tales. &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt; warned against playing God. &lt;em&gt;Christmas Evil&lt;/em&gt; warns against playing Santa. It&amp;#39;s a laughable notion until you consider it from a child&amp;#39;s perspective. Moral absolutes like naughty and nice don&amp;#39;t work in the adult world, but try explaining that to a child. The film commits to this premise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end, Maggart&amp;#39;s performance makes the film. His character is very much a child trapped in a middle-aged body, and Maggart convinces. The audience I saw the film with offered no snarky chuckles or giggles; they sat transfixed. Much as in &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt;, we come to care about this misunderstood monster. The script helps by ensuring Harry never harms a child. It reserves Harry&amp;#39;s murderous outbursts for the film&amp;#39;s real creeps: the other adults. It&amp;#39;s an important detail that lets the film earn its ending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I think about &lt;em&gt;Christmas Evil&lt;/em&gt;, the more I admire it. Will it hold up to repeat viewings? I&amp;#39;ll let you know next Christmas.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>74. Jack Frost (1997)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/jack-frost-1997//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/jack-frost-1997/</id><updated>2016-12-26</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/jack-frost-1997/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/sDgsisYLTBNCXNTYRP_8YyW1QO2Y2F38NTQO9YUd_iNl42SVTrWRxPggfw078QizjMa-ks4GLJyrDzauoLzJAuDJHCpsoQopIUrgSlMfO0NlSHGtYvMNRXVF5CRdcHHFBPezew=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jack Frost&lt;/em&gt; is bad, even by “movie about a killer snowman” standards. And those are low standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot concerns—well, I’ve already mentioned the killer snowman, yes? Then, for most readers, I have described the plot in sufficient detail. For those still curious, the film opens with Federal agents transporting a serial killer (named Jack Frost, of course) to his execution. The icy conditions cause the paddy wagon to collide with a top-secret government tanker truck. The truck’s contents spray out, melting the killer&amp;#39;s skin and bones. His liquid remains merge with the snow, granting him a second life as a snowman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a reasonable setup. The problem lies in the execution. Had the film played as a straight horror whose antagonist happens to be a snowman, it might have worked. Just imagine the absurdist humor in swapping Michael Myers for a snowman in &lt;em&gt;Halloween (1978)&lt;/em&gt;. But &lt;em&gt;Jack Frost&lt;/em&gt; drowns in a sea of camera winks and awkward comedy bits. It’s not a horror film, it’s a manufactured attempt at “so-bad-it’s-good” schlock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that approach to work, the titular killer snowman needs to be an anti-hero; someone we can perversely root for as he offs the self-centered jerk taking up two parking spaces during the holiday rush, the obnoxious boss who overworks his employees on Christmas Eve, and yes, even the ungrateful kid who’s unhappy with his gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jack Frost&lt;/em&gt; offers no such vicarious thrills. The serial killer turned snowman is out to fulfill a petty revenge pact against the small-town sheriff who arrested him. It’s an uninspired plot for an uninspired film that’s neither scary nor funny; and thus, not worth your time.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>73. Straw Dogs (1971)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/straw-dogs-1971//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/straw-dogs-1971/</id><updated>2016-12-19</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/straw-dogs-1971/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ypTOnjofVKo1mS6s5IGRxWK0rCGIoACFxoTqZk-laP8hnsVfBlsPNZkacAppZ1oqS3biEWAnzRPzsZjeMmZV2cLDTZQ7e_vZuIsFxkLYW7sTqEbq7L76oSnmhYcmsoawq1BIDQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sam Peckinpah&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Straw Dogs&lt;/em&gt; is an ugly, brutal, nihilistic, gut-punch of a horror film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horror fans will recognize the plot. A young couple moves to a small, isolated village where they hope to renovate an old house. They ignore repeated warnings to leave and bad things happen, culminating in the young lovers barricading themselves in their home, fighting to keep an unspeakable evil from gaining entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference is in the details. &lt;em&gt;Straw Dogs&lt;/em&gt; takes place in an English village; the quaint sort you see in romantic comedies. But instead of charming, quirky characters, the residents of this hamlet are leering, hard-drinking thugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Into this rural jungle comes mild-mannered American mathematician David (Dustin Hoffman) and his attractive wife Amy (Susan George). They&amp;#39;re fleeing some vague unrest in America and the village is her childhood home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we meet David and Amy, we get our first indication the film will stray from the formula. They aren&amp;#39;t the typical idyllic couple thrust into danger. David&amp;#39;s condescending manner alienates the few locals who would befriend him but he&amp;#39;s too self-absorbed to notice. His intellectual snobbery leads him to treat Amy like a child. Amy&amp;#39;s petulant responses only reinforce the behavior. Their bickering rings true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot kicks in when some local men, including a former boyfriend of Amy&amp;#39;s, named Charlie, worm their way into a job repairing the couple&amp;#39;s garage roof. The men drag out the work. They ogle Amy. One sneaks into the house and steals a pair of Amy&amp;#39;s panties, which he later flaunts at the pub. Things reach a tipping point when David and Amy discover their cat hung in their bedroom closet. When David proves reluctant to confront the men, Amy presses the issue. David snaps at her. She calls him a coward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This conflict between David and Amy sets up the film&amp;#39;s most controversial scene: Charlie raping Amy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a hard scene to watch. I&amp;#39;ve seen the film multiple times, and it doesn&amp;#39;t get any easier. At first, Amy screams and fights back. Charlie slaps her and she crumbles to the floor in slow motion. Resigned to her fate, Amy stops fighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Peckinpah twists the knife. He quick cuts between the present and Amy&amp;#39;s intimate memories of David. Amy&amp;#39;s anger toward David swirls and churns inside her. Her resignation turns to passion as she turns from victim to betrayer and embraces her former lover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, as Amy and Charlie lay entwined, Peckinpah goes for the jugular. One of Charlie&amp;#39;s goon friends enters, holding a shotgun. With some reluctance, Charlie steps aside and watches his friend force himself on Amy at gunpoint. Amy&amp;#39;s shrieks surround us as her violation is absolute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Controversial? Absolutely. Gratuitous? No. The scene is horrifying but necessary. It drives an unspoken wedge between David and Amy, setting up the rest of the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finale sees Charlie and gang laying siege to David and Amy&amp;#39;s house. It&amp;#39;s a familiar scene in horror films; the men could just as easily be zombies or other monsters, and Peckinpah uses lots of low-angle shots and foggy backlighting. But the real horror isn&amp;#39;t what&amp;#39;s trying to get in, it&amp;#39;s what&amp;#39;s coming out between David and Amy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A series of plot-driven coincidences have led to David sheltering a mentally challenged man in the couple&amp;#39;s attic. The mob outside believes this man murdered a local girl earlier that evening. When the attacks start, Amy urges David to acquiesce to the mob&amp;#39;s demands and turn the man over, but David refuses. Bitter that David will stand up for a stranger but not her, Amy refuses to help. This proves the turning point in their relationship. Later, when Amy&amp;#39;s in trouble, she yells for Charlie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s easy to dismiss &lt;em&gt;Straw Dogs&lt;/em&gt; as misogynistic, but that&amp;#39;s short-sighted. This film hates everyone. While Amy is assaulted, David&amp;#39;s out hunting with the very men who attack her. Of course, the trip was just a ruse to lure him away, but David only accepted to buddy-up with alpha-male Charlie. David would label himself a pacifist but behaves as a sycophant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that goes to what makes the film special. It&amp;#39;s violent, sure, but it&amp;#39;s not the violence that stays with you. Rather, it&amp;#39;s the bleak reflection of human nature. Horror movies tend to paint their protagonists as bland, cookie-cutter stereotypes; their misfortune born out of some trespass or bad luck. Not here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The horror of &lt;em&gt;Straw Dogs&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;#39;t that it could &lt;em&gt;happen&lt;/em&gt; to us, it&amp;#39;s that the characters could &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; us. By committing to its bleak vision the film projects authority. By making its protagonists monsters themselves, the film transcends the exploitation genre. It may not be entertaining in the conventional sense, but every viewing stays with me for days. I may not like what &lt;em&gt;Straw Dogs&lt;/em&gt; is saying, but I can&amp;#39;t deny its impact.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: A+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>72. The Getaway (1972)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-getaway-1972//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-getaway-1972/</id><updated>2016-12-05</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-getaway-1972/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/3H45oFIj7vXiyg8k4jQ31wblut4vMmI4hmwq_h-b17Q6U78pSN1GXsntFrNmU-QCpQNQnGj_9-Pi=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Getaway&lt;/em&gt; is a slick bit of neo-noir exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve McQueen stars as Doc McCoy, an incarcerated bank robber. The opening credit sequence--cut to the staccato rhythm of an industrial loom--hammers home the hellish, regimented existence of prison life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doc finds himself near breaking after his expected parole is denied. When his wife Carol (Ali McGraw) visits him in jail, Doc cuts the visit short, telling her to contact a man named Beynon and tell him “I&amp;#39;m for sale. His price.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beynon (Ben Johnson) is a greasy operator who sits on the parole board. He pulls some strings and Doc is paroled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doc&amp;#39;s reunion with Carol is a touch of genuine sweetness that transcends the film&amp;#39;s exploitative nature. The near-wordless scenes convey the sudden change in their lives. Reunited, the two experience a brief respite before Doc meets with Beynon to repay his debt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job is a local bank. Beynon has already picked the crew. Doc would rather use his own guys, but Beynon won&amp;#39;t budge. With no leverage, Doc agrees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The robbery, of course, goes wrong. One of Beynon&amp;#39;s guys panics. Things get bloody. In his trademark fashion, director Sam Peckinpah renders each fatality in graphic slow motion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirty minutes into the film, the real story begins. Doc and Carol head for Mexico with the loot. The law and Beynon&amp;#39;s gang pursue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love how the film avoids painting Doc as a hero. He kills without hesitation. There&amp;#39;s even a rough scene where smacks Carol. And yet, McQueen&amp;#39;s performance engenders sympathy. You sense Doc&amp;#39;s desire to be a better man but fear he&amp;#39;ll lose the battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s part of the film&amp;#39;s overall sense of dread. In pursuit of Doc, one of Beynon&amp;#39;s gang takes a husband and wife hostage. The wife falls for their captor, degrading herself and humiliating her husband. As Doc and Carol flee, you&amp;#39;re sure they won&amp;#39;t make it. Even when they escape, you&amp;#39;re certain the next close-call will be their last. Chalk that up to Peckinpah&amp;#39;s commitment to grounding the film in a plausible reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sets look worn and dusty. The characters glisten with a perpetual sheen of sweat from the oppressive Texas heat. They eat greasy cheeseburgers, hole up in dingy motels, and travel in oversized cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And those cars make for gripping chase scenes. As characters panic, oversteer, fishtail, and crash, you appreciate the challenge of controlling such large vehicles at high speeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the film&amp;#39;s highlight belongs to an on-foot chase. After a con-man switches locker keys with Carol and snags the loot, Doc engages in a desperate pursuit through a crowded train station. The dialog-free sequence crackles with tension and echoes vintage Hitchcock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scenes like this, along with McQueen&amp;#39;s charisma and Peckinpah&amp;#39;s stylish editing help gloss over the clunky plot. &lt;em&gt;The Getaway&lt;/em&gt; may be little more than pulp, but it&amp;#39;s damn entertaining.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>71. Doctor Strange (2016)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/doctor-strange-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/doctor-strange-2016/</id><updated>2016-11-28</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/doctor-strange-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Fy7FUeNQVfMdLwIj_JHquTJoXwp0DquRwvPVURemABSX3aw-9se2e0xZrv-idwOmD1gjJ8T39OCv=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; offers ephemeral entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set in the Marvel cinematic universe, the film stars Benedict Cumberbatch as Stephen Strange, a hotshot neurosurgeon. After a car accident cripples his hands, Strange’s desperate search for a miracle cure leads him to Nepal. There he meets The Ancient One, played by Tilda Swinton, who trains him in the mystic arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strange proves himself an exceptional student. Good thing, as he’s soon under attack from Kaecilius, the Ancient One’s former star pupil. Kaecilius now serves Dormammu, an ancient entity from the Dark Dimension. Soon, Strange is all that stands between Earth and a horrible (but not well explained) fate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen this story before in countless martial arts films. An acolyte approaches a great master for training, excels against the odds, then clashes with the master’s once favorite student. This film merely substitutes magic for kung-fu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem lies in the homogenized and watered-down execution. Strange’s arc revolves around him overcoming his arrogance. But the film paints him as a brilliant surgeon far ahead of his colleagues. Is that arrogance? Why not paint Strange as a real monster? The film doesn’t seem comfortable making Strange too unlikable. Thus, Cumberbatch’s Strange plays as a less fun version of Robert Downey Jr.’s Tony Stark from the &lt;em&gt;Iron Man&lt;/em&gt; films. The resulting character feels thin and flat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This extends to the villains. Mads Mikkelsen can play a great bad guy but fails to register as Kaecilius. The script gives him no edge. We’ve seen the disgruntled student archetype in countless films before, and &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; offers nothing new. Even Dormammu, who should rank among the most horrific villains in the Marvel oeuvre, fails to terrify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The special effects also fail to connect. We see cities twisting and folding upon themselves like Rubik’s Cubes, but the film fails to surround these scenes with a compelling story. Watching New York transform into an M.C. Escher style visage is impressive, but not engaging. The effects should serve the story, not substitute for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds like I hated the film. I did not. Though I would have preferred his native British accent, I enjoyed Cumberbatch’s performance. The real star, however, is Tilda Swinton. She takes a throw-away archetype and delivers the film’s most memorable character. And as someone who grew up reading the comics, I loved seeing the sentient Cloak of Levitation, even if it was little more than comic relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, after the obligatory post-credit sequence, I left the theater impressed with &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt;. But in retrospect, I could remember images in the film, but none of my feelings upon seeing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a reoccurring effect in the film where characters enter the Astral Plane. Their ethereal bodies float in the air and pass through solid objects. If they try hard enough, they can bump walls or knock things over. It’s an apt enough metaphor for the film. It looks good, but it’s hollow inside and struggles to connect. When you try to grab it, you discover there’s nothing there.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>70. Sagebrush Trail (1933)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/sagebrush-trail-1933//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/sagebrush-trail-1933/</id><updated>2016-11-21</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/sagebrush-trail-1933/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/t-YlFZzOBSK4QJXy7XZhfQhiwqqlYvXoJF85WXSfOPlWXg3hHjw5PbUBFp96zepLn2A6HWSVaxG3=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The underwater scenes in &lt;em&gt;Sagebrush Trail&lt;/em&gt; belie its shoestring budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those scenes come early. John Wayne plays a fugitive named John (of course) stowed away aboard a freight train. As the train pulls into the station, lawmen are waiting. After some cat and mouse, John hops a horse and flees into the countryside. The lawmen pursue. John dead-ends at a lake, dismounts, and dives into the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see John underwater, breathing through a reed. It&amp;#39;s not a special effect. I&amp;#39;m not sure how they shot these scenes, but that&amp;#39;s Wayne underwater, breathing through a stick in what looks like a lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After eluding the lawmen, who believe him dead, John surfaces and encounters a gunslinger. The gunslinger, recognizing a fellow desperado, introduces himself as Jones and invites John to join an outlaw gang. John accepts and he and Jones become fast-friends and rivals for the local shopgirl, Sally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, John&amp;#39;s not really a bad guy. He passes notes to Sally warning her of the gang&amp;#39;s intentions. And of course, it was Jones who committed the crime pinned on John. And of course, John doesn&amp;#39;t discover this until the second act&amp;#39;s end. But you know what? I didn&amp;#39;t mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sagebrush Trail&lt;/em&gt; may suffer from predictable plotting, stilted dialog, and fight scenes where the participants punch each other&amp;#39;s shoulders, but I still enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the aforementioned underwater scenes, I liked the location photography and wipe transitions. And the script&amp;#39;s making Jones a flawed but likable character was a nice touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most of all, I liked Wayne. This was his second production for Monogram Pictures, after &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/riders-of-destiny-1933/&quot;&gt;Riders of Destiny (1933)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Though Wayne struggles with the romantic comedy scenes, he&amp;#39;s making strides as a performer. More than ever before, we see flashes of his famous Duke persona. And judging by the underwater scenes, he&amp;#39;s doing some of his own stunts to boot.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>69. The Sentinel (1977)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-sentinel-1977//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-sentinel-1977/</id><updated>2016-11-14</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-sentinel-1977/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/kxf7iIKKYoFRZdgn7mW5D-IVUDAGpSn0VjUjuQp1L5vB-Mooasc61eOcROuNr7gtSs9VcbwociKh=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chris Sarandon saves &lt;em&gt;The Sentinel&lt;/em&gt; from its own excess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film stars Cristina Raines as a fashion model who moves into a fantastic apartment in a converted Brooklyn brownstone. A series of strange encounters with her eccentric neighbors leaves her paranoid and on edge. Her boyfriend, a hot-shot defense attorney played by Sarandon, investigates and uncovers a horrific conspiracy involving the Catholic Church and a gateway to Hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The setup invites comparisons to &lt;em&gt;Rosemary’s Baby (1968)&lt;/em&gt;. But unlike that film, which was about women&amp;#39;s reproductive rights, &lt;em&gt;The Sentinel&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;#39;t about anything. It&amp;#39;s an exploitation picture offering a smorgasbord of gore, nudity, lesbianism, human deformities, and female masturbation. I don&amp;#39;t mind these things. I object to the film’s middling execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Movie fans will enjoy spotting the once and future stars peppering the cast. José Ferrer as an unnamed robed figure. Ava Gardner as a charming real estate agent. Burgess Meredith as a creepy neighbor. Eli Wallach as a cagey detective. Christopher Walken as Wallach’s grinning partner. Jeff Goldblum as a fashion photographer. Beverly D’Angelo as a mute exhibitionist. An unrecognizable John Carradine as an aging priest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the film wastes its talented ensemble. It regulates most of the former stars, like Ferrer, Gardner, and Carradine, to throwaway roles for name recognition. Other performances veer into camp. Beverly D’Angelo’s memorable scene elicits chuckles instead of chills. Eli Wallach&amp;#39;s phoned-in turn plays as caricature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sprawling cast is a byproduct of the convoluted, nonsensical plot. Consider the scene where a character breaks through a wall in the brownstone and uncovers a plaque bearing an inscription from Dante’s &lt;em&gt;Inferno&lt;/em&gt;. It’s the film in a microcosm: effective and atmospheric, but its logic crumbles under the slightest scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What saved the film for me was Sarandon. Despite sporting a mustache that only adds to the film&amp;#39;s second-rate feel, Sarandon is perfect in his role. He avoids the idiot plot and acts according to character. And there&amp;#39;s just something about him playing a charming but ruthless character that I enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I saw &lt;em&gt;The Sentinel&lt;/em&gt;, I thought its mix of camp and shock hit more often than it missed—if only just. Watching it again, I’m not so sure. The performances don’t hold up well to repeat viewings, but Sarandon was every bit as good as I remembered.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>68. Curse of the Demon (1958)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/curse-of-the-demon-1958//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/curse-of-the-demon-1958/</id><updated>2016-11-07</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/curse-of-the-demon-1958/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Qyy-4N8MQjl3tTIF-bHyjNuAgoZghlz7L_FdCwONdmhmLDcEex-ieWdSWnPa0XmPI6m3Tc3ZplgA=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;A producer&amp;#39;s meddling keeps &lt;em&gt;Curse of the Demon&lt;/em&gt; from perfection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story sees American psychologist John Holden (Dana Andrews) travel to London. He&amp;#39;s there to expose self-professed black magician Julian Karswell (Niall MacGinnis) as a fraud. Karswell tries to dissuade Holden, but Holden remains resolute. Karswell then announces Holden will die in three days. Holden is skeptical, but after a series of unexplained events, his skepticism crumbles and he begins to fear for his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the best kind of thriller: one populated by intelligent characters who behave according to their personalities, not the whims of the plot. It avoids cheap jump-scares. Instead, director Jacques Tourneur uses atmosphere to build tension. Shadowy hallways and darkened rooms keep us on edge. And, for the real horror, there&amp;#39;s Niall MacGinnis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved MacGinnis&amp;#39; performance. It&amp;#39;s a perfect combination of charm and menace. There&amp;#39;s a great scene where Holden has broken into Karswell&amp;#39;s palatial home. In the darkness, a house cat transforms into a leopard and attacks. Holden struggles for his life, only escaping once Karswell enters and turns on the lights. Karswell treats the intruding Holden as one would treat a party guest who&amp;#39;d gotten lost looking for the bathroom. By underplaying the role, MacGinnis makes the character all the more sinister. Christopher Lee built a career on similar performances. And yet, MacGinnis conveys a vulnerability beneath the bluster that adds unexpected depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opposite MacGinnis, Andrews delivers a curious turn. His cadence and speech patterns mimic John Wayne&amp;#39;s. They&amp;#39;re so similar, I wonder if it was a deliberate impersonation. This brings up an interesting tangent. The Duke played many roles in many movies, but he never made a straight horror picture. Judging by Andrews&amp;#39; performance here, Wayne could have pulled it off with flair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, despite the solid script, competent direction and inspired performances, &lt;em&gt;Curse of the Demon&lt;/em&gt; falters. The opening sequence sees the titular demon marching out of the woods. A similar sequence occurs at the film&amp;#39;s end. In both, the demon’s mechanical movement and frozen expression scream rubber suit. My wife thought it resembled a homecoming float. Not only do these shots cheapen the film, they undermine any sense of ambiguity regarding Karswell&amp;#39;s powers. Holden is the audience surrogate. His skepticism is our skepticism. But this falls apart when we know Karswell&amp;#39;s powers are real from the outset. Instead of questioning things along with Holden, we grow impatient waiting for him to catch up. A great psychological thriller devolves into a cheap monster movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can thank producer Hal E. Chester. He added the demon shots after principal photography wrapped. Tourneur and Andrews fought him on it. Writer Charles Bennett threatened to shoot Chester dead. They all lost. The studio, Columbia, did cut some footage for the American release, but not of the monster. What a shame.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>67. Torso (1973)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/torso-1973//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/torso-1973/</id><updated>2016-10-31</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/torso-1973/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Y_IbflpaJ_iIgxd1thi7OTYEH7xp1iHj-4VSR24Zf_hdegkTj4DiKnlsPbZDUSWau43K9mlO7qXu=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Torso&lt;/em&gt; executes a generic plot with panache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film takes place in scenic Perugia, Italy. A masked killer strangles two female university students, sparking a manhunt. Another student thinks she recognizes the murder weapon, leading to threatening phone calls from the killer. Alarmed, she retreats to a cliff-side villa with four girlfriends, including an American exchange student, played by Suzy Kendall. The killer, of course, follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It plays as a mystery, inviting us to guess the killer’s identity. The script proffers a myriad of suspects, painting almost every male character as possessive, misogynistic, or perverted. The few that appear normal feel suspect by comparison. I admit, it fooled me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mystery aside, what I enjoyed most about &lt;em&gt;Torso&lt;/em&gt; was its style. There’s a scene where the killer tracks a girl through a swampy marsh. The lighting, camerawork, and editing create a kind of kinetic claustrophobia. The more she runs, the more her world shrinks. Even as the tension held me rapt, the sheer craft made me smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it gets better. The last act sees Kendall locked in a bedroom. She slides a piece of newspaper under the door, hoping to catch the key as she forces it out of the lock. I won&amp;#39;t spoil what happens, but I will say this scene caps twenty-some dialog-free minutes that serve as a master class in suspense. They&amp;#39;re so good, I forgave the finale, which sees the killer reveal his identity and explain his psychosis via some awkward and disappointing exposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only problem with &lt;em&gt;Torso&lt;/em&gt; lies with its heroines. I liked how the film paints them as strong, independent women. Fleeing to a remote outpost wasn&amp;#39;t the smartest move, but it was refreshing to see them do something besides run to the nearest man for protection. If only the script had provided them with distinct personalities. Aside from Kendall’s character, they felt interchangeable and never endeared themselves. It’s a common problem with mysteries. We learn more about the various red herrings than about the protagonists.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>