<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'><title>Frank's Movie Log</title><subtitle>I'm not a great writer. Maybe not even a good one. But with practice I can be better.</subtitle><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/feed.xml' rel='self' /><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com' /><updated>2016-10-03T21:07:18-04:00</updated><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com</id><author><name>Frank Showalter</name></author><entry><title>63. Riders of Destiny (1933) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/riders-of-destiny-1933//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/riders-of-destiny-1933/</id><updated>2016-10-03</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/riders-of-destiny-1933/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/XQ2i0QG1HLggAkzMOlhIq5OtUnqD7MgY0WHbIdKxNDMyCEzlFNnQ5iKW-qG8I2CKbWqMvUPaEj1U=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riders of Destiny&lt;/em&gt; is not a good movie, but it is an important one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It opens with John Wayne on horseback, strumming a guitar and singing a solemn ballad. The voice isn&amp;#39;t Wayne&amp;#39;s, and it&amp;#39;s clear he won&amp;#39;t win any lip-sync awards. After his introduction, Wayne evades some bad guys in a scene that tries for slapstick but fails. Soon, he’s embroiled in a water-rights dispute between some ranchers and a shady businessman. Suffering from laughable dialog and stilted pacing, the film works best when it cuts to the action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overseen by Yakima Canutt, the stunts pack a raw, visceral energy. One, a horse and rider diving off a cliff into a lake, proved so impressive, the studio recycled it for later productions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was John Wayne&amp;#39;s first film for Monogram Pictures. Over the next two years, Monogram would cast Wayne as the lead in 16 productions, all westerns. They were quick and cheap shoots, wrapping in a week with budgets of around ten-thousand dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these films, Wayne began crafting his on-screen image. During production, he bonded with the stuntmen over drinks and card games. Many were real cowboys. Wayne’s desire to emulate their physicality and mannerisms formed the foundation of his iconic posture, gait, and cadence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;#39;t recommend &lt;em&gt;Riders of Destiny&lt;/em&gt;, but for John Wayne fans it&amp;#39;s an opportunity to watch the fledgling actor workshop a persona that would become legend.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>62. The Witch (2015) ★★★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-witch-2015//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-witch-2015/</id><updated>2016-09-26</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-witch-2015/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ucvDLbqgo5JvXCTKiEugYUB1ayTWCbri8PrvJj7L0cD9COZ8cgaw1okLe7N8a8vb93R21wm8LbjT=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witch&lt;/em&gt; gets better with each viewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without revealing too much, the story follows a Puritan family exiled from their plantation in 17th century New England. Alone in the wild, they establish a small farm outside a looming forest. Tragedies beset them. As the stress mounts, they turn against one another, unaware of the horror lurking in the woods nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film requires active listening. Writer-director Robert Eggers sourced his dialog from documents and diaries written during the film’s period. The resulting English sounds a step removed from our own, packed with thees and thous and unfamiliar inflections. Those expecting to sit back, tune out, and be entertained may find themselves frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Eggers rewards our attention. The film’s credibility astounds. The production built a working farm and lit it with near-natural light sources. Eggers scoured Canada for a forest that could pass for New England woodland. The remote location he chose doubles well enough, yet still seems alien and ominous. It’s an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cast helps. Everyone impresses, but Anya Taylor-Joy astounds. Her performance as a teenage girl coming of age on a puritanical farm feels both original and authentic, and  she delivers it with startling ease. The only thing I didn&amp;#39;t buy were her teeth. Like the rest of the cast, they were too perfect. In a lesser picture, I wouldn&amp;#39;t have noticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a film of jump-scares or gory set pieces. The story unfolds with a grim, nihilistic inevitability. Take out the supernatural elements and you still have a riveting drama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what makes &lt;em&gt;The Witch&lt;/em&gt; so special. It works as a horror movie. It works as a drama. It works as a fable. It works as an indictment of patriarchal societies. Like all great films, it rewards subsequent viewings. Whether you&amp;#39;re savoring the attention to detail, or exploring the subtext, the film satisfies. As of this writing, I’ve seen it twice. That&amp;#39;s not nearly enough.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>61. Ride Him, Cowboy (1932) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/ride-him-cowboy-1932//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/ride-him-cowboy-1932/</id><updated>2016-09-19</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/ride-him-cowboy-1932/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/E-QB2xmfRBF3cjt4GWqiNxjZOqiPaHo5_wbatcoAr0x6dppxSllTDAwdazWYBsjB_T2p5RAE_LGY=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Ride Him, Cowboy&lt;/em&gt;, a town puts a horse on trial for attempted murder. This may not be the film&amp;#39;s most ridiculous scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the second production, following &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/haunted-gold-1932/&quot;&gt;Haunted Gold (1932)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, under a six-picture contract John Wayne signed with Warner Bros. It’s a remake of &lt;em&gt;The Unknown Cavalier (1926)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Warner Bros. acquired First National Pictures a few years prior, they inherited the rights to several silent westerns starring Ken Maynard. These were popular, A-list productions featuring Maynard’s impressive stunt work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warner Bros. sought to remake the Maynard silents with sound, recycling as much footage as possible, reshooting only the close-ups and interiors. All they needed was an actor who matched Maynard’s build. Enter Wayne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayne plays a wandering cowboy who tries to apprehend a mysterious outlaw known as The Hawk, only to end up framed for the outlaw&amp;#39;s crimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening sequence reveals The Hawk&amp;#39;s identity, so there&amp;#39;s no mystery. It also telegraphs the finale by introducing someone who can identify The Hawk. Granted, said person lies comatose but, as the doctor says, “He&amp;#39;ll be fine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This absurdity continues to the aforementioned horse trial, through Wayne&amp;#39;s introduction, and to his framing. This consists of The Hawk dropping Wayne&amp;#39;s monogrammed harmonica after raiding a homestead. That&amp;#39;s all the town needs to lynch Wayne. As they say, “We&amp;#39;ve got incontrovertible proof.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, despite the inanity, or perhaps because of it, the script surprises. When the female lead finds herself surrounded by The Hawk&amp;#39;s gang, she isn’t captured. Instead, she displays surprising wit and actually rescues Wayne. It&amp;#39;s only &lt;em&gt;later&lt;/em&gt; that she’s captured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for Wayne, he&amp;#39;s still learning. You catch glimpses of his iconic persona, such as his reaction shots during his sham trial, but they&amp;#39;re rare.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>60. Don't Breathe (2016) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/dont-breathe-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/dont-breathe-2016/</id><updated>2016-09-12</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/dont-breathe-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/cnJFclunmZzTHZWFiGRCRo8T4ynvtLaB4yQ8JD-U0rjmRXJkL6YSZI1cjPVD5EynpbcsiMaQb87M=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more I think about &lt;em&gt;Don&amp;#39;t Breathe&lt;/em&gt;, the less I like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story sees a trio of teens burgle a blind man&amp;#39;s dilapidated Detroit home. But the mark proves resourceful, and soon the kids are fighting to escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting the kids into the house takes forever. We sit through pages of clunky exposition meant to endear the kids to us. It does not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once inside, we’re treated to the film’s lone highlight. The kids&amp;#39; initial encounter with the blind man crackles with palpable tension. I gasped aloud when one character revealed his presence via a creaky floorboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the plot kicks in, shuffling the characters from one set piece to another with no relatable behavior or convincing motivation. It&amp;#39;s lazy writing run amok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time passed, I grew restless. The script ignores the obvious. The man is blind. Grab a hammer, hide behind a door, and brain him. None of the teens try it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sense of humor might have saved the movie. But it piles one outlandish plot twist upon another without even a wink toward its own inanity. Even worse, the twists turn downright ugly, proving &lt;em&gt;Don&amp;#39;t Breathe&lt;/em&gt; would rather push our buttons than tell a compelling story.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>59. Haunted Gold (1932) ★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/haunted-gold-1932//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/haunted-gold-1932/</id><updated>2016-09-05</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/haunted-gold-1932/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/P47rhaXRp-REMXOMjCAtfRLrjETjpyxTOAZPehjXp1xY9gEh7RjAsmPFA0ZmlVKyzcds9tQD52qQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I like John Wayne, but I struggled with &lt;em&gt;Haunted Gold&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first movie produced under a six-picture contract Wayne signed with Warner Bros. It&amp;#39;s a remake of &lt;em&gt;The Phantom City (1928)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Warner Bros. acquired First National Pictures a few years prior, they inherited the rights to several silent westerns starring Ken Maynard. These were popular, A-list productions featuring Maynard’s impressive stunt work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warner Bros. sought to remake the Maynard silents with sound, recycling as much footage as possible, reshooting only the close-ups and interiors. All they needed was an actor who matched Maynard’s build. Enter Wayne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayne plays a cowboy investigating an abandoned mine. It’s a dull, talky story involving half-shares in mines, frame-ups, betrayals, and a mysterious Phantom. One assumes Maynard&amp;#39;s version had more life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayne&amp;#39;s performance is stiff and unsure, lacking even a glimpse of his signature laconic persona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there’s Blue Washington as Wayne’s sidekick. It’s an unfunny and demeaning role that sees him referred to as “boy” by Wayne and “watermelon mouth” by the villains. It makes a bad movie even worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warner Bros. may have known they had a turkey on their hands. They shot and released two more Maynard remakes with Wayne, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/ride-him-cowboy-1932/&quot;&gt;Ride Him, Cowboy (1932)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Big Stampede (1932)&lt;/em&gt;, before releasing this stinker.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>58. Suicide Squad (2016) ★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/suicide-squad-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/suicide-squad-2016/</id><updated>2016-08-29</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/suicide-squad-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/L01xxwaB8vaZvOMiNDzVOC1Zpc_5Q9yvh2aiaLXA780phd7z09v35NeuYvOXmIbQFnaQ1bb4PzKn=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;d think an ancient demon threatening armageddon would be hard to forget, but &lt;em&gt;Suicide Squad&lt;/em&gt; proves otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot concerns a group of incarcerated super-villains made to form a super-powered Delta Force. Will Smith plays Deadshot, an assassin who never misses. Margot Robbie plays Harley Quinn, a former psychiatrist whose super-power is finding The Joker attractive. Viola Davis plays Amanda Waller, the puppet-master who sells the project to the Washington brass. The rest of the cast fall somewhere between underwritten and extraneous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dirty Dozen (1976)&lt;/em&gt;, this ain&amp;#39;t. Deadshot won&amp;#39;t kill women or children. Harley&amp;#39;s just a brat in love with a psycho. &lt;em&gt;The Bad News Bears (1976)&lt;/em&gt; had more edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the Batman cameo disappoints. In &lt;em&gt;Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice (2016)&lt;/em&gt;, Batman erupted from the shadows to cripple thugs with brutal efficiency. Here, he floats down well-lit side streets to tap super-villains on the shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only characters packing genuine menace are Waller and The Joker, neither of whom is on the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Joker is hardly in the film. Jared Leto mashes up Heath Ledger&amp;#39;s intensity in &lt;em&gt;The Dark Knight (2008)&lt;/em&gt; with Jack Nicholson&amp;#39;s flamboyant camp in &lt;em&gt;Batman (1989)&lt;/em&gt;. The resulting performance is awful, but at least it holds your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest is forgettable. There&amp;#39;s a scene eighty-some-minutes in where the squad rescues Waller. I thought the movie over. But I&amp;#39;d forgotten the film&amp;#39;s antagonists, a pair of supernatural entities bent on world destruction or some-such. Instead of the end-credits, I faced forty more minutes of contrived plot and overwrought CGI, most of which I&amp;#39;d forgotten before I left the theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>57. The Killer Nun (1979) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-killer-nun-1979//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-killer-nun-1979/</id><updated>2016-08-19</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-killer-nun-1979/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/XCwo6MGUFHR5-etMd1PLMYPRVT3H2Kv6FBZ-hSnNgRSXRAlAw2Ktg28pc-fzYS9dE6MgfIrgGEZF=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a nunsploitation picture, boredom is a cardinal sin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anita Ekberg plays Sister Gertrude, a hospital matron with an unhinged psyche. She complains of intense headaches and steals to support a morphine addiction. Outside the hospital, she drinks, smokes, and has anonymous sex. During dinner, she reprimands a patient by stomping their dentures to pieces. In bed with a young nun, she orders her would-be paramour to “Say you&amp;#39;re a dirty whore.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, when patients turn up murdered, Sister Gertrude is the prime suspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this point, the film has abandoned the lurid sleaze and manic energy that carried the first half. In their place, we get a convoluted scheme to replace the head physician and a flimsy mystery. Worse still, we guess the big twist, making the film&amp;#39;s final half tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Killer Nun&lt;/em&gt; is trash, but not total trash, and that&amp;#39;s a shame.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>55. Chain Lightning (1950) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/chain-lightning-1950//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/chain-lightning-1950/</id><updated>2016-02-17</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/chain-lightning-1950/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/fXE6R_a57mB0-5L6fujb4hR1tEKUQ9FdNVRfjfmNjtwHrQHXAm5QJ8MOKSyLkERibOmdMlUcLRcv=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The skin-tight flight suit is a bridge too far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone younger with a fuller build might have pulled it off. William Holden or Kirk Douglas, maybe. But at 49, Humphrey Bogart looks ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story opens during World War II with Bogart as an enlisted pilot leading bombing runs and romancing a Red Cross worker played by Eleanor Parker. When he&amp;#39;s ordered home, Bogart and Parker try to marry but a series of contrivances thwarts their efforts and Bogart leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut to present day where more contrivances see a washed-up Bogart land a test pilot job for an aviation mogul played by Raymond Massey. Of course, Parker shows up as Massey’s secretary. She’s dating Massey’s chief engineer, played by Richard Whorf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflict arises when Bogart suggests piloting Massey’s experimental fighter jet from Alaska to Washington, D.C. It’s a stunt to convince the Washington brass the plane is ready for production. Whorf opposes the stunt, convinced the jet needs the new safety features he&amp;#39;s developing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Massey wants to produce the fighter now. Bogart wants the money the stunt will net him so he can propose to Parker. Whorf wants time to finish his safety innovations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Bogart races to Washington clad in the aforementioned flight suit, Whorf races to implement his new designs, using himself as a test pilot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a passable story buried in &lt;em&gt;Chain Lightning&lt;/em&gt;, but Bogart’s wrong for the role. The laughable sight of him squeezed into the flight suit distracts from the script’s foresight. Though common enough today, escape pods, pressurized flight suits, and braking parachutes were science fiction to 1950s audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compounding matters, the film pushes the melodrama, despite the three leads having no chemistry. Will Bogart and Parker get back together? Will there be obstacles to their romance? I think you know the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting film feels like one of Bogart’s pre-&lt;em&gt;Casablanca (1942)&lt;/em&gt; pictures that saw him cast in whatever assembly line production Warners was cranking out that week. Bogart deserved better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And really, what were they thinking with that flight suit?&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>54. Black Mass (2015) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/black-mass-2015//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/black-mass-2015/</id><updated>2016-02-06</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/black-mass-2015/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/hpK784BJIMAgPi4-toiRP4LCjxRXEuK1VBqsDmAFjMu5wD_49HtopxMBYOEUa2PUGiliFwEieLbI=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on a true story, &lt;em&gt;Black Mass&lt;/em&gt; sees Johnny Depp made up as a balding and paunchy James “Whitey” Bulger. The film follows Bulger’s ascent from small-time hood to crime-lord of South Boston. A journey made possible by the FBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early in the film, the Feds offer Bulger a sweet deal. In exchange for information on the Italian mob in North Boston, the FBI leave Bulger’s crew alone. Even better, they eliminate the competition. Best of all, Bulger’s FBI handler is a South Boston native who idolizes him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the FBI ask is that Bulger not kill anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of course, Bulger kills people. He executes one of his lackeys. His gang somehow gets involved in Jai Alai and Bulger orders the commissioner killed. He strangles a young girl who may have talked to the cops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last murder was where the film lost me. It’s late in the film and the script introduces the girl only for Bulger to kill her five minutes later. The scene plays like something out of a horror movie and does nothing to build characterization or advance the plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also meet Bulger’s younger brother, a state senator played by Benedict Cumberbatch. Cumberbatch is good casting. His Boston accent may be jarring, but he’s believable as Depp’s brother. While both men seem too slight for their parts, they’re convincing as family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film invites comparisons with Scorsese’s &lt;em&gt;Goodfellas (1990)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Departed (2006)&lt;/em&gt;, but these comparisons underscore &lt;em&gt;Black Mass&lt;/em&gt;’s weakness: Bulger isn’t a compelling character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see Bulger build his empire, yet have no idea how he spends a typical day. He makes piles of money but, aside from a pair of cowboy boots, we never see him spend it. He suffers what we’re told are life-changing tragedies, yet seems unfazed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depp tries as Bulger, but he can’t compensate for the shallow characterization. He can’t disappear into the character because there is no character, just makeup and an accent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no psychological insight, &lt;em&gt;Black Mass&lt;/em&gt; feels hollow. We may learn much of Whitey Bulger’s life, but we learn very little about &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>53. The House That Dripped Blood (1971) ★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-house-that-dripped-blood-1971//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-house-that-dripped-blood-1971/</id><updated>2015-11-25</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-house-that-dripped-blood-1971/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/FMMgkimfRtPRm2id-f-ft-JjAMqk0TwHmvQnGRypZmP1imYN_H1srF3U69u_UnE9SHs0kDvsEXck=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reviewing anthology movies is hard. I picture you, dear reader, trudging through endless paragraphs of plot synopsis and I feel guilty. I have let you down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My duty as a reviewer is to describe the film. My job as a writer is to respect your time and attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so my challenge is to describe the picture in a succinct manner that holds your interest. Not that different, I suppose, from what I expect of the films I review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But just as I’m willing to humor a movie that stumbles, provided its intentions are good, I ask you, dear reader, to bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The House that Dripped Blood&lt;/em&gt; comprises four stories revolving around an old English country house. They vary in quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first story, &lt;em&gt;Method for Murder&lt;/em&gt;, sees a writer, Charles Hillyer, move into the house along with his wife. Hillyer writes lurid thrillers. He’s certain the house’s creaky atmosphere will help him finish his latest novel. Things take a turn for the macabre when Hillyer sees his literary creation, the murderous strangler Dominic, lurking around the estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a worn premise, but screenwriter Robert Bloch puts a twist on the twist that makes for a satisfying ending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second story, &lt;em&gt;Waxworks&lt;/em&gt;, follows a retired businessman named Philip Grayson, played by Peter Cushing. While touring a horrific wax museum in town, Grayson notices a figure that bears a striking resemblance to a girl he loved as a young man. Soon, he’s obsessed with the perceived effigy and, as you suspect, it doesn’t end well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the first installment, you’ll see the twist coming, but Cushing makes it work. Soon to be a widower in real life, Cushing brings a pathos to what’s otherwise a throw-away role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third story, &lt;em&gt;Sweets to the Sweet&lt;/em&gt; is the best. Christopher Lee plays John Reid, a widower. The details surrounding his wife’s death are hazy, and Reid doesn’t seem to miss her. He moves into the house with his young daughter, Jane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon arrival the estate agent gives them a tour of the house. When they reach a room with a lit fireplace, Jane runs crying from the fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reid hires a tutor for Jane, insisting she not go to school with other children. Astonished Jane has no toys of her own, the tutor buys her a small doll. Outraged, Reid throws the doll into the fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mystery builds to a satisfying conclusion, with Lee exploiting audience expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final story, &lt;em&gt;The Cloak&lt;/em&gt;, concerns an aging, egotistical horror actor named Paul Henderson. In a flat bit of meta-humor, he dismisses the current generation of horror films, saying he prefers the classics, like Dracula. Although he’s quick to add “The Lugosi one, not this new chap.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot kicks in when Henderson acquires a cape that belonged to an actual vampire. Wearing it, Henderson sprouts fangs, loses his reflection, and gains the ability to fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s played as camp, which is a shame. Co-star Ingrid Pitt, strikes the right balance, but Jon Pertwee’s performance as Henderson never hooked me. The resulting segment fails to thrill or amuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anthology films are hard to grade. My rating averages the individual segments. The third piece’s excellences cancels the fourth’s failed camp. But Christopher Lee’s segment is enough to recommend &lt;em&gt;The House that Dripped Blood&lt;/em&gt;. After all, if the other stories don’t seem appealing, there’s always the fast-forward button.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>