<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'><title>Frank's Movie Log</title><subtitle>I'm not a great writer. Maybe not even a good one. But with practice I can be better.</subtitle><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/feed.xml' rel='self' /><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com' /><updated>2016-09-13T19:56:54-04:00</updated><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com</id><author><name>Frank Showalter</name></author><entry><title>60. Don't Breathe (2016) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/dont-breathe-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/dont-breathe-2016/</id><updated>2016-09-12</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/dont-breathe-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/cnJFclunmZzTHZWFiGRCRo8T4ynvtLaB4yQ8JD-U0rjmRXJkL6YSZI1cjPVD5EynpbcsiMaQb87M=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more I think about &lt;em&gt;Don&amp;#39;t Breathe&lt;/em&gt;, the less I like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story sees a trio of teens burgle a blind man&amp;#39;s dilapidated Detroit home. But the mark proves resourceful, and soon the kids are fighting to escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting the kids into the house takes forever. We sit through pages of clunky exposition meant to endear the kids to us. It does not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once inside, we’re treated to the film’s lone highlight. The kids&amp;#39; initial encounter with the blind man crackles with palpable tension. I gasped aloud when one character revealed his presence via a creaky floorboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the plot kicks in, shuffling the characters from one set piece to another with no relatable behavior or convincing motivation. It&amp;#39;s lazy writing run amok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time passed, I grew restless. The script ignores the obvious. The man is blind. Grab a hammer, hide behind a door, and brain him. None of the teens try it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sense of humor might have saved the movie. But it piles one outlandish plot twist upon another without even a wink toward its own inanity. Even worse, the twists turn downright ugly, proving &lt;em&gt;Don&amp;#39;t Breathe&lt;/em&gt; would rather push our buttons than tell a compelling story.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>59. Haunted Gold (1932) ★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/haunted-gold-1932//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/haunted-gold-1932/</id><updated>2016-09-05</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/haunted-gold-1932/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/yl-Rqf7_LBlfsTZ4M_YWpKDl55lGDGKRlJnBs90OWN9L8dgRIaHZZ2mb8ZUjBMSTjWUiOgheTMoD=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I like John Wayne, but I struggled with &lt;em&gt;Haunted Gold&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayne plays a cowboy investigating an abandoned mine. It&amp;#39;s a dull, talky story involving half-shares in mines, frame-ups, betrayals, and a mysterious Phantom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, it&amp;#39;s a remake of &lt;em&gt;The Phantom City (1928)&lt;/em&gt; and even recycles some of that picture&amp;#39;s footage. In true B-movie fashion, those shots use a different film stock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for Wayne, his performance is stiff and unsure, miles from his signature laconic persona.  At twenty-five, he was still learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there&amp;#39;s Blue Washington as Wayne&amp;#39;s sidekick. It&amp;#39;s an unfunny and demeaning role that sees him referred to as &amp;quot;boy&amp;quot; by Wayne and &amp;quot;watermelon mouth&amp;quot; by the villains. It makes a bad movie even worse.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>58. Suicide Squad (2016) ★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/suicide-squad-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/suicide-squad-2016/</id><updated>2016-08-29</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/suicide-squad-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/L01xxwaB8vaZvOMiNDzVOC1Zpc_5Q9yvh2aiaLXA780phd7z09v35NeuYvOXmIbQFnaQ1bb4PzKn=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;d think an ancient demon threatening armageddon would be hard to forget, but &lt;em&gt;Suicide Squad&lt;/em&gt; proves otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot concerns a group of incarcerated super-villains made to form a super-powered Delta Force. Will Smith plays Deadshot, an assassin who never misses. Margot Robbie plays Harley Quinn, a former psychiatrist whose super-power is finding The Joker attractive. Viola Davis plays Amanda Waller, the puppet-master who sells the project to the Washington brass. The rest of the cast fall somewhere between underwritten and extraneous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dirty Dozen (1976)&lt;/em&gt;, this ain&amp;#39;t. Deadshot won&amp;#39;t kill women or children. Harley&amp;#39;s just a brat in love with a psycho. &lt;em&gt;The Bad News Bears (1976)&lt;/em&gt; had more edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the Batman cameo disappoints. In &lt;em&gt;Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice (2016)&lt;/em&gt;, Batman erupted from the shadows to cripple thugs with brutal efficiency. Here, he floats down well-lit side streets to tap super-villains on the shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only characters packing genuine menace are Waller and The Joker, neither of whom is on the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Joker is hardly in the film. Jared Leto mashes up Heath Ledger&amp;#39;s intensity in &lt;em&gt;The Dark Knight (2008)&lt;/em&gt; with Jack Nicholson&amp;#39;s flamboyant camp in &lt;em&gt;Batman (1989)&lt;/em&gt;. The resulting performance is awful, but at least it holds your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest is forgettable. There&amp;#39;s a scene eighty-some-minutes in where the squad rescues Waller. I thought the movie over. But I&amp;#39;d forgotten the film&amp;#39;s antagonists, a pair of supernatural entities bent on world destruction or some-such. Instead of the end-credits, I faced forty more minutes of contrived plot and overwrought CGI, most of which I&amp;#39;d forgotten before I left the theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>57. The Killer Nun (1979) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-killer-nun-1979//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-killer-nun-1979/</id><updated>2016-08-19</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-killer-nun-1979/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/XCwo6MGUFHR5-etMd1PLMYPRVT3H2Kv6FBZ-hSnNgRSXRAlAw2Ktg28pc-fzYS9dE6MgfIrgGEZF=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a nunsploitation picture, boredom is a cardinal sin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anita Ekberg plays Sister Gertrude, a hospital matron with an unhinged psyche. She complains of intense headaches and steals to support a morphine addiction. Outside the hospital, she drinks, smokes, and has anonymous sex. During dinner, she reprimands a patient by stomping their dentures to pieces. In bed with a young nun, she orders her would-be paramour to “Say you&amp;#39;re a dirty whore.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, when patients turn up murdered, Sister Gertrude is the prime suspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this point, the film has abandoned the lurid sleaze and manic energy that carried the first half. In their place, we get a convoluted scheme to replace the head physician and a flimsy mystery. Worse still, we guess the big twist, making the film&amp;#39;s final half tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Killer Nun&lt;/em&gt; is trash, but not total trash, and that&amp;#39;s a shame.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>55. Chain Lightning (1950) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/chain-lightning-1950//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/chain-lightning-1950/</id><updated>2016-02-17</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/chain-lightning-1950/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/fXE6R_a57mB0-5L6fujb4hR1tEKUQ9FdNVRfjfmNjtwHrQHXAm5QJ8MOKSyLkERibOmdMlUcLRcv=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The skin-tight flight suit is a bridge too far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone younger with a fuller build might have pulled it off. William Holden or Kirk Douglas, maybe. But at 49, Humphrey Bogart looks ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story opens during World War II with Bogart as an enlisted pilot leading bombing runs and romancing a Red Cross worker played by Eleanor Parker. When he&amp;#39;s ordered home, Bogart and Parker try to marry but a series of contrivances thwarts their efforts and Bogart leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut to present day where more contrivances see a washed-up Bogart land a test pilot job for an aviation mogul played by Raymond Massey. Of course, Parker shows up as Massey’s secretary. She’s dating Massey’s chief engineer, played by Richard Whorf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflict arises when Bogart suggests piloting Massey’s experimental fighter jet from Alaska to Washington, D.C. It’s a stunt to convince the Washington brass the plane is ready for production. Whorf opposes the stunt, convinced the jet needs the new safety features he&amp;#39;s developing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Massey wants to produce the fighter now. Bogart wants the money the stunt will net him so he can propose to Parker. Whorf wants time to finish his safety innovations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Bogart races to Washington clad in the aforementioned flight suit, Whorf races to implement his new designs, using himself as a test pilot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a passable story buried in &lt;em&gt;Chain Lightning&lt;/em&gt;, but Bogart’s wrong for the role. The laughable sight of him squeezed into the flight suit distracts from the script’s foresight. Though common enough today, escape pods, pressurized flight suits, and braking parachutes were science fiction to 1950s audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compounding matters, the film pushes the melodrama, despite the three leads having no chemistry. Will Bogart and Parker get back together? Will there be obstacles to their romance? I think you know the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting film feels like one of Bogart’s pre-&lt;em&gt;Casablanca (1942)&lt;/em&gt; pictures that saw him cast in whatever assembly line production Warners was cranking out that week. Bogart deserved better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And really, what were they thinking with that flight suit?&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>54. Black Mass (2015) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/black-mass-2015//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/black-mass-2015/</id><updated>2016-02-06</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/black-mass-2015/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/hpK784BJIMAgPi4-toiRP4LCjxRXEuK1VBqsDmAFjMu5wD_49HtopxMBYOEUa2PUGiliFwEieLbI=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on a true story, &lt;em&gt;Black Mass&lt;/em&gt; sees Johnny Depp made up as a balding and paunchy James “Whitey” Bulger. The film follows Bulger’s ascent from small-time hood to crime-lord of South Boston. A journey made possible by the FBI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early in the film, the Feds offer Bulger a sweet deal. In exchange for information on the Italian mob in North Boston, the FBI leave Bulger’s crew alone. Even better, they eliminate the competition. Best of all, Bulger’s FBI handler is a South Boston native who idolizes him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the FBI ask is that Bulger not kill anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of course, Bulger kills people. He executes one of his lackeys. His gang somehow gets involved in Jai Alai and Bulger orders the commissioner killed. He strangles a young girl who may have talked to the cops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last murder was where the film lost me. It’s late in the film and the script introduces the girl only for Bulger to kill her five minutes later. The scene plays like something out of a horror movie and does nothing to build characterization or advance the plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also meet Bulger’s younger brother, a state senator played by Benedict Cumberbatch. Cumberbatch is good casting. His Boston accent may be jarring, but he’s believable as Depp’s brother. While both men seem too slight for their parts, they’re convincing as family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film invites comparisons with Scorsese’s &lt;em&gt;Goodfellas (1990)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Departed (2006)&lt;/em&gt;, but these comparisons underscore &lt;em&gt;Black Mass&lt;/em&gt;’s weakness: Bulger isn’t a compelling character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see Bulger build his empire, yet have no idea how he spends a typical day. He makes piles of money but, aside from a pair of cowboy boots, we never see him spend it. He suffers what we’re told are life-changing tragedies, yet seems unfazed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depp tries as Bulger, but he can’t compensate for the shallow characterization. He can’t disappear into the character because there is no character, just makeup and an accent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no psychological insight, &lt;em&gt;Black Mass&lt;/em&gt; feels hollow. We may learn much of Whitey Bulger’s life, but we learn very little about &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>53. The House That Dripped Blood (1971) ★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-house-that-dripped-blood-1971//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-house-that-dripped-blood-1971/</id><updated>2015-11-25</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-house-that-dripped-blood-1971/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/FMMgkimfRtPRm2id-f-ft-JjAMqk0TwHmvQnGRypZmP1imYN_H1srF3U69u_UnE9SHs0kDvsEXck=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reviewing anthology movies is hard. I picture you, dear reader, trudging through endless paragraphs of plot synopsis and I feel guilty. I have let you down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My duty as a reviewer is to describe the film. My job as a writer is to respect your time and attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so my challenge is to describe the picture in a succinct manner that holds your interest. Not that different, I suppose, from what I expect of the films I review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But just as I’m willing to humor a movie that stumbles, provided its intentions are good, I ask you, dear reader, to bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The House that Dripped Blood&lt;/em&gt; comprises four stories revolving around an old English country house. They vary in quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first story, &lt;em&gt;Method for Murder&lt;/em&gt;, sees a writer, Charles Hillyer, move into the house along with his wife. Hillyer writes lurid thrillers. He’s certain the house’s creaky atmosphere will help him finish his latest novel. Things take a turn for the macabre when Hillyer sees his literary creation, the murderous strangler Dominic, lurking around the estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a worn premise, but screenwriter Robert Bloch puts a twist on the twist that makes for a satisfying ending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second story, &lt;em&gt;Waxworks&lt;/em&gt;, follows a retired businessman named Philip Grayson, played by Peter Cushing. While touring a horrific wax museum in town, Grayson notices a figure that bears a striking resemblance to a girl he loved as a young man. Soon, he’s obsessed with the perceived effigy and, as you suspect, it doesn’t end well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the first installment, you’ll see the twist coming, but Cushing makes it work. Soon to be a widower in real life, Cushing brings a pathos to what’s otherwise a throw-away role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third story, &lt;em&gt;Sweets to the Sweet&lt;/em&gt; is the best. Christopher Lee plays John Reid, a widower. The details surrounding his wife’s death are hazy, and Reid doesn’t seem to miss her. He moves into the house with his young daughter, Jane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon arrival the estate agent gives them a tour of the house. When they reach a room with a lit fireplace, Jane runs crying from the fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reid hires a tutor for Jane, insisting she not go to school with other children. Astonished Jane has no toys of her own, the tutor buys her a small doll. Outraged, Reid throws the doll into the fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mystery builds to a satisfying conclusion, with Lee exploiting audience expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final story, &lt;em&gt;The Cloak&lt;/em&gt;, concerns an aging, egotistical horror actor named Paul Henderson. In a flat bit of meta-humor, he dismisses the current generation of horror films, saying he prefers the classics, like Dracula. Although he’s quick to add “The Lugosi one, not this new chap.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot kicks in when Henderson acquires a cape that belonged to an actual vampire. Wearing it, Henderson sprouts fangs, loses his reflection, and gains the ability to fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s played as camp, which is a shame. Co-star Ingrid Pitt, strikes the right balance, but Jon Pertwee’s performance as Henderson never hooked me. The resulting segment fails to thrill or amuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anthology films are hard to grade. My rating averages the individual segments. The third piece’s excellences cancels the fourth’s failed camp. But Christopher Lee’s segment is enough to recommend &lt;em&gt;The House that Dripped Blood&lt;/em&gt;. After all, if the other stories don’t seem appealing, there’s always the fast-forward button.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>52. And Now the Screaming Starts! (1973) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/and-now-the-screaming-starts-1973//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/and-now-the-screaming-starts-1973/</id><updated>2015-11-23</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/and-now-the-screaming-starts-1973/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ARAju_iOzOZS1h9gLHUDw4QAGydv9SsG4HZQsJiX5a8f3ycYf4GtzXm8UcCk5yNsH-Kf_mWJe2cA=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The severed hand is surprisingly effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gory details aside, the story feels familiar. Attractive young Catherine marries handsome young English nobleman Charles. They move into his ancestral manor. Strange things happen. Bumps in the night. Catherine sees visions of a man with a severed hand and empty, bleeding eye sockets. An unseen apparition rapes her in their marriage bed…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don’t forget the severed hand. It’s always lurking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catherine begins to suspect Charles is keeping something from her. She digs for the truth, but every time she gets close, someone ends up dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, Catherine is pregnant. Charles, worried for her sanity, calls in Dr. Pope, played by Peter Cushing. Pope is like a non-believing Van Helsing in an atrocious wig. Though he’s window dressing tangential to plot, Peter Cushing’s always welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the script mishandles the mystery. Rather than dole out clues, it reveals everything in a single flashback before the film’s finale. This approach only works if the script leads the audience to a wrong conclusion before shocking them straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we guess the big twist long before the script gets around to revealing it. Then we have to sit through the drawn out ending. The big reveal should be the climax, not precede it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s the film’s biggest problem. It overstays its welcome. Even at 91 minutes, it’s too long. Granted, the rain during the finale is a nice touch, but, then again, everything in the film looks great. It’s the execution that’s lacking. &lt;em&gt;And Now the Screaming Starts&lt;/em&gt; has all the ingredients for solid gothic thriller. It just screws up the recipe.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>51. Asylum (1972) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/asylum-1972//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/asylum-1972/</id><updated>2015-11-21</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/asylum-1972/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/vWbQ1BsWKuqKq1IweFXLKqjbv4uj3SXMUqTcCFtf3q_hZJEabfVxWIsxpxZeLAwBOGo5l0wHcWaF=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Asylum&lt;/em&gt; is another anthology horror from Amicus Productions. As with &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-house-that-dripped-blood-1971/&quot;&gt;The House That Dripped Blood (1971)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, the script comes courtesy of Robert Bloch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The framing story follows a young doctor named Martin. Martin is interviewing for a position at an asylum for the “incurable insane”. He’s greeted with several surprises. The asylum head, Dr. Starr, has gone insane himself and is now counted amongst the asylum’s patients. Starr’s replacement, Dr. Rutherford, is wheel-chair bound after a patient attack. As if those weren’t enough red flags,  Rutherford makes Martin an unusual offer. Martin can have the job provided he deduces which of the patients is Dr. Starr. Martin protests, but heads upstairs to interview the patients. The bulk of the film illustrates their stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first story concerns a man who murders his wife, chops up her body, wraps the parts in packing paper, and stores them in a basement freezer. Unfortunately, said wife had a magic bracelet. When the husband tosses the bracelet into the freezer, the body parts spring to life, attacking him and his mistress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These types of stories always fail to suspend my disbelief. Not the resurrection part which is creepy with a nice touch where we see a severed head sucking air through the paper wrap. No, the problem lies in the physics of those body parts moving about. Just because they’re reanimated, it doesn’t give them the ability to fly. Yet, how else to explain a severed head climbing a flight of stairs? We see arms and legs lurching about and it looks laughable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we meet Bruno, a former tailor. Broke and facing eviction, Bruno finds salvation in a mysterious gentlemen named Smith. Played by Peter Cushing, Smith offers an extraordinary sum for Bruno to make a suit for Smith’s son. Smith insists Bruno must work according to Smith’s precise specifications. These include oddities such as only working on the suit during the late night and early morning hours. Bruno agrees to Smith’s demands and, a few nights later, arrives on Smith’s doorstep with the suit. To Bruno’s horror, Smith reveals that he has no money to pay. This will prove to be Smith’s smallest surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In what will become a running theme, the special effects are the story’s undoing. Cushing is great, and the story’s mystery held my attention. But the finale relies on another effect I couldn’t swallow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third entry is more grounded. The story concerns a young woman named Barbara, played by Charlotte Rampling. Barbara is fresh from psychiatric care and under the careful watch of her brother and a nurse. Soon, Barbara’s mischievous friend Lucy shows up. Lucy urges Barbara not to take her medication. Not good for Barbara’s brother and nurse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story is most effective of the lot, but the big reveal will be obvious to anyone with a passing knowledge of the horror genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last tale involves Dr. Byron, played by Herbert Lom. Byron has perfected soul transference and transfers his essence into a small effigy. The figure resembles a robot as tall as a can of soda with a plastic Herbert Lom head. It looks as ridiculous as it sounds. The stop motion animation reminded me of the Rankin Bass Christmas specials. Despite its appearance, it’s quite deadly, as Dr. Rutherford soon discovers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What to make of this final tale? I can’t imagine anyone finding it frightening. Did director Roy Ward Baker give up and try for camp?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what of &lt;em&gt;Asylum&lt;/em&gt; as a whole? Given the talent involved, it’s a let down. Instead of exploiting its able cast, &lt;em&gt;Asylum&lt;/em&gt;’s script relies on special effects the production can’t deliver. The one time it &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; lean on its cast, it forces poor Charlotte Rampling through a tired trope. Still, it held my attention, so that’s something.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>50. Big City Blues (1932) ★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/big-city-blues-1932//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/big-city-blues-1932/</id><updated>2015-09-21</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/big-city-blues-1932/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/No22yUXPMksosLp6bX1NHDxgotjK_F9Ya0KvrxCJMhMCFTQTlUFLOsTh1uP8yK-CpORwr8dGSeT1=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;em&gt;Big City Blues&lt;/em&gt; because it features an early, uncredited performance from Humphrey Bogart. Given the film’s obscurity, my expectations were low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story follows Bud, played by Eric Linden. Bud is a young man from Hoopersville, an Indiana town with a population of just eight thousand. Bud’s inherited a small sum and can’t wait to escape small-town life. He buys a train ticket for New York City. Convinced the big city will eat him alive, the station staff wager Bud will return within a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon arriving, Bud checks into a posh suite at the expensive Hotel Hercules. This at the suggestion of Bud’s only contact in New York, his cousin Gibboney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cousin Gibboney is a fast-talking piece of work. When Bud says he’s paying eight dollars per day for his suite, Gibboney feigns nonchalance. “Well don’t worry about that,” Gibboney says, “I’ll just have that chopped right in half. I’ll speak to the manager of the hotel, he’s an old pal of mine.” Later, Gibboney explains, “That room was supposed to go for twelve dollars a day, but don’t worry, I spoke to the manager and I fixed it. It’s all right. You can have it for eight.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gibboney introduces Bud to a couple of chorus girls, including Vida, played by Joan Blondell. Vida and Bud make googly eyes. Gibboney invites the girls to a party in Bud’s suite later that evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Bud’s money, Gibboney acquires some black market booze. Assorted partiers arrive. Bud and Vida flirt, ignoring the crowd and the hooch. Credit the film for accuracy here, as the crowd goes from jubilant antics to a drunken stupor as the night wears on. As the guest begin to leave, there’s a drunken fight between two men, one played by Bogart. The lights go out. When they come back on, one guest is dead. The remaining partygoers flee, including Vida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The police figure Bud for the murder, and issue a warrant for his arrest. Alone and short on funds, Bud reunites with Vida in a speakeasy. He uses the last of his money to gamble, hoping to win enough to secure a future with Vida. Bud wins back his losses and then some, but of course, he doesn’t quit while he’s ahead. Bud loses everything. Then the police pounce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film plays as a cautionary fable, but the pre-code script imbues New York with a certain allure. Part of said allure is Blondell as Vida. She’s all wholesome charm tinged with a bad-girl streak. Like a spiked milkshake. Before gambling away his money, Bud wonders if they should just leave. Vida replies, “I don’t wanna leave. I wanna stay where there’s noise and excitement and crowds!” Judging by Bud’s reaction, this is just the response he wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linden plays Bud as naive without being cloying. The script helps. In a lesser film, Bud would be judgmental. Here, he doesn’t object to the bootleg gin and he knows his way around a dice game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a great film, but it’s not a bad one either. It held my interest and even offered a chuckle or two via Gibboney’s rapid-fire dialog. I may have watched &lt;em&gt;Big City Blues&lt;/em&gt; for Bogart, but I enjoyed more than just his small role.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>