<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'><title>Frank's Movie Log</title><subtitle>Quality reviews of films of questionable quality.</subtitle><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/feed.xml' rel='self' /><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com' /><updated>2016-11-21T22:34:50-05:00</updated><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com</id><author><name>Frank Showalter</name></author><entry><title>70. Sagebrush Trail (1933) ★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/sagebrush-trail-1933//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/sagebrush-trail-1933/</id><updated>2016-11-21</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/sagebrush-trail-1933/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/t-YlFZzOBSK4QJXy7XZhfQhiwqqlYvXoJF85WXSfOPlWXg3hHjw5PbUBFp96zepLn2A6HWSVaxG3=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The underwater scenes in &lt;em&gt;Sagebrush Trail&lt;/em&gt; belie its shoestring budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those scenes come early. John Wayne plays a fugitive named John (of course) stowed away aboard a freight train. As the train pulls into the station, lawmen are waiting. After some cat and mouse, John hops a horse and flees into the countryside. The lawmen pursue. John dead-ends at a lake, dismounts, and dives into the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see John underwater, breathing through a reed. It&amp;#39;s not a special effect. I&amp;#39;m not sure how they shot these scenes, but that&amp;#39;s Wayne underwater, breathing through a stick in what looks like a lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After eluding the lawmen, who believe him dead, John surfaces and encounters a gunslinger. The gunslinger, recognizing a fellow desperado, introduces himself as Jones and invites John to join an outlaw gang. John accepts and he and Jones become fast-friends and rivals for the local shopgirl, Sally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, John&amp;#39;s not really a bad guy. He passes notes to Sally warning her of the gang&amp;#39;s intentions. And of course, it was Jones who committed the crime pinned on John. And of course, John doesn&amp;#39;t discover this until the second act&amp;#39;s end. But you know what? I didn&amp;#39;t mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sagebrush Trail&lt;/em&gt; may suffer from predictable plotting, stilted dialog, and fight scenes where the participants punch each other&amp;#39;s shoulders, but I still enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the aforementioned underwater scenes, I liked the location photography and wipe transitions. And the script&amp;#39;s making Jones a flawed but likable character was a nice touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most of all, I liked Wayne. This was his second production for Monogram Pictures, after &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/riders-of-destiny-1933/&quot;&gt;Riders of Destiny (1933)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Though Wayne struggles with the romantic comedy scenes, he&amp;#39;s making strides as a performer. More than ever before, we see flashes of his famous Duke persona. And judging by the underwater scenes, he&amp;#39;s doing some of his own stunts to boot.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>69. The Sentinel (1977) ★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-sentinel-1977//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-sentinel-1977/</id><updated>2016-11-14</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-sentinel-1977/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/kxf7iIKKYoFRZdgn7mW5D-IVUDAGpSn0VjUjuQp1L5vB-Mooasc61eOcROuNr7gtSs9VcbwociKh=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chris Sarandon saves &lt;em&gt;The Sentinel&lt;/em&gt; from its own excess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film stars Cristina Raines as a fashion model who moves into a fantastic apartment in a converted Brooklyn brownstone. A series of strange encounters with her eccentric neighbors leaves her paranoid and on edge. Her boyfriend, a hot-shot defense attorney played by Sarandon, investigates and uncovers a horrific conspiracy involving the Catholic Church and a gateway to Hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The setup invites comparisons to &lt;em&gt;Rosemary’s Baby (1968)&lt;/em&gt;. But unlike that film, which was about women&amp;#39;s reproductive rights, &lt;em&gt;The Sentinel&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;#39;t about anything. It&amp;#39;s an exploitation picture offering a smorgasbord of gore, nudity, lesbianism, human deformities, and female masturbation. I don&amp;#39;t mind these things. I object to the film’s middling execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Movie fans will enjoy spotting the once and future stars peppering the cast. José Ferrer as an unnamed robed figure. Ava Gardner as a charming real estate agent. Burgess Meredith as a creepy neighbor. Eli Wallach as a cagey detective. Christopher Walken as Wallach’s grinning partner. Jeff Goldblum as a fashion photographer. Beverly D’Angelo as a mute exhibitionist. An unrecognizable John Carradine as an aging priest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the film wastes its talented ensemble. It regulates most of the former stars, like Ferrer, Gardner, and Carradine, to throwaway roles for name recognition. Other performances veer into camp. Beverly D’Angelo’s memorable scene elicits chuckles instead of chills. Eli Wallach&amp;#39;s phoned-in turn plays as caricature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sprawling cast is a byproduct of the convoluted, nonsensical plot. Consider the scene where a character breaks through a wall in the brownstone and uncovers a plaque bearing an inscription from Dante’s &lt;em&gt;Inferno&lt;/em&gt;. It’s the film in a microcosm: effective and atmospheric, but its logic crumbles under the slightest scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What saved the film for me was Sarandon. Despite sporting a mustache that only adds to the film&amp;#39;s second-rate feel, Sarandon is perfect in his role. He avoids the idiot plot and acts according to character. And there&amp;#39;s just something about him playing a charming but ruthless character that I enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I saw &lt;em&gt;The Sentinel&lt;/em&gt;, I thought its mix of camp and shock hit more often than it missed—if only just. Watching it again, I’m not so sure. The performances don’t hold up well to repeat viewings, but Sarandon was every bit as good as I remembered.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>68. Curse of the Demon (1958) ★★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/curse-of-the-demon-1958//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/curse-of-the-demon-1958/</id><updated>2016-11-07</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/curse-of-the-demon-1958/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Qyy-4N8MQjl3tTIF-bHyjNuAgoZghlz7L_FdCwONdmhmLDcEex-ieWdSWnPa0XmPI6m3Tc3ZplgA=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;A producer&amp;#39;s meddling keeps &lt;em&gt;Curse of the Demon&lt;/em&gt; from perfection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story sees American psychologist John Holden (Dana Andrews) travel to London. He&amp;#39;s there to expose self-professed black magician Julian Karswell (Niall MacGinnis) as a fraud. Karswell tries to dissuade Holden, but Holden remains resolute. Karswell then announces Holden will die in three days. Holden is skeptical, but after a series of unexplained events, his skepticism crumbles and he begins to fear for his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the best kind of thriller: one populated by intelligent characters who behave according to their personalities, not the whims of the plot. It avoids cheap jump-scares. Instead, director Jacques Tourneur uses atmosphere to build tension. Shadowy hallways and darkened rooms keep us on edge. And, for the real horror, there&amp;#39;s Niall MacGinnis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved MacGinnis&amp;#39; performance. It&amp;#39;s a perfect combination of charm and menace. There&amp;#39;s a great scene where Holden has broken into Karswell&amp;#39;s palatial home. In the darkness, a house cat transforms into a leopard and attacks. Holden struggles for his life, only escaping once Karswell enters and turns on the lights. Karswell treats the intruding Holden as one would treat a party guest who&amp;#39;d gotten lost looking for the bathroom. By underplaying the role, MacGinnis makes the character all the more sinister. Christopher Lee built a career on similar performances. And yet, MacGinnis conveys a vulnerability beneath the bluster that adds unexpected depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opposite MacGinnis, Andrews delivers a curious turn. His cadence and speech patterns mimic John Wayne&amp;#39;s. They&amp;#39;re so similar, I wonder if it was a deliberate impersonation. This brings up an interesting tangent. The Duke played many roles in many movies, but he never made a straight horror picture. Judging by Andrews&amp;#39; performance here, Wayne could have pulled it off with flair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, despite the solid script, competent direction and inspired performances, &lt;em&gt;Curse of the Demon&lt;/em&gt; falters. The opening sequence sees the titular demon marching out of the woods. A similar sequence occurs at the film&amp;#39;s end. In both, the demon’s mechanical movement and frozen expression scream rubber suit. My wife thought it resembled a homecoming float. Not only do these shots cheapen the film, they undermine any sense of ambiguity regarding Karswell&amp;#39;s powers. Holden is the audience surrogate. His skepticism is our skepticism. But this falls apart when we know Karswell&amp;#39;s powers are real from the outset. Instead of questioning things along with Holden, we grow impatient waiting for him to catch up. A great psychological thriller devolves into a cheap monster movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can thank producer Hal E. Chester. He added the demon shots after principal photography wrapped. Tourneur and Andrews fought him on it. Writer Charles Bennett threatened to shoot Chester dead. They all lost. The studio, Columbia, did cut some footage for the American release, but not of the monster. What a shame.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>67. Torso (1973) ★★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/torso-1973//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/torso-1973/</id><updated>2016-10-31</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/torso-1973/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Y_IbflpaJ_iIgxd1thi7OTYEH7xp1iHj-4VSR24Zf_hdegkTj4DiKnlsPbZDUSWau43K9mlO7qXu=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Torso&lt;/em&gt; executes a generic plot with panache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film takes place in scenic Perugia, Italy. A masked killer strangles two female university students, sparking a manhunt. Another student thinks she recognizes the murder weapon, leading to threatening phone calls from the killer. Alarmed, she retreats to a cliff-side villa with four girlfriends, including an American exchange student, played by Suzy Kendall. The killer, of course, follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It plays as a mystery, inviting us to guess the killer’s identity. The script proffers a myriad of suspects, painting almost every male character as possessive, misogynistic, or perverted. The few that appear normal feel suspect by comparison. I admit, it fooled me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mystery aside, what I enjoyed most about &lt;em&gt;Torso&lt;/em&gt; was its style. There’s a scene where the killer tracks a girl through a swampy marsh. The lighting, camerawork, and editing create a kind of kinetic claustrophobia. The more she runs, the more her world shrinks. Even as the tension held me rapt, the sheer craft made me smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it gets better. The last act sees Kendall locked in a bedroom. She slides a piece of newspaper under the door, hoping to catch the key as she forces it out of the lock. I won&amp;#39;t spoil what happens, but I will say this scene caps twenty-some dialog-free minutes that serve as a master class in suspense. They&amp;#39;re so good, I forgave the finale, which sees the killer reveal his identity and explain his psychosis via some awkward and disappointing exposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only problem with &lt;em&gt;Torso&lt;/em&gt; lies with its heroines. I liked how the film paints them as strong, independent women. Fleeing to a remote outpost wasn&amp;#39;t the smartest move, but it was refreshing to see them do something besides run to the nearest man for protection. If only the script had provided them with distinct personalities. Aside from Kendall’s character, they felt interchangeable and never endeared themselves. It’s a common problem with mysteries. We learn more about the various red herrings than about the protagonists.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>66. The Pit (1981) ★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-pit-1981//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-pit-1981/</id><updated>2016-10-24</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-pit-1981/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/RWu-i9XAIElgsPF4HpQlnhdTYfxFpZP8rncZVWqoLYegY2CFhA4z3m181oKEfq5twCg1-2PXioSr=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pit&lt;/em&gt; careens between laughable and disturbing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We meet Jamie, a twelve-year-old boy transitioning to adolescence. He’s noticed girls and nudie-books, but still clings to his teddy bear. When his parents take a trip, Jamie develops a crush on the live-in babysitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a reasonable set-up for a coming-of-age comedy, but the script takes a different direction. Jamie’s teddy bear urges him to do things. Bad things, like watch his babysitter while she sleeps, or terrorize a neighbor into stripping nude as he snaps Polaroids, or frame a man for murder, or feed people to a pit of trolls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way the movie lumps the titular pit in with Jamie’s other deviations is part of its quirky charm. The troll effects look cheap, and the entire premise of luring people into a giant hole in the woods is silly. It’s as though the filmmakers knew they couldn’t make these bits scary, so they opted for weird. It works. Instead of a forgettable monster movie we get oddball schlock. And I love how obnoxious the film paints Jamie’s victims. Early on, Jamie, looking lonesome, approaches an older boy and girl. Jamie says little more than “Hi,” before the older boy punches him in the face. No reason, the boy’s just mean. When Jamie feeds him to the trolls, we’re not sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s another movie lurking beneath the inanity. A much darker one. Bits and pieces surface, like Jamie alluding to his mother molesting him, or the aforementioned scene where he watches his babysitter sleep. These scenes transcend the schlock and convey a genuine sense of unease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end, &lt;em&gt;The Pit&lt;/em&gt; is unlike anything I’ve seen. It’s not a good film, but its off-beat nature intrigues. You laugh as Jamie wheels an old biddy into the pit, then feel your skin crawl as he hits on his babysitter. It’s a wild ride.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>65. Phantasm (1979) ★★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/phantasm-1979//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/phantasm-1979/</id><updated>2016-10-17</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/phantasm-1979/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/IVL-n1s23XRh7rcJSbW0dd8L3wFqy6hiU7HbYF-bJg6XfZgWI7JOTI0XLhTRis5qXDs_3X5ShVAz=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was still watching Saturday morning cartoons and struggling with cursive writing when I first saw &lt;em&gt;Phantasm&lt;/em&gt;. It traumatized  me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s told from a kid’s point-of view. A boy who’s put away his toys but hasn&amp;#39;t yet discovered girls. His parents died a few months earlier in a car crash. Now, he follows his older brother everywhere. In the process, he uncovers some strange goings-on involving the local mortician, played by Angus Scrimm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love how writer-director Don Coscarelli avoids traditional plot tropes. When no one believes him, the kid breaks into the mortuary. After evading a lethal flying ball, he escapes with a gruesome piece of evidence. The next morning, he shows his older brother, who takes a single look and says, “Okay, I believe you.” A lesser film would see the boy lose the evidence during his escape, or have the older brother dismiss it with some awkward rationalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t reveal any more of the plot, as much of the film&amp;#39;s joy comes from the unexpected directions it takes. It plays like a surreal nightmare. Scenes feel disjointed. We often sense we’re missing something. These seeming plot holes only add to the film’s unrelenting sense of unease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it’s often lumped in with the slasher pictures that dominated early 80s horror, &lt;em&gt;Phantasm&lt;/em&gt; stands apart. It’s equal parts science fiction and dark fantasy. Take out the brief nudity and iconic chrome ball, and you&amp;#39;d have a PG-13 film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But about that ball. Those with squeamish stomachs may find it rough. As a special effect, it’s a collision of imagination,  exploitation, and blood. Lots of blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That ball pushed my younger self over the edge. I had nightmares for weeks. So much of the film, from the stark white mortuary interiors to Scrimm himself, looks unsettling. It sounds unsettling too, with an ominous, disconcerting score that adds to the film&amp;#39;s impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching it now, &lt;em&gt;Phantasm&lt;/em&gt; plays like a remake of the film I saw as a child. Scenes tug at memories of a more brutal experience. One that carved itself into my malleable psyche and sewed the seeds of my predilection for nihilistic, nightmarish horror. &lt;em&gt;Phantasm&lt;/em&gt; may not be perfect, but it made an impression.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>64. Mars Attacks! (1996) ★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/mars-attacks-1996//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/mars-attacks-1996/</id><updated>2016-10-10</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/mars-attacks-1996/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/UaIryK7fdz3ppPVenyCpIZH8N_igIhz5H5gSo31rmY4OQilJabolh4ji7z45AKK3ztNCGlMDiHOQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mars Attacks!&lt;/em&gt; could have been awful but settles for mediocre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film jumps between several storylines as aliens from Mars attack Earth. We follow the President and his staff, a pair of television personalities, a family in rural Kansas, a sleazy Las Vegas developer, and a washed up heavyweight boxer. Jack Nicholson leads an all-star cast as both the President and the Vegas developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The studio advertised the film as spoofing 1950s science-fiction pictures, but it doesn’t play that way. Among the cast, it&amp;#39;s telling that amateur actor and former NFL fullback Jim Brown seems the most comfortable. He plays the boxer reduced to dressing as a pharaoh for an Egyptian-themed casino. When the Martians attack, Brown heads out to reunite with his ex-wife (Pam Grier) and kids. He gets some help from Tom Jones, who plays himself. There’s a wonderful scene where Brown asks Jones, “Do you know how to fly a plane?” to which Jones replies, “Of course! You got one?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sort of goofball casting matches the goofy sci-fi premise.  Brown and Jones both seem aware of their shortcomings as actors, and their stiff performances are genuine and entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a glimpse of the movie I suspect director Tim Burton wanted to make. He seems less interested in spoofing the genre than recreating it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not a bad idea, but no one told the big-name cast. Few appear to enjoy the material. Most convey a sense of condescension, their performances screaming “I’m overacting on purpose!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did they have a choice? Unlike Brown and Jones, the rest of the cast can’t pretend they’re amateurs. And playing it straight wouldn’t have helped. Pam Grier plays her role with such conviction, her scenes feel spliced in from a different film. Martin Short plays his role as though he were in an overt comedy, to similar effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least they got the Martians right. The 1950s films featured serious monsters cobbled together with silly effects. Here, we get cartoonish villains brought to life with no visible wires, seams, or zippers. In my favorite scene, the Martians laser a national monument, catch the falling debris with their flying saucer, and redirect the rubble onto a fleeing tour group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, &lt;em&gt;Mars Attacks!&lt;/em&gt; underwhelms. It’s a rare movie that would be much better were it much worse.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>63. Riders of Destiny (1933) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/riders-of-destiny-1933//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/riders-of-destiny-1933/</id><updated>2016-10-03</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/riders-of-destiny-1933/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/XQ2i0QG1HLggAkzMOlhIq5OtUnqD7MgY0WHbIdKxNDMyCEzlFNnQ5iKW-qG8I2CKbWqMvUPaEj1U=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riders of Destiny&lt;/em&gt; is not a good movie, but it is an important one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It opens with John Wayne on horseback, strumming a guitar and singing a solemn ballad. The voice isn&amp;#39;t Wayne&amp;#39;s, and it&amp;#39;s clear he won&amp;#39;t win any lip-sync awards. After his introduction, Wayne evades some bad guys in a scene that tries for slapstick but fails. Soon, he’s embroiled in a water-rights dispute between some ranchers and a shady businessman. Suffering from laughable dialog and stilted pacing, the film works best when it cuts to the action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overseen by Yakima Canutt, the stunts pack a raw, visceral energy. One, a horse and rider diving off a cliff into a lake, proved so impressive, the studio recycled it for later productions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was John Wayne&amp;#39;s first film for Monogram Pictures. Over the next two years, Monogram would cast Wayne as the lead in 16 productions, all westerns. They were quick and cheap shoots, wrapping in a week with budgets of around ten-thousand dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these films, Wayne began crafting his on-screen image. During production, he bonded with the stuntmen over drinks and card games. Many were real cowboys. Wayne’s desire to emulate their physicality and mannerisms formed the foundation of his iconic posture, gait, and cadence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;#39;t recommend &lt;em&gt;Riders of Destiny&lt;/em&gt;, but for John Wayne fans it&amp;#39;s an opportunity to watch the fledgling actor workshop a persona that would become legend.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>62. The Witch (2015) ★★★★★</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-witch-2015//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-witch-2015/</id><updated>2016-09-26</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-witch-2015/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ucvDLbqgo5JvXCTKiEugYUB1ayTWCbri8PrvJj7L0cD9COZ8cgaw1okLe7N8a8vb93R21wm8LbjT=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witch&lt;/em&gt; gets better with each viewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without revealing too much, the story follows a Puritan family exiled from their plantation in 17th century New England. Alone in the wild, they establish a small farm outside a looming forest. Tragedies beset them. As the stress mounts, they turn against one another, unaware of the horror lurking in the woods nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film requires active listening. Writer-director Robert Eggers sourced his dialog from documents and diaries written during the film’s period. The resulting English sounds a step removed from our own, packed with thees and thous and unfamiliar inflections. Those expecting to sit back, tune out, and be entertained may find themselves frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Eggers rewards our attention. The film’s credibility astounds. The production built a working farm and lit it with near-natural light sources. Eggers scoured Canada for a forest that could pass for New England woodland. The remote location he chose doubles well enough, yet still seems alien and ominous. It’s an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cast helps. Everyone impresses, but Anya Taylor-Joy astounds. Her performance as a teenage girl coming of age on a puritanical farm feels both original and authentic, and  she delivers it with startling ease. The only thing I didn&amp;#39;t buy were her teeth. Like the rest of the cast, they were too perfect. In a lesser picture, I wouldn&amp;#39;t have noticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a film of jump-scares or gory set pieces. The story unfolds with a grim, nihilistic inevitability. Take out the supernatural elements and you still have a riveting drama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what makes &lt;em&gt;The Witch&lt;/em&gt; so special. It works as a horror movie. It works as a drama. It works as a fable. It works as an indictment of patriarchal societies. Like all great films, it rewards subsequent viewings. Whether you&amp;#39;re savoring the attention to detail, or exploring the subtext, the film satisfies. As of this writing, I’ve seen it twice. That&amp;#39;s not nearly enough.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>61. Ride Him, Cowboy (1932) &#x2605;&#x2605;</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/ride-him-cowboy-1932//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/ride-him-cowboy-1932/</id><updated>2016-09-19</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/ride-him-cowboy-1932/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/E-QB2xmfRBF3cjt4GWqiNxjZOqiPaHo5_wbatcoAr0x6dppxSllTDAwdazWYBsjB_T2p5RAE_LGY=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Ride Him, Cowboy&lt;/em&gt;, a town puts a horse on trial for attempted murder. This may not be the film&amp;#39;s most ridiculous scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the second production, following &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/haunted-gold-1932/&quot;&gt;Haunted Gold (1932)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, under a six-picture contract John Wayne signed with Warner Bros. It’s a remake of &lt;em&gt;The Unknown Cavalier (1926)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Warner Bros. acquired First National Pictures a few years prior, they inherited the rights to several silent westerns starring Ken Maynard. These were popular, A-list productions featuring Maynard’s impressive stunt work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warner Bros. sought to remake the Maynard silents with sound, recycling as much footage as possible, reshooting only the close-ups and interiors. All they needed was an actor who matched Maynard’s build. Enter Wayne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayne plays a wandering cowboy who tries to apprehend a mysterious outlaw known as The Hawk, only to end up framed for the outlaw&amp;#39;s crimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening sequence reveals The Hawk&amp;#39;s identity, so there&amp;#39;s no mystery. It also telegraphs the finale by introducing someone who can identify The Hawk. Granted, said person lies comatose but, as the doctor says, “He&amp;#39;ll be fine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This absurdity continues to the aforementioned horse trial, through Wayne&amp;#39;s introduction, and to his framing. This consists of The Hawk dropping Wayne&amp;#39;s monogrammed harmonica after raiding a homestead. That&amp;#39;s all the town needs to lynch Wayne. As they say, “We&amp;#39;ve got incontrovertible proof.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, despite the inanity, or perhaps because of it, the script surprises. When the female lead finds herself surrounded by The Hawk&amp;#39;s gang, she isn’t captured. Instead, she displays surprising wit and actually rescues Wayne. It&amp;#39;s only &lt;em&gt;later&lt;/em&gt; that she’s captured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for Wayne, he&amp;#39;s still learning. You catch glimpses of his iconic persona, such as his reaction shots during his sham trial, but they&amp;#39;re rare.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>