<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'><title>Frank's Movie Log</title><subtitle>Quality reviews of films of questionable quality.</subtitle><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/feed.xml' rel='self' /><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com' /><updated>2017-04-22T20:17:04-04:00</updated><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com</id><author><name>Frank Showalter</name></author><entry><title>Shock (1946)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/shock-1946//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/shock-1946/</id><updated>2017-04-17</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/shock-1946/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/6goXr9YlP7Fo6zg1X2R9Eabmn-iXHhtD_SzG8_NS529ejrdyrMOsr-84JqJD27uXP0AdxK7UX193n22YMpKuEEs6byE7ZARY8QQYfgGC04y3opLJEHFuTEP60qYCo1d4mJhJMQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;You won&amp;#39;t believe me when I tell you not to watch &lt;em&gt;Shock&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially if you&amp;#39;re a Vincent Price fan. The plot alone will convince you it&amp;#39;s worth watching. Price plays a psychiatrist who murders his wife. Unbeknownst to him, Anabel Shaw&amp;#39;s character witnesses the murder from her hotel room. The sight renders her catatonic and she falls under the care of—you guessed it—Price&amp;#39;s character. Better still: Shaw&amp;#39;s character spies the murder only after waking from an anxiety-laden nightmare, calling into question her reliability as a narrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could play as a cross between &lt;em&gt;Rebecca (1940)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Suspicion (1941)&lt;/em&gt;. Instead, it plays like &lt;em&gt;Double Indemnity (1944)&lt;/em&gt;. There&amp;#39;s no doubt Price&amp;#39;s character is guilty. He&amp;#39;s egged on by femme fatale Lynn Bari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can hear you saying to yourself, “That sounds interesting.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m here to tell you, it isn&amp;#39;t. Price doesn&amp;#39;t register as charming or sinister. He has zero chemistry with Bari, who herself fails to register as seductive or cunning. This renders the entire film rather boring, which as I&amp;#39;ve written before, is a film&amp;#39;s most unforgivable sin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;#39;s face it: if you&amp;#39;re a Vincent Price fan, you won&amp;#39;t believe me. Price played this sort of role so well in so many later pictures, you can&amp;#39;t fathom him falling flat. To those fans, I offer this condolence: if you make it through the film, you&amp;#39;ll see the ending, which I found so unintentionally funny I laughed aloud. So that&amp;#39;s something.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Breakfast at Tiffany's (1961)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/breakfast-at-tiffanys-1961//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/breakfast-at-tiffanys-1961/</id><updated>2017-04-10</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/breakfast-at-tiffanys-1961/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/5tMVCQoWpYy9bfXzSIoJ5yCNDbDSQ0Bt_i22ZWy_HDHZxAn7xpetQeXKUhgVEsTy0wrSf0Qmy7IhXz8fHirBCDye9Jv3Bg4csWLoxU_DLXcgZ8q0P69nIyr3hVNnZTkAZeE-Uw=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s Audrey Hepburn&amp;#39;s movie, but George Peppard deserves some credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His performance channels a young William Holden or Steve McQueen. Sure, seeing colonel John &amp;quot;Hannibal&amp;quot; Smith play a romantic lead will shock those of a certain age, but the jolt is short-lived. Peppard pulls off the role with aplomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts with his clothes. Okay—not really, but I love his wardrobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peppard plays Paul, a writer posing as a gigolo or vice versa. As the film opens, he&amp;#39;s moving into a converted New York brownstone apartment. There he meets Holly Golightly, a quirky socialite played by Hepburn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He falls for her. She for him. Complications ensue. What makes &lt;em&gt;Breakfast at Tiffany&amp;#39;s&lt;/em&gt; special is not the plot, but the characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul and Holly are both damaged people, skirting responsibility and commitment with a fear bordering on phobic. When Paul meets Holly he&amp;#39;s drawn by her fragile nature. The diminutive Hepburn looks the part. Paul longs to swoop in and save Holly. Unlike her other suitors, Paul&amp;#39;s in no position to save anyone, he&amp;#39;s just as wounded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patricia Neal plays the rich, married woman who pays Paul&amp;#39;s rent and keeps him in nice clothes. She makes an impression by underplaying her role. As does Buddy Ebsen as a lovesick figure from Holly&amp;#39;s shadowy past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s this willingness to embrace flawed characters—and not flawed in cute ways, but morally suspect ones—that makes &lt;em&gt;Breakfast at Tiffany&amp;#39;s&lt;/em&gt; stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, we get plenty of soft focus close-ups, Mickey Rooney as a racist caricature meant as comic relief, and a finale set in a rainy, yet well-lit alley, but &lt;em&gt;Breakfast at Tiffany&amp;#39;s&lt;/em&gt; transcends the tropes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest complaint lies with the ending. Holly isn&amp;#39;t a real person, she&amp;#39;s a ghost, drifting in and out of people&amp;#39;s lives, leaving an indelible impression. That Paul could end up with her doesn&amp;#39;t ring true. She&amp;#39;s not the girl you marry, she&amp;#39;s the girl you wonder about years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it&amp;#39;s a great film and Hepburn deserves the kudos showered upon her performance. But it works because Peppard wins us over too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Logan (2017)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/logan-2017//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/logan-2017/</id><updated>2017-04-03</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/logan-2017/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/i8MoyM90ZwROOXuzUTOhkM9j9rsS3uGF73dVSqV67PHqw9U7jGEqPArKCYUoBBvT-S7EeKGAWlQuRvLEvxwgPd59o0_4ATGGGjxHYmVF4rKoIQA1rz7ydczdlk4RvMuOQQdxYQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s taken 17 years, but &lt;em&gt;Logan&lt;/em&gt; gives us the Wolverine we&amp;#39;ve always wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugh Jackman reprises the titular role for what he claims is the final time. Given the film&amp;#39;s box office success, I consider his retirement suspect, but I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film opens with Logan jarred from a drunken stupor in the back seat of a car. He stumbles out to discover a gang of young thieves attempting to strip the car. He pleas for them to stop and the thieves shoot him without a moment&amp;#39;s hesitation. He drops to the ground, apparently dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A beat passes and Logan struggles to his feet. The thieves turn, surprised. Once again, Logan appeals to reason. Again, the thieves shoot him. Logan&amp;#39;s temper snaps, he lets loose a slew of obscenities and winces in anger as he unsheathes his claws. The thieves&amp;#39; eyes go wide with terror as Logan snarls and charges forward, dismembering the punks in a bloody burst of violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This film earns its R-rating but doesn&amp;#39;t wallow in it. The violence feels gritty but not gratuitous. This is Wolverine uncensored, ripped from the comics and thrust into the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, almost. The time, we learn, is the near-future. The place is the southern US. Logan earns a low-profile living driving a limousine. He spends his meager earnings bribing hospital staff for the medication he administers to Charles Xavier, played once again by Patrick Stewart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forced into hiding, Logan and Xavier are all that remain of the X-Men. Xavier&amp;#39;s succumbing to dementia, rendering his mind a potential weapon of mass destruction. Logan&amp;#39;s mutant healing ability is fading and the adamantium lacing his bones is slowly poisoning him. Facing mortality and struggling to make ends meet, they are comic book heroes made human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, almost. The plot kicks in when Logan discovers he has a daughter who&amp;#39;s being hunted by a military-industrial conglomerate. As much as the film yearns to transcend the comic book genre, we get a cybernetic head bad guy, an evil Wolverine clone, and some magic healing juice that exists to facilitate the third act. These aren&amp;#39;t deal-breakers, but they weaken the film&amp;#39;s impact. With so much nonsense it&amp;#39;s hard to take the serious parts, well, seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I enjoyed &lt;em&gt;Logan&lt;/em&gt;, if for nothing more than Jackman and Stewart&amp;#39;s performances. They make their characters feel familiar yet fresh and appear to relish the unidealized roles. That said, as the film unwound, I kept hoping Ian McKellen would turn up as Magneto. His scenes with Stewart were among the highlights of &lt;em&gt;X-Men (2000)&lt;/em&gt;, and he deserves an encore. Hey, maybe reconsider that retirement, Hugh?&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>What We Do in the Shadows (2014)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/what-we-do-in-the-shadows-2014//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/what-we-do-in-the-shadows-2014/</id><updated>2017-03-27</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/what-we-do-in-the-shadows-2014/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/M5-wOBa6l7Gzdjt27b-Tg1lNeiAoVoA_hCWAS1bWUtawEHHWSiFw5IpmgGiuup8svPdJDJ3I1GlE1khxjkdy-O9AXDaA2Z1CdjBiGeLd1JY-Z-YLSQvAzaBsvJrkbJzQTKApmQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Funny, clever, and gruesome—albeit overlong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What We Do in the Shadows&lt;/em&gt; is a mockumentary following four vampires sharing a house in Wellington, New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film works best when it satirizes reality TV and focuses on the minutia of household life. The vampires bicker over household chores, dress for a night out, and prepare dinner for their would-be victims. In these moments, the film shines. Watching them struggle to dress up without mirrors had me roaring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a genre fan, I liked how the film satirized multiple cinematic vampire incarnations. Everything from &lt;em&gt;Nosferatu (1922)&lt;/em&gt; through &lt;em&gt;Twilight (2008)&lt;/em&gt;. The interplay between these incarnations offers some of the film&amp;#39;s best laughs. There&amp;#39;s also a group of werewolves, lead by Rhys Darby in a scene-stealing performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also enjoyed the film&amp;#39;s willingness to embrace the gore. One horrific yet hilarious scene involves a vampire trying and failing to devour a victim without spraying blood all over an antique couch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But about the length. Even at just 86 minutes, the film drags. The forced plot provides little emotional or comedic payoff and feels like dead weight. If reality TV can do without plot, why can&amp;#39;t the film that skewers it? Given how much the film gets right, it&amp;#39;s a petty quibble, but one that keeps &lt;em&gt;What We Do in the Shadows&lt;/em&gt; shy of perfection.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Get Out (2017)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/get-out-2017//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/get-out-2017/</id><updated>2017-03-20</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/get-out-2017/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/F-qUqcN3CF-VsNS0o6Gp3h7LmcxMHpnX_zdVNWZJxRrFZi8jwXya8ogdAYU9za_tEo6Skfb2xkBEefJOZ-hyjzjz5ujxGCK-GdEsctW6i5-2ttY5VeWg-0pgk0hYSu37mxlWFQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reviewing this one without spoilers will prove difficult. Bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Kaluuya stars as Chris, a young photographer. Chris&amp;#39;s girlfriend, Rose (Allison Williams), takes him home to meet her parents at their remote estate. Chris is apprehensive because Rose hasn&amp;#39;t told her family he&amp;#39;s black. She assures him everything will be fine. Everything is not fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgive my not revealing more but, as Roger Ebert often said, it&amp;#39;s not what the film is about, but how it is about it. With &lt;em&gt;Get Out&lt;/em&gt;, writer/director Jordan Peele offers a horror film that&amp;#39;s a meditation on racism in America, but not how you&amp;#39;d expect. Every time I thought I knew where he was going, Peele surprised me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This extends to the execution. Horror films sink or swim based on how they handle the tropes. The best filmmakers define, perfect, upend, or avoid them. Peele embraces them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow me to spoil a single scene to make my point. It&amp;#39;s the middle of the night. Chris has endured a rough day with Rose&amp;#39;s family. He&amp;#39;s tired, on edge, and can&amp;#39;t sleep. He sneaks out for a cigarette. Outside he sees—wait, I changed my mind. I can&amp;#39;t spoil the scene; it&amp;#39;s too good. But consider how Peele embraces the trope of drawing the protagonist into a spooky situation. Chris doesn&amp;#39;t investigate an odd noise, or similar clunky idiot plot behavior, his motives feel organic. As for what he sees, well, it&amp;#39;s scary, bizarre and humorous all at once. Peele leverages the setup&amp;#39;s inherent suspense and channels it into an original payoff. It&amp;#39;s genre Aikido.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, aside from Rose&amp;#39;s brother&amp;#39;s part feeling underwritten or severely edited, the film shines. It&amp;#39;s not until the third act, when the film&amp;#39;s cards are on the table, that it falters. We&amp;#39;ve grown so enamored with Peele&amp;#39;s ability to repurpose the genre&amp;#39;s staples, that it feels like a letdown when he indulges in a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this point, I&amp;#39;m torn. I love the third act&amp;#39;s gleefully gory, over the top nature, but it feels like a safety net. Like a comedian following a raw emotional truth with a punchline. The finale plays well, but Peele earned a darker, more honest ending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t wait to see what he does next.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>The Telegraph Trail (1933)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-telegraph-trail-1933//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-telegraph-trail-1933/</id><updated>2017-03-13</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-telegraph-trail-1933/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/XHBA647jX1GTDnCK4OMTtfI199xs8xFu-slUrz-8kzWpfIN-LE6PRSkQjRxGXkialj2T4XVGEB93cJhhHgZmE-CLuX7jLMOsrDDiBvj7VLzU6hjXqNxnzhSqfAiemLZU-OBekQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Young John Wayne gets his best supporting cast in years, but the resulting picture still stinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Telegraph Trail&lt;/em&gt; was the fourth production, following &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-big-stampede-1932/&quot;&gt;The Big Stampede (1932)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, under a six-picture contract Wayne signed with Warner Bros. It recycles footage from Ken Maynard&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;The Red Raiders (1927)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Warner Bros. acquired First National Pictures a few years prior, they inherited the rights to several popular silent westerns starring Maynard. These were A-list productions showcasing Maynard&amp;#39;s impressive stunt work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warner Bros. figured they could save money by reusing the Maynard action footage in new pictures. They just needed an actor who matched Maynard&amp;#39;s build. Enter Wayne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This picture sees Wayne play calvary scout John Trent. When his comrade and good pal Jonesy is killed to prevent completion of a telegraph line, Trent and his buddy Tippy (Frank McHugh) set out to apprehend the culprits. Along the way, they encounter hostile natives incited by corrupt trader Gus Lynch (Albert J. Smith). There&amp;#39;s also the obligatory love interest for Wayne, played by Alice Keller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayne&amp;#39;s prior pictures for Warner Bros. saddled him with subpar supporting casts, but this time he gets McHugh, a great character actor, and Smith, a great heavy. But the lackluster result proves Wayne still had lots to learn. It doesn&amp;#39;t help that he and Keller have minimal chemistry, or that the finale drags on far too long and reuses the same recycled footage multiple times. Later in his career, Wayne could have carried the film, but at this point, he struggles to hold his own.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Island of Death (1977)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/island-of-death-1977//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/island-of-death-1977/</id><updated>2017-03-06</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/island-of-death-1977/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/E6YsMkhKqoxT0l9pybIzA_fYdP2mtP6w-5FXNtqp3SXS_ix7whZV2w9mjlpIdbMu47h6M5VxHANXsgpN5wpi2pXwQ6J5Wvfe-_p6f1f2Lj9kcDugEihz3vRumrMi2n8UoV4ZNQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it cut to Robert Behling&amp;#39;s contorted face as he sodomized the baby goat, I thought, “Now, this is 4-star material.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, maybe not exactly, but I admired the gumption. Few films would dare hurtle so far over the top, and if they dared, they&amp;#39;d build up to it. &lt;em&gt;Island of Death&lt;/em&gt; gives us that scene in the first 15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to make an unintentional parody? Director Nico Mastorakis offers no indication he sought to satirize the exploitation horror genre, but his film is so ridiculous, modern horror audiences are bound to take it as comedy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot concerns a young couple played by Behling and Jane Lyle who arrive on the Greek island of Mykonos and embark on a thrill-kill spree. That&amp;#39;s it. It doesn&amp;#39;t pretend to have a deeper purpose or meaning. It&amp;#39;s all shock for shock&amp;#39;s sake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, it&amp;#39;s surprisingly well done. Mastorakis makes terrific use of the photogenic locales and enlivens the over-the-top violence with inventive camerawork. Consider the nocturnal chase through the city&amp;#39;s labyrinthine alleys. Mastorakis heightens the sense of panic by using a fish-eye lens and several low-angles shots from the victim&amp;#39;s point-of-view. In a lesser film, such choices would feel gimmicky, but they work here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The assured photography contrasts with the uneven performances. Though the supporting players are either wooden or over-the-top, Behling and Lyle play their parts so straight they verge on camp. As parody, the performances are inspired. Behling&amp;#39;s delivery alone is priceless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By his own account, Mastorakis made &lt;em&gt;Island of Death&lt;/em&gt; after seeing &lt;em&gt;The Texas Chainsaw Massacre (1974)&lt;/em&gt;. That film&amp;#39;s box-office success lead him to believe an even more extreme picture would make even more money. This naked ambition manifests in an everything-but-the-kitchen sink approach that pushes the film past any genuine scares or mean-spirited umbrage, and firmly into parody. Were I to enumerate the film&amp;#39;s assorted affronts to good taste it would appear brutal, yet I came away entertained. &lt;em&gt;Island of Death&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;#39;t for everyone, but exploitation fans will love it.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Cathy's Curse (1977)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/cathys-curse-1977//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/cathys-curse-1977/</id><updated>2017-02-27</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/cathys-curse-1977/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/gj0_EJhBtkOJopy7j4P8pks2Ru0H8s7Lk4MXDXgvD92y71laL1jQVCNsDpvv6jVo3PG-TsSOCq7XlXdcXRTCORkHCec25P_1O6aQu3SsO06NebwhrB1Lc81CJLiFpR2E3DvbZA=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did a 40-year-old, little-seen Canadian horror movie land a 2k restoration and limited theatrical run? It started with an internet movie review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian Collins publishes &lt;a href=&quot;http://horror-movie-a-day.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Horror Movie a Day&lt;/a&gt;. For the site&amp;#39;s first six years, Collins watched and reviewed a horror movie every single day. Two months into his run, buried in a fifty-film “Chilling Classics” DVD pack, Collins discovered &lt;em&gt;Cathy&amp;#39;s Curse&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://horror-movie-a-day.blogspot.com/2007/04/cathys-curse.html&quot;&gt;His review&lt;/a&gt; crowned it the “Best/Worst” film he&amp;#39;d seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;Cathy&amp;#39;s Curse&lt;/em&gt; was a cult film, Collins became the cult leader. As his site&amp;#39;s audience grew, Collins kept recommending the film and even posted &lt;a href=&quot;http://horror-movie-a-day.blogspot.com/2009/03/cathys-curse-commentary-now-live.html&quot;&gt;a commentary track&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this exposure convinced Severin Films to acquire the rights and sponsor a 2k restoration.  In recognition of Collins&amp;#39; efforts, they invited him to record a new audio commentary for the Blu-ray release. Said release also included a limited theatrical run, which is how I found myself watching &lt;em&gt;Cathy&amp;#39;s Curse&lt;/em&gt; on the big screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story follows a couple and their young daughter as they move back into the husband&amp;#39;s childhood home. A malevolent spirit possesses the daughter leading to lots of profanity, extreme acne, and several unexplained deaths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s as bad as &lt;a href=&quot;http://horror-movie-a-day.blogspot.com/2007/04/cathys-curse.html&quot;&gt;Collins&amp;#39; review&lt;/a&gt; claims, with inane dialog, incomprehensible editing, and whiplash performances. Aside from one scene, where a drunken groundskeeper finds himself covered in snakes and spiders, it&amp;#39;s a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, I found myself bored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cathy&amp;#39;s Curse&lt;/em&gt; achieved cult status as a so-bad-it&amp;#39;s-good film. One with flaws so obvious and fixable, it was as though the filmmakers were blissful idiots. But watching the restored digital projection, the film looked too good. Cleaning up the picture made the film feel less like an inept amateur effort and more like a lazy professional one. The added scenes smoothed over the worst editing mishaps but added to the film&amp;#39;s glacial pacing. Several scenes elicit laughs, but they&amp;#39;re few and farther between. It&amp;#39;s still bad, but so-bad-it&amp;#39;s-good? Not so much.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>John Wick: Chapter 2 (2017)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/john-wick-chapter-2-2017//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/john-wick-chapter-2-2017/</id><updated>2017-02-20</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/john-wick-chapter-2-2017/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/LX9kcyaFYAPZBXR3EWNkTAUDpU-MO1jwWf3tv1lQdjasq5k-bPDrH6ROqfeFG0vs_RyBqNNc5LuALmwX3i8LVpNcQOOggc8BESvfs_3MyGjJnLcl-zqZlfgZPv7BXPCLfk0Rkg=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I spent a good portion of &lt;em&gt;John Wick: Chapter 2&lt;/em&gt; thinking Keanu Reeves wasn’t right for the titular part. Then I realized he makes the film work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picking up where &lt;em&gt;John Wick (2014)&lt;/em&gt; ended, we follow John Wick as he rebuilds his house, sends his car for repairs, and tries to resume a normal life. I liked how these scenes acknowledge the mess action pictures leave in their wake. But soon enough, a smarmy mafioso appears, calling in a marker and forcing Wick back into life as an assassin. We meet a delightful array of supporting characters and thrill as Wick offs dozens of bad guys using knives, guns, cars, pens—you name it—before an obligatory double-cross makes him the target of every assassin in New York City. The film doesn’t so much end as set up another installment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may read like a direct-to-video production, but &lt;em&gt;John Wick: Chapter 2&lt;/em&gt; transcends the action genre, thanks to Reeves. It starts with the cognitive dissonance he creates. How he marches through the film with a shadow limp. The closeups that betray his fifty-two years. The weariness behind his eyes that clashes with his surfer-dude delivery. How nothing in the film surprises him. I have a theory that ties it all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider, if you will, that the John Wick universe, with its surreal characters, superhuman assassins, and over-the-top violence, isn’t attempting to pass as real. And consider further that the John Wick character isn’t reluctant to kill out of a moral quandary, but because he knows he can’t lose. In this respect, Reeves’ weary delivery fits perfectly. How many times has he played this story out? His final line, saying “I’ll kill them all,” isn’t a warning or a threat, but a plea. He’s already killed them all, countless times. He’s a self-aware action hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, it’s a stretch, and the third installment will likely prove me wrong, but I’m looking forward to it, regardless.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Maléfique (2002)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/malefique-2002//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/malefique-2002/</id><updated>2017-02-13</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/malefique-2002/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Gx06bofb27ZJC9m3SnJeq2c5Tjq18GTibJ62vv2xS-WdKgXvV0vx82TOGyAgOdrdj4CMNEdZ_u6EqLWjfB5v93R4UVdPXSXzzbW2DWBvukA5NbVvpBtdFpusoEceSq1EhLMQ_g=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maléfique&lt;/em&gt; falls short of its potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film opens with a man saying goodbye to his wife and young son. The man’s name is Carrère. He is a white-collar criminal and today marks his first day in prison. We meet his cellmates: Lassalle, an older librarian who says little, Marcus, a brash young man whose large breast implants clash with his brawny physique, and Pâquerette, a man-child with a penchant for eating things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After establishing these characters and their interpersonal dynamics, the plot kicks into gear. The men discover an old diary that doubles as a spell book. Eager to escape, the men try some incantations but discover magic carries a high cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I relished this premise. Taking four desperate (but not fierce) men and dangling a supernatural means of escape overflows with potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carrère and Lassalle are well-cast. As Carrère, Gérald Laroche provides a grounded audience surrogate whose gradual transformation into a bitter convict carries the film. As Lassalle, Philippe Laudenbach adds gravitas, communicating volumes with his weary looks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was fine with Clovis Cornillac as Marcus, but his character felt underwritten—his transgenderedness regulated to a plot device. As Pâquerette, Dimitri Rataud’s performance felt artificial. I kept hoping the film would reveal Pâquerette as a calculating mastermind masquerading as an imbecile, but no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, the story devolves into a predictable version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Monkey&#39;s_Paw&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Monkey’s Paw&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. What begins with echoes of Lovecraft ends like an episode of &lt;em&gt;Tales from the Crypt&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a film that took these characters—one imprisoned in his body, one in his mind, one in his wealth—and explored their prisons and the lengths they would go for freedom. &lt;em&gt;Maléfique&lt;/em&gt; is not that movie. It’s not a bad film, just a disappointing one.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>