<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'><title>Frank's Movie Log</title><subtitle>Quality reviews of films of questionable quality.</subtitle><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/feed.xml' rel='self' /><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com' /><updated>2017-05-22T22:53:04-04:00</updated><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com</id><author><name>Frank Showalter</name></author><entry><title>Play Motel (1979)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/play-motel-1979//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/play-motel-1979/</id><updated>2017-05-22</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/play-motel-1979/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/2ZyuabwsHwnSKAPR5yy1dOkft_OvODMZfgoDsMXDjALPMdzDJQsvw3S-slLMIMsZvcVYzSmMXhIkRH7QX-fAAa1xPohbDESRzKMNFrBlqGAjUX5JywHuzR0ef_JSJU_eh8ahEw=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went in expecting a sleazy giallo and I got a sleazy giallo with a catchy folk-rock theme song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, the film&amp;#39;s IMDb page has no trivia. No proof the American distributor already owned the song, changed the film&amp;#39;s title, and spliced it into the soundtrack. None at all. So clearly, director Mario Gariazzo commissioned the theme, believing it a perfect tonal fit. If that&amp;#39;s true, it might merit an extra star.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film&amp;#39;s plot concerns a blackmail scam photographing wealthy marks in compromising positions in the titular establishment. Said positions feature lots of nudity and kinky behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, a black-gloved killer starts picking off victims peripheral to the scam. After the killer stashes a body in a parked car&amp;#39;s trunk, the cars owners, a young couple, get involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the local police&amp;#39;s urging, the couple turn amateur sleuths, a questionable decision that sees the wife pose node for a sleazy photographer while her husband waits in the car. When she&amp;#39;s inevitably captured and beaten, he&amp;#39;s laughably unconcerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all plays out as an over-the-top cross between Scooby-Doo and softcore porn. The end reveal is laugh-out-loud implausible, and the blackmail scenes are as explicit as the censors would allow. It&amp;#39;s pure exploitation in all it&amp;#39;s ridiculous glory and I&amp;#39;ll admit, it kept me entertained. If sleazy giallos are your thing, &lt;em&gt;Play Motel&lt;/em&gt; won&amp;#39;t disappoint.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Heat (1995)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/heat-1995//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/heat-1995/</id><updated>2017-05-15</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/heat-1995/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/7V1hPikvQPV9SeB6Rt9eQSKJerda-EY8MHOl7JTP8D8r7_wtWbmjjFgaTIgAIMkVu1IASE5eBKcGGCTA6--qp6xFIuII6Yv0S2-lexbvdsNhDWCsB3B7DagUtGgOYgmkK8yB4g=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tilt forward in my seat. My heels rise. The balls of my feet press into the floor. My hands clench tight and I realize I&amp;#39;m holding my breath. &lt;em&gt;Heat&lt;/em&gt; on the big screen is an experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve seen the film several times, yet the centerpiece shootout scene in the streets of downtown Los Angeles always elicits a visceral reaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boiled down, it&amp;#39;s a cops and robbers story. Robert De Niro leads a crew of professional thieves taking down a series of Los Angeles scores. Al Pacino leads the cops in pursuit. They&amp;#39;re archetypes in the Howard Hawks tradition—professions personified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, &lt;em&gt;Heat&lt;/em&gt; feels like a Hawks picture, right down to the underwritten female characters. But while Hawks romanticized the professional, &lt;em&gt;Heat&lt;/em&gt; shows us the cost of such a lifestyle. De Niro plans the heists with military precision, yet lives alone in a palatial seaside estate that could pass for vacant. Pacino hunts De Niro&amp;#39;s crew with obsessive fervor, even as his third marriage crumbles around him. Both performances feel larger than life yet intensely human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But back to the shootout. It makes the movie. The scene carries an immense gravitas because everything about it feels authentic. From the way the characters fire short bursts and reload, to their tactical movements, it all resonates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s not to say writer/director Michael Mann values authenticity over drama. His kinetic editing includes plenty of long and wide shots to establish movement and geography, immersing us in the scene. We don&amp;#39;t witness the gunfight we &lt;em&gt;experience&lt;/em&gt; it.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: A+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Free Fire (2016)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/free-fire-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/free-fire-2016/</id><updated>2017-05-08</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/free-fire-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/gCIe14X_ycptKUtFPj1mRS479ZGy7emqLvc1_gve1Ik48XW0eucK0GhxLoc0LRUPFroQJe07nOmcBn3iVvKGsadZgwnf6UERV_sFFH10vKNcPEQUH8ZYPRgXF8NPGgkbN5TFIw=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;You know that scene in crime movies, where a back-alley deal turns sour, resulting in a shootout? &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; stretches that into an entire movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set in 1978 Boston, the plot sees Cillian Murphy and Michael Smiley play IRA gang leaders buying guns from gang leaders played by Sharlto Copley and Armie Hammer. Brie Larson plays the intermediary. As the deal goes down, a grunt in one gang squabbles with a grunt the other gang, escalating into a full-fledged melee. Amid the flying bullets, the script weaves in some double-crosses. But honestly? The details escape me. &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; isn’t concerned with plot, but style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s got style to spare. The clothes, the hair, the set decoration—this movie does the impossible: it makes 1978 look cool. Do they give Academy Awards for that? They should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as much as I enjoyed the film’s look, the execution frustrated me. When the firefight breaks out, director Ben Wheatley offers no sense of geography. Folks shoot and scramble for cover but we have no sense of their placement in relation to one another. A few wide shots would have sufficed. Disorient characters, not the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it almost doesn’t matter. The dialog held my ear, and despite little plot or characterization, the cast—particularly Hammer—grabbed my attention through sheer charisma. &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; isn’t a good movie, but it’s as good an okay movie as you’ll find.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Raw (2016)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/raw-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/raw-2016/</id><updated>2017-05-01</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/raw-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/VmNSE_2S2EWCGmmdKeH3j1kg-A9nEgN7LArm6DWjFVAX8CKLppkKpwu4gnv9eMbDf2rFzVMpo3z8nV16iwdU1Rbw6tBc5EEzHMzTEZb1qJ98qyg69WfmbxgzI0d1uClQ1idMHg=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was fine with the cannibalism, but everything else irked me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Raw&lt;/em&gt; stars Garance Marillier as Justine, a young woman entering veterinarian college. On her first night, a hazing ritual sees masked men invade the dorms and force the freshmen to march and crawl—half dressed—across the campus. I couldn’t believe how the students reacted. No one asserted themselves or fought back. Maybe it’s a cultural thing (it’s a French film) but the herd imagery felt too pointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot kicks in when another hazing ritual forces Justine—a lifelong vegetarian—to try meat. This first taste unlocks an insatiable craving for human flesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface, &lt;em&gt;Raw&lt;/em&gt; is about Justine discovering and battling her cannibalistic urges. But writer/director Julia Ducournau positions cannibalism as a metaphor for escaping overbearing parents, discovering one’s sexuality, defending animal rights, and struggling to escape an older sibling’s shadow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juggling so many metaphors leaves little time for subtlety. It’s frustrating. Several scenes made me uncomfortable but said discomfort felt manipulative and obnoxious. Other scenes fall apart upon reflection. Some scenes do both. The night following her first taste of meat, Justine awakens covered in huge itchy welts with swaths of her skin peeling off in dry sheets. She yawns and goes back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, &lt;em&gt;Raw&lt;/em&gt; has its strengths. The cinematography grabbed my attention from the opening shot, and the performances convince to the degree the script allows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I just couldn’t buy it. For a film desperate to frame its genre elements as a serious conceit, too many details strained credibility. Justine as a cannibal? Sure. But a campus full of kids not glued to their smartphones? Preposterous.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Deadpool (2016)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/deadpool-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/deadpool-2016/</id><updated>2017-04-24</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/deadpool-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/8A6X_dIRLq2H0qzof8S796jLPeoVhO6K-im-Hm3b6s7rSbYEJIcf-6jg10i8YUu9A2nAxMRJehtYOVGY0jwnyjGlhQOBmrbyZ7M5SRpaXMtJRkPKz76lLZ6QeOkgKUdAtFaEnw=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beneath the crude jokes and over-the-top violence lurks a serious film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, not exactly, but &lt;em&gt;Deadpool&lt;/em&gt; works because it takes its source material seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan Reynolds stars as Wade Wilson a former special forces operative turned mercenary with a heart of gold. Just as he meets the girl of his dreams and finds the happiness that&amp;#39;s eluded him all his life, Wade learns he&amp;#39;s developed terminal cancer. A mysterious organization reaches out with the promise of a cure. Wade accepts, but the cure carries at a steep price. Presumed dead, Wade embarks on a mission of vengeance, complete with running color commentary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deadpool&lt;/em&gt; plays as a self-aware comic book film. The first time I watched it, I laughed so hard I missed most of the jokes. Besides the non-stop non-sequiturs, we get jokes about the plot, jokes about the other &lt;em&gt;X-Men&lt;/em&gt; films, and jokes about the limited budget. They&amp;#39;re not belittling the genre, just mining it for laughs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And these laughs come wrapped in a solid origin story. The film invests time in Wade and his relationships, making him more than a clown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the credit goes to Reynolds. His deadpan comedy proves the perfect match for the character&amp;#39;s gallows humor. He doesn&amp;#39;t just carry the film, he propels it along with his considerable charisma. This despite having essentially a voice-over role for most of his scenes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s said one can mark a genre&amp;#39;s end when it devolves into comedy, as &lt;em&gt;Abbott and Costello Meet Frankenstein (1948)&lt;/em&gt; ended the Universal Monster era. But that needn&amp;#39;t be the case. Rather than transplant genre characters into a comedic film, &lt;em&gt;Deadpool&lt;/em&gt; takes a genre film and adds liberal doses of comedy. It&amp;#39;s a subtle but important distinction. &lt;em&gt;Deadpool&lt;/em&gt; may be hilarious, but it&amp;#39;s a comic book movie first, and a comedy second.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Shock (1946)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/shock-1946//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/shock-1946/</id><updated>2017-04-17</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/shock-1946/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/6goXr9YlP7Fo6zg1X2R9Eabmn-iXHhtD_SzG8_NS529ejrdyrMOsr-84JqJD27uXP0AdxK7UX193n22YMpKuEEs6byE7ZARY8QQYfgGC04y3opLJEHFuTEP60qYCo1d4mJhJMQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;You won&amp;#39;t believe me when I tell you not to watch &lt;em&gt;Shock&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially if you&amp;#39;re a Vincent Price fan. The plot alone will convince you it&amp;#39;s worth watching. Price plays a psychiatrist who murders his wife. Unbeknownst to him, Anabel Shaw&amp;#39;s character witnesses the murder from her hotel room. The sight renders her catatonic and she falls under the care of—you guessed it—Price&amp;#39;s character. Better still: Shaw&amp;#39;s character spies the murder only after waking from an anxiety-laden nightmare, calling into question her reliability as a narrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could play as a cross between &lt;em&gt;Rebecca (1940)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Suspicion (1941)&lt;/em&gt;. Instead, it plays like &lt;em&gt;Double Indemnity (1944)&lt;/em&gt;. There&amp;#39;s no doubt Price&amp;#39;s character is guilty. He&amp;#39;s egged on by femme fatale Lynn Bari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can hear you saying to yourself, “That sounds interesting.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m here to tell you, it isn&amp;#39;t. Price doesn&amp;#39;t register as charming or sinister. He has zero chemistry with Bari, who herself fails to register as seductive or cunning. This renders the entire film rather boring, which as I&amp;#39;ve written before, is a film&amp;#39;s most unforgivable sin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;#39;s face it: if you&amp;#39;re a Vincent Price fan, you won&amp;#39;t believe me. Price played this sort of role so well in so many later pictures, you can&amp;#39;t fathom him falling flat. To those fans, I offer this condolence: if you make it through the film, you&amp;#39;ll see the ending, which I found so unintentionally funny I laughed aloud. So that&amp;#39;s something.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Breakfast at Tiffany's (1961)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/breakfast-at-tiffanys-1961//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/breakfast-at-tiffanys-1961/</id><updated>2017-04-10</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/breakfast-at-tiffanys-1961/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/5tMVCQoWpYy9bfXzSIoJ5yCNDbDSQ0Bt_i22ZWy_HDHZxAn7xpetQeXKUhgVEsTy0wrSf0Qmy7IhXz8fHirBCDye9Jv3Bg4csWLoxU_DLXcgZ8q0P69nIyr3hVNnZTkAZeE-Uw=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s Audrey Hepburn&amp;#39;s movie, but George Peppard deserves some credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His performance channels a young William Holden or Steve McQueen. Sure, seeing colonel John &amp;quot;Hannibal&amp;quot; Smith play a romantic lead will shock those of a certain age, but the jolt is short-lived. Peppard pulls off the role with aplomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts with his clothes. Okay—not really, but I love his wardrobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peppard plays Paul, a writer posing as a gigolo or vice versa. As the film opens, he&amp;#39;s moving into a converted New York brownstone apartment. There he meets Holly Golightly, a quirky socialite played by Hepburn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He falls for her. She for him. Complications ensue. What makes &lt;em&gt;Breakfast at Tiffany&amp;#39;s&lt;/em&gt; special is not the plot, but the characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul and Holly are both damaged people, skirting responsibility and commitment with a fear bordering on phobic. When Paul meets Holly he&amp;#39;s drawn by her fragile nature. The diminutive Hepburn looks the part. Paul longs to swoop in and save Holly. Unlike her other suitors, Paul&amp;#39;s in no position to save anyone, he&amp;#39;s just as wounded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patricia Neal plays the rich, married woman who pays Paul&amp;#39;s rent and keeps him in nice clothes. She makes an impression by underplaying her role. As does Buddy Ebsen as a lovesick figure from Holly&amp;#39;s shadowy past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s this willingness to embrace flawed characters—and not flawed in cute ways, but morally suspect ones—that makes &lt;em&gt;Breakfast at Tiffany&amp;#39;s&lt;/em&gt; stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, we get plenty of soft focus close-ups, Mickey Rooney as a racist caricature meant as comic relief, and a finale set in a rainy, yet well-lit alley, but &lt;em&gt;Breakfast at Tiffany&amp;#39;s&lt;/em&gt; transcends the tropes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest complaint lies with the ending. Holly isn&amp;#39;t a real person, she&amp;#39;s a ghost, drifting in and out of people&amp;#39;s lives, leaving an indelible impression. That Paul could end up with her doesn&amp;#39;t ring true. She&amp;#39;s not the girl you marry, she&amp;#39;s the girl you wonder about years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it&amp;#39;s a great film and Hepburn deserves the kudos showered upon her performance. But it works because Peppard wins us over too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Logan (2017)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/logan-2017//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/logan-2017/</id><updated>2017-04-03</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/logan-2017/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/i8MoyM90ZwROOXuzUTOhkM9j9rsS3uGF73dVSqV67PHqw9U7jGEqPArKCYUoBBvT-S7EeKGAWlQuRvLEvxwgPd59o0_4ATGGGjxHYmVF4rKoIQA1rz7ydczdlk4RvMuOQQdxYQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s taken 17 years, but &lt;em&gt;Logan&lt;/em&gt; gives us the Wolverine we&amp;#39;ve always wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugh Jackman reprises the titular role for what he claims is the final time. Given the film&amp;#39;s box office success, I consider his retirement suspect, but I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film opens with Logan jarred from a drunken stupor in the back seat of a car. He stumbles out to discover a gang of young thieves attempting to strip the car. He pleas for them to stop and the thieves shoot him without a moment&amp;#39;s hesitation. He drops to the ground, apparently dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A beat passes and Logan struggles to his feet. The thieves turn, surprised. Once again, Logan appeals to reason. Again, the thieves shoot him. Logan&amp;#39;s temper snaps, he lets loose a slew of obscenities and winces in anger as he unsheathes his claws. The thieves&amp;#39; eyes go wide with terror as Logan snarls and charges forward, dismembering the punks in a bloody burst of violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This film earns its R-rating but doesn&amp;#39;t wallow in it. The violence feels gritty but not gratuitous. This is Wolverine uncensored, ripped from the comics and thrust into the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, almost. The time, we learn, is the near-future. The place is the southern US. Logan earns a low-profile living driving a limousine. He spends his meager earnings bribing hospital staff for the medication he administers to Charles Xavier, played once again by Patrick Stewart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forced into hiding, Logan and Xavier are all that remain of the X-Men. Xavier&amp;#39;s succumbing to dementia, rendering his mind a potential weapon of mass destruction. Logan&amp;#39;s mutant healing ability is fading and the adamantium lacing his bones is slowly poisoning him. Facing mortality and struggling to make ends meet, they are comic book heroes made human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, almost. The plot kicks in when Logan discovers he has a daughter who&amp;#39;s being hunted by a military-industrial conglomerate. As much as the film yearns to transcend the comic book genre, we get a cybernetic head bad guy, an evil Wolverine clone, and some magic healing juice that exists to facilitate the third act. These aren&amp;#39;t deal-breakers, but they weaken the film&amp;#39;s impact. With so much nonsense it&amp;#39;s hard to take the serious parts, well, seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I enjoyed &lt;em&gt;Logan&lt;/em&gt;, if for nothing more than Jackman and Stewart&amp;#39;s performances. They make their characters feel familiar yet fresh and appear to relish the unidealized roles. That said, as the film unwound, I kept hoping Ian McKellen would turn up as Magneto. His scenes with Stewart were among the highlights of &lt;em&gt;X-Men (2000)&lt;/em&gt;, and he deserves an encore. Hey, maybe reconsider that retirement, Hugh?&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>What We Do in the Shadows (2014)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/what-we-do-in-the-shadows-2014//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/what-we-do-in-the-shadows-2014/</id><updated>2017-03-27</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/what-we-do-in-the-shadows-2014/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/M5-wOBa6l7Gzdjt27b-Tg1lNeiAoVoA_hCWAS1bWUtawEHHWSiFw5IpmgGiuup8svPdJDJ3I1GlE1khxjkdy-O9AXDaA2Z1CdjBiGeLd1JY-Z-YLSQvAzaBsvJrkbJzQTKApmQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Funny, clever, and gruesome—albeit overlong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What We Do in the Shadows&lt;/em&gt; is a mockumentary following four vampires sharing a house in Wellington, New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film works best when it satirizes reality TV and focuses on the minutia of household life. The vampires bicker over household chores, dress for a night out, and prepare dinner for their would-be victims. In these moments, the film shines. Watching them struggle to dress up without mirrors had me roaring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a genre fan, I liked how the film satirized multiple cinematic vampire incarnations. Everything from &lt;em&gt;Nosferatu (1922)&lt;/em&gt; through &lt;em&gt;Twilight (2008)&lt;/em&gt;. The interplay between these incarnations offers some of the film&amp;#39;s best laughs. There&amp;#39;s also a group of werewolves, lead by Rhys Darby in a scene-stealing performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also enjoyed the film&amp;#39;s willingness to embrace the gore. One horrific yet hilarious scene involves a vampire trying and failing to devour a victim without spraying blood all over an antique couch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But about the length. Even at just 86 minutes, the film drags. The forced plot provides little emotional or comedic payoff and feels like dead weight. If reality TV can do without plot, why can&amp;#39;t the film that skewers it? Given how much the film gets right, it&amp;#39;s a petty quibble, but one that keeps &lt;em&gt;What We Do in the Shadows&lt;/em&gt; shy of perfection.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Get Out (2017)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/get-out-2017//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/get-out-2017/</id><updated>2017-03-20</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/get-out-2017/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/F-qUqcN3CF-VsNS0o6Gp3h7LmcxMHpnX_zdVNWZJxRrFZi8jwXya8ogdAYU9za_tEo6Skfb2xkBEefJOZ-hyjzjz5ujxGCK-GdEsctW6i5-2ttY5VeWg-0pgk0hYSu37mxlWFQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reviewing this one without spoilers will prove difficult. Bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Kaluuya stars as Chris, a young photographer. Chris&amp;#39;s girlfriend, Rose (Allison Williams), takes him home to meet her parents at their remote estate. Chris is apprehensive because Rose hasn&amp;#39;t told her family he&amp;#39;s black. She assures him everything will be fine. Everything is not fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgive my not revealing more but, as Roger Ebert often said, it&amp;#39;s not what the film is about, but how it is about it. With &lt;em&gt;Get Out&lt;/em&gt;, writer/director Jordan Peele offers a horror film that&amp;#39;s a meditation on racism in America, but not how you&amp;#39;d expect. Every time I thought I knew where he was going, Peele surprised me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This extends to the execution. Horror films sink or swim based on how they handle the tropes. The best filmmakers define, perfect, upend, or avoid them. Peele embraces them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow me to spoil a single scene to make my point. It&amp;#39;s the middle of the night. Chris has endured a rough day with Rose&amp;#39;s family. He&amp;#39;s tired, on edge, and can&amp;#39;t sleep. He sneaks out for a cigarette. Outside he sees—wait, I changed my mind. I can&amp;#39;t spoil the scene; it&amp;#39;s too good. But consider how Peele embraces the trope of drawing the protagonist into a spooky situation. Chris doesn&amp;#39;t investigate an odd noise, or similar clunky idiot plot behavior, his motives feel organic. As for what he sees, well, it&amp;#39;s scary, bizarre and humorous all at once. Peele leverages the setup&amp;#39;s inherent suspense and channels it into an original payoff. It&amp;#39;s genre Aikido.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, aside from Rose&amp;#39;s brother&amp;#39;s part feeling underwritten or severely edited, the film shines. It&amp;#39;s not until the third act, when the film&amp;#39;s cards are on the table, that it falters. We&amp;#39;ve grown so enamored with Peele&amp;#39;s ability to repurpose the genre&amp;#39;s staples, that it feels like a letdown when he indulges in a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this point, I&amp;#39;m torn. I love the third act&amp;#39;s gleefully gory, over the top nature, but it feels like a safety net. Like a comedian following a raw emotional truth with a punchline. The finale plays well, but Peele earned a darker, more honest ending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t wait to see what he does next.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>