<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'><title>Frank's Movie Log</title><subtitle>Quality reviews of films of questionable quality.</subtitle><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/feed.xml' rel='self' /><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com' /><updated>2017-06-11T14:35:23-04:00</updated><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com</id><author><name>Frank Showalter</name></author><entry><title>The Ghoul (1933)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-ghoul-1933//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-ghoul-1933/</id><updated>2017-06-12</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-ghoul-1933/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/GfPDGVCpp5mYVL-WLq7e-qfMaTu91UxP_P-hRwLuSZmUSVmm84Xz-scVA37pgP27Bzv5JqMwleVYv0wrDZqC3E75U5MARmam4iD0rJZMIrG7hMVAgtHH7T4uTN5Nl0BjKI2rXA=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even the most ardent Boris Karloff fan can skip &lt;em&gt;The Ghoul&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a bait and switch. The opening sees Karloff playing an ailing, disfigured Egyptologist. Bedridden in a gloomy mansion, he details the conditions for his entombment following his imminent death. It&amp;#39;s a good setup, and the funeral scene that follows has us pumped for some undead action. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But these scenes appear tacked on to capitalize on Karloff&amp;#39;s prior box office successes: &lt;em&gt;The Mummy (1932)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Old Dark House (1932)&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the title, &lt;em&gt;The Ghoul&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;#39;t a horror film. With Karloff off-screen, the film devolves into a tedious mystery. A slew of characters turn up searching for a rare jewel stolen from Karloff&amp;#39;s tomb. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the supporting cast&amp;#39;s flat delivery and stiff dialog, following the convoluted plot proves an ordeal. The overbearing score doesn&amp;#39;t help. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, the cobwebbed sets and shadowy photography create a rich gothic atmosphere, but the film fails to exploit it. When Karloff finally returns for the film&amp;#39;s final third as the titular ghoul, he&amp;#39;s far from terrifying. Creeping around like a dim-witted zombie, he seems as bored as we are.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Casablanca (1942)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/casablanca-1942//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/casablanca-1942/</id><updated>2017-06-05</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/casablanca-1942/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/d1dVVcIG3eIy7M0F4k64jbkOV_jrOcp6_U3tY-zVC8547wbCjOkt3Zo350K55V0BL-SMfXjHYCyYCzXab13bxQbXyvqhqzaASve5KksyEPNH5pfPdJ2bOfWAqODqxiyQ7dGcxA=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the time I watched &lt;em&gt;Casablanca&lt;/em&gt;, I already knew every line of dialog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my senior year of high school, I worked at Suncoast Video. It wasn&amp;#39;t a rental store, but one that sold VHS and Laserdisc movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On monitors mounted throughout the store we&amp;#39;d show whatever clamshelled, family-friendly title corporate was pushing—think &lt;em&gt;Free Willy (1993)&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the holiday season, corporate would ship washing-machine-sized boxes of product for us to stock. Nothing stayed in the back room so we&amp;#39;d be there—well past midnight—stacking copies of &lt;em&gt;The Bodyguard (1992)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Sister Act (1992)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we worked, we&amp;#39;d put on a movie. The monitors would be off, but we&amp;#39;d listen. &lt;em&gt;Casablanca&lt;/em&gt; proved an employee favorite on those long nights. Though I&amp;#39;d never seen it, I loved the crackling dialog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would take a miracle to get you out of Casablanca and the Germans have outlawed miracles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story takes place during World War II. Casablanca, an unoccupied French colony, has become a purgatory for European refugees looking to escape to America. We meet Rick, an American expatriate played by Humphrey Bogart. He runs the most popular cafe in town. As Louis, the venal Prefect of Police played by Claude Rains says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everybody comes to Rick&amp;#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Rick&amp;#39;s they&amp;#39;re entertained by Sam, a piano playing singer played by Dooley Wilson. Aside from Sam and the cafe, Rick maintains a cool detachment from everything and everyone. That changes once long-lost flame Ilsa (played by Ingrid Bergman) walks in on the arm of Victor Lazlo, a resistance leader wanted by the Germans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing Ilsa shakes Rick from his isolationist stance, and soon he&amp;#39;s abetting the local resistance. The Germans retaliate by insisting Louis shut down the cafe. Amid the chaos of the police chasing everyone out, Rick demands an explanation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LOUIS&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;#39;m shocked, SHOCKED, to find gambling going on here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(A croupier approaches with a large wad of cash)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CROUPIER&lt;br&gt;
Your winnings sir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LOUIS&lt;br&gt;
Oh, thank you, very much!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s not just funny, it&amp;#39;s Billy Wilder funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the film pivots with ease. Grounded in relatable emotions, the melodrama packs a punch. Consider how Rick spits venom at Ilsa:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I guess neither one of our stories is very funny. Tell me, who was it you left me for? Was it Lazlo, or were there others in between or… aren&amp;#39;t you the kind that tells?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No weepy speeches, just relatable emotion setup by an earlier scene between a drunken Rick and Sam:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAM&lt;br&gt;
Let&amp;#39;s get outta here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RICK&lt;br&gt;
No Sam, I&amp;#39;m waiting for a lady.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SAM&lt;br&gt;
Please boss, let&amp;#39;s go. Ain&amp;#39;t nothing but trouble for you here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RICK (staring at the liquor in front of him)&lt;br&gt;
She&amp;#39;s coming back. I know she&amp;#39;s coming back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SAM&lt;br&gt;
We&amp;#39;ll take the car. We&amp;#39;ll drive all night. We&amp;#39;ll get drunk. We&amp;#39;ll go fishing and stay away until she&amp;#39;s gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RICK (not looking at Sam)&lt;br&gt;
Shut up and go home, will ya?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SAM&lt;br&gt;
No sir, I&amp;#39;m staying right here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great lines abound but some of the film&amp;#39;s best moments are visual. I didn&amp;#39;t discover them until years later, when I finally sat down and watched the film. Nice touches like when the waiter checks his pockets after the pickpocket bumps him. Or the beat-perfect editing between Rick and Louis during the finale. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And let&amp;#39;s talk about that ending. It&amp;#39;s not a happy one. Rick sends the love of his life away and goes off to a likely death. Noble? Absolutely. But in an era where studios were allergic to unhappy endings, it&amp;#39;s amazing this one went over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, it&amp;#39;s impressive how the script doesn&amp;#39;t have Ilsa waffle, even when she believes Rick has betrayed Victor. This casts her in an unflattering light, but gives the ending its resonance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a movie buff before &lt;em&gt;Casablanca&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;s what got me the video store job. But &lt;em&gt;Casablanca&lt;/em&gt; made me a Bogart fan, which led me to &lt;em&gt;The Big Sleep (1946)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Maltese Falcon (1941)&lt;/em&gt;, which led me to &lt;em&gt;The Thin Man (1934)&lt;/em&gt;, along with the films of John Huston and Howard Hawks, which led me to the films of William Powell and John Wayne, which led me to &lt;em&gt;Rio Bravo (1959)&lt;/em&gt;, and well… you get the idea. &lt;em&gt;Casablanca&lt;/em&gt; changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;#39;m not alone. Roger Ebert considered &lt;em&gt;Casablanca&lt;/em&gt; his favorite movie. What higher recommendation can I offer?&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: A+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice (2016)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/batman-v-superman-dawn-of-justice-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/batman-v-superman-dawn-of-justice-2016/</id><updated>2017-05-29</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/batman-v-superman-dawn-of-justice-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/uXESZr9B66hNHOWjAqCKIkvbr9z5_Y75PXpankNncjEVfwVw1TzZSsDJTBgNUShg0r6MCthhnFVf0-VuKmdyrRQchUd_FEIXV3AYP7_AsEzL3ucDVAhKcX3howwklGPxNe8DhA=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buried under the bad, there&amp;#39;s just enough good to make &lt;em&gt;Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice&lt;/em&gt; a frustrating experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film opens during the final moments of &lt;em&gt;Man of Steel (2013)&lt;/em&gt;. We follow Ben Affleck as Bruce Wayne rushing through the chaotic streets of Metropolis. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overhead, Superman battles Zod—a Kryptonian bent on wiping out humanity. The two aliens crash through buildings and unleash arcs of laser-like heat vision. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Bruce approaches Wayne Enterprises&amp;#39; Metropolis office, Superman and Zod rip through the building like a bullet. The skyscraper topples, sending out a massive cloud of debris. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People scream. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emergency responders freeze. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruce Wayne runs toward the destruction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the dust clears, Bruce snatches little girl from the path of some falling debris. He crouches down and looks in her wide eyes. “It&amp;#39;s going to be okay,” he says. “We&amp;#39;re going to find your mom. Where is she? Where&amp;#39;s your mom?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girl points—her arm shaking—toward the smoldering rubble of the Wayne tower. Bruce pulls the girl close and glares up—eyes full of rage—at Superman and Zod still zooming through the air. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that shot, any apprehension I had about Affleck evaporated. He&amp;#39;s not wearing the suit, but he&amp;#39;s Batman. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this sequence&amp;#39;s accomplishments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It summarizes and even provides the payoff for the excessive destruction sequences of the prior film. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sells Affleck in the role of Batman. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It establishes motivation for the conflict between the titular characters. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this with near-constant action and no exposition. It&amp;#39;s an amazing sequence. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it also commits the film&amp;#39;s most egregious sin: it raises our expectations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here, the film devolves into a mess of dead-end plot threads and superfluous characters. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some had potential. Holly Hunter plays a US Senator chairing a hearing discussing Superman&amp;#39;s unchecked role in global affairs. We&amp;#39;re given an iconic image of Superman hovering outside the Capitol building, before symbolically landing and walking inside. What followed should have been crackling, character-driven drama. Instead, the building blows up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This explosion comes courtesy of Lex Luthor, played by Jessie Eisenberg as an eccentric young industrialist. He blows up the Capitol because—well, mostly because the script feels stitched together. Luthor manipulates Superman and Batman into fighting one another because—well, see above. Luthor also creates a giant monster because… well, you get the idea. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other characters and scenes exist solely to set up the next films in the franchise. We meet Wonder Woman. She&amp;#39;s superfluous to the story, but proves a compelling character, largely because she&amp;#39;s devoid of angst. We also get awkward teases for Aquaman, the Flash, and Cyborg. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, there&amp;#39;s so much going on, I can&amp;#39;t imagine someone following it all without having read the comics. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How else to recognize the small, but important bits of characterization? Like how Joker&amp;#39;s murdering Robin lead to this film&amp;#39;s more brutal Batman. Or bigger bits, like uber-villain Darkseid&amp;#39;s Omega sigil in Bruce&amp;#39;s apocalyptic vision and how Luthor&amp;#39;s ramblings in the finale reference Darkseid&amp;#39;s mother box technology. Reading between the lines, Luthor was little more than Renfield to Darkseid&amp;#39;s Dracula. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But relying on the viewer&amp;#39;s prior exposure to the characters invites preconceived notions of who these characters should be. And I can&amp;#39;t imagine anyone familiar with the Superman mythos getting behind this version of Luthor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we haven&amp;#39;t even covered the inanity of a script that sees Batman murder criminals and cause the same wanton destruction that so enraged him during the film&amp;#39;s opening sequence. Consider Batman, in his plane, leading a monster back to the city so he can retrieve a weapon that might kill it. Why not fly back, grab the weapon, then battle the monster in relative isolation? Because the movie isn&amp;#39;t interested in making sense. It&amp;#39;s too busy trying to build a franchise.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Play Motel (1979)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/play-motel-1979//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/play-motel-1979/</id><updated>2017-05-22</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/play-motel-1979/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/2ZyuabwsHwnSKAPR5yy1dOkft_OvODMZfgoDsMXDjALPMdzDJQsvw3S-slLMIMsZvcVYzSmMXhIkRH7QX-fAAa1xPohbDESRzKMNFrBlqGAjUX5JywHuzR0ef_JSJU_eh8ahEw=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I expected a sleazy giallo and I got a sleazy giallo. The catchy folk-rock theme song? That surprised me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, the film&amp;#39;s IMDb page has no trivia. No proof the American distributor already owned the song, spliced it into the soundtrack, and changed the film&amp;#39;s title. Nope, none at all. So, clearly, director Mario Gariazzo commissioned the theme, believing it a perfect tonal fit. If that&amp;#39;s true, it might merit an extra star.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film&amp;#39;s plot concerns a blackmail scam photographing wealthy marks in compromising positions in the titular establishment. Said positions feature lots of nudity and kinky behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, a black-gloved killer starts picking off victims peripheral to the scam. After the killer stashes a body in a parked car&amp;#39;s trunk, the car&amp;#39;s owners, a young couple, get involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the local police&amp;#39;s urging, the couple turns amateur sleuths, a questionable decision that sees the wife pose nude for a sleazy photographer while her husband waits in the car. When she&amp;#39;s inevitably captured and beaten, he&amp;#39;s laughably unconcerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all plays out as an over-the-top cross between Scooby-Doo and softcore porn. The end reveal is laugh-out-loud implausible, and the blackmail scenes are as explicit as the censors would allow. It&amp;#39;s pure exploitation in all it&amp;#39;s ridiculous glory and I&amp;#39;ll admit, it kept me entertained. If sleazy giallos are your thing, &lt;em&gt;Play Motel&lt;/em&gt; won&amp;#39;t disappoint.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Heat (1995)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/heat-1995//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/heat-1995/</id><updated>2017-05-15</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/heat-1995/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/7V1hPikvQPV9SeB6Rt9eQSKJerda-EY8MHOl7JTP8D8r7_wtWbmjjFgaTIgAIMkVu1IASE5eBKcGGCTA6--qp6xFIuII6Yv0S2-lexbvdsNhDWCsB3B7DagUtGgOYgmkK8yB4g=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tilt forward in my seat. My heels rise. The balls of my feet press into the floor. My hands clench tight and I realize I&amp;#39;m holding my breath. &lt;em&gt;Heat&lt;/em&gt; on the big screen is an experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve seen the film several times, yet the centerpiece shootout scene in the streets of downtown Los Angeles always elicits a visceral reaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boiled down, it&amp;#39;s a cops and robbers story. Robert De Niro leads a crew of professional thieves taking down a series of Los Angeles scores. Al Pacino leads the cops in pursuit. They&amp;#39;re archetypes in the Howard Hawks tradition—professions personified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, &lt;em&gt;Heat&lt;/em&gt; feels like a Hawks picture, right down to the underwritten female characters. But while Hawks romanticized the professional, &lt;em&gt;Heat&lt;/em&gt; shows us the cost of such a lifestyle. De Niro plans the heists with military precision, yet lives alone in a palatial seaside estate that could pass for vacant. Pacino hunts De Niro&amp;#39;s crew with obsessive fervor, even as his third marriage crumbles around him. Both performances feel larger than life yet intensely human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But back to the shootout. It makes the movie. The scene carries an immense gravitas because everything about it feels authentic. From the way the characters fire short bursts and reload, to their tactical movements, it all resonates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s not to say writer/director Michael Mann values authenticity over drama. His kinetic editing includes plenty of long and wide shots to establish movement and geography, immersing us in the scene. We don&amp;#39;t witness the gunfight we &lt;em&gt;experience&lt;/em&gt; it.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: A+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Free Fire (2016)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/free-fire-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/free-fire-2016/</id><updated>2017-05-08</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/free-fire-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/gCIe14X_ycptKUtFPj1mRS479ZGy7emqLvc1_gve1Ik48XW0eucK0GhxLoc0LRUPFroQJe07nOmcBn3iVvKGsadZgwnf6UERV_sFFH10vKNcPEQUH8ZYPRgXF8NPGgkbN5TFIw=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;You know that scene in crime movies, where a back-alley deal turns sour, resulting in a shootout? &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; stretches that into an entire movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set in 1978 Boston, the plot sees Cillian Murphy and Michael Smiley play IRA gang leaders buying guns from gang leaders played by Sharlto Copley and Armie Hammer. Brie Larson plays the intermediary. As the deal goes down, a grunt in one gang squabbles with a grunt the other gang, escalating into a full-fledged melee. Amid the flying bullets, the script weaves in some double-crosses. But honestly? The details escape me. &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; isn’t concerned with plot, but style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s got style to spare. The clothes, the hair, the set decoration—this movie does the impossible: it makes 1978 look cool. Do they give Academy Awards for that? They should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as much as I enjoyed the film’s look, the execution frustrated me. When the firefight breaks out, director Ben Wheatley offers no sense of geography. Folks shoot and scramble for cover but we have no sense of their placement in relation to one another. A few wide shots would have sufficed. Disorient characters, not the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it almost doesn’t matter. The dialog held my ear, and despite little plot or characterization, the cast—particularly Hammer—grabbed my attention through sheer charisma. &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; isn’t a good movie, but it’s as good an okay movie as you’ll find.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Raw (2016)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/raw-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/raw-2016/</id><updated>2017-05-01</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/raw-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/VmNSE_2S2EWCGmmdKeH3j1kg-A9nEgN7LArm6DWjFVAX8CKLppkKpwu4gnv9eMbDf2rFzVMpo3z8nV16iwdU1Rbw6tBc5EEzHMzTEZb1qJ98qyg69WfmbxgzI0d1uClQ1idMHg=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was fine with the cannibalism, but everything else irked me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Raw&lt;/em&gt; stars Garance Marillier as Justine, a young woman entering veterinarian college. On her first night, a hazing ritual sees masked men invade the dorms and force the freshmen to march and crawl—half dressed—across the campus. I couldn’t believe how the students reacted. No one asserted themselves or fought back. Maybe it’s a cultural thing (it’s a French film) but the herd imagery felt too pointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot kicks in when another hazing ritual forces Justine—a lifelong vegetarian—to try meat. This first taste unlocks an insatiable craving for human flesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface, &lt;em&gt;Raw&lt;/em&gt; is about Justine discovering and battling her cannibalistic urges. But writer/director Julia Ducournau positions cannibalism as a metaphor for escaping overbearing parents, discovering one’s sexuality, defending animal rights, and struggling to escape an older sibling’s shadow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juggling so many metaphors leaves little time for subtlety. It’s frustrating. Several scenes made me uncomfortable but said discomfort felt manipulative and obnoxious. Other scenes fall apart upon reflection. Some scenes do both. The night following her first taste of meat, Justine awakens covered in huge itchy welts with swaths of her skin peeling off in dry sheets. She yawns and goes back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, &lt;em&gt;Raw&lt;/em&gt; has its strengths. The cinematography grabbed my attention from the opening shot, and the performances convince to the degree the script allows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I just couldn’t buy it. For a film desperate to frame its genre elements as a serious conceit, too many details strained credibility. Justine as a cannibal? Sure. But a campus full of kids not glued to their smartphones? Preposterous.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Deadpool (2016)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/deadpool-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/deadpool-2016/</id><updated>2017-04-24</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/deadpool-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/8A6X_dIRLq2H0qzof8S796jLPeoVhO6K-im-Hm3b6s7rSbYEJIcf-6jg10i8YUu9A2nAxMRJehtYOVGY0jwnyjGlhQOBmrbyZ7M5SRpaXMtJRkPKz76lLZ6QeOkgKUdAtFaEnw=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beneath the crude jokes and over-the-top violence lurks a serious film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, not exactly, but &lt;em&gt;Deadpool&lt;/em&gt; works because it takes its source material seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan Reynolds stars as Wade Wilson a former special forces operative turned mercenary with a heart of gold. Just as he meets the girl of his dreams and finds the happiness that&amp;#39;s eluded him all his life, Wade learns he&amp;#39;s developed terminal cancer. A mysterious organization reaches out with the promise of a cure. Wade accepts, but the cure carries at a steep price. Presumed dead, Wade embarks on a mission of vengeance, complete with running color commentary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deadpool&lt;/em&gt; plays as a self-aware comic book film. The first time I watched it, I laughed so hard I missed most of the jokes. Besides the non-stop non-sequiturs, we get jokes about the plot, jokes about the other &lt;em&gt;X-Men&lt;/em&gt; films, and jokes about the limited budget. They&amp;#39;re not belittling the genre, just mining it for laughs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And these laughs come wrapped in a solid origin story. The film invests time in Wade and his relationships, making him more than a clown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the credit goes to Reynolds. His deadpan comedy proves the perfect match for the character&amp;#39;s gallows humor. He doesn&amp;#39;t just carry the film, he propels it along with his considerable charisma. This despite having essentially a voice-over role for most of his scenes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s said one can mark a genre&amp;#39;s end when it devolves into comedy, as &lt;em&gt;Abbott and Costello Meet Frankenstein (1948)&lt;/em&gt; ended the Universal Monster era. But that needn&amp;#39;t be the case. Rather than transplant genre characters into a comedic film, &lt;em&gt;Deadpool&lt;/em&gt; takes a genre film and adds liberal doses of comedy. It&amp;#39;s a subtle but important distinction. &lt;em&gt;Deadpool&lt;/em&gt; may be hilarious, but it&amp;#39;s a comic book movie first, and a comedy second.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Shock (1946)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/shock-1946//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/shock-1946/</id><updated>2017-04-17</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/shock-1946/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/6goXr9YlP7Fo6zg1X2R9Eabmn-iXHhtD_SzG8_NS529ejrdyrMOsr-84JqJD27uXP0AdxK7UX193n22YMpKuEEs6byE7ZARY8QQYfgGC04y3opLJEHFuTEP60qYCo1d4mJhJMQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;You won&amp;#39;t believe me when I tell you not to watch &lt;em&gt;Shock&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially if you&amp;#39;re a Vincent Price fan. The plot alone will convince you it&amp;#39;s worth watching. Price plays a psychiatrist who murders his wife. Unbeknownst to him, Anabel Shaw&amp;#39;s character witnesses the murder from her hotel room. The sight renders her catatonic and she falls under the care of—you guessed it—Price&amp;#39;s character. Better still: Shaw&amp;#39;s character spies the murder only after waking from an anxiety-laden nightmare, calling into question her reliability as a narrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could play as a cross between &lt;em&gt;Rebecca (1940)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Suspicion (1941)&lt;/em&gt;. Instead, it plays like &lt;em&gt;Double Indemnity (1944)&lt;/em&gt;. There&amp;#39;s no doubt Price&amp;#39;s character is guilty. He&amp;#39;s egged on by femme fatale Lynn Bari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can hear you saying to yourself, “That sounds interesting.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m here to tell you, it isn&amp;#39;t. Price doesn&amp;#39;t register as charming or sinister. He has zero chemistry with Bari, who herself fails to register as seductive or cunning. This renders the entire film rather boring, which as I&amp;#39;ve written before, is a film&amp;#39;s most unforgivable sin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;#39;s face it: if you&amp;#39;re a Vincent Price fan, you won&amp;#39;t believe me. Price played this sort of role so well in so many later pictures, you can&amp;#39;t fathom him falling flat. To those fans, I offer this condolence: if you make it through the film, you&amp;#39;ll see the ending, which I found so unintentionally funny I laughed aloud. So that&amp;#39;s something.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Breakfast at Tiffany's (1961)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/breakfast-at-tiffanys-1961//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/breakfast-at-tiffanys-1961/</id><updated>2017-04-10</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/breakfast-at-tiffanys-1961/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/5tMVCQoWpYy9bfXzSIoJ5yCNDbDSQ0Bt_i22ZWy_HDHZxAn7xpetQeXKUhgVEsTy0wrSf0Qmy7IhXz8fHirBCDye9Jv3Bg4csWLoxU_DLXcgZ8q0P69nIyr3hVNnZTkAZeE-Uw=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s Audrey Hepburn&amp;#39;s movie, but George Peppard deserves some credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His performance channels a young William Holden or Steve McQueen. Sure, seeing colonel John &amp;quot;Hannibal&amp;quot; Smith play a romantic lead will shock those of a certain age, but the jolt is short-lived. Peppard pulls off the role with aplomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts with his clothes. Okay—not really, but I love his wardrobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peppard plays Paul, a writer posing as a gigolo or vice versa. As the film opens, he&amp;#39;s moving into a converted New York brownstone apartment. There he meets Holly Golightly, a quirky socialite played by Hepburn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He falls for her. She for him. Complications ensue. What makes &lt;em&gt;Breakfast at Tiffany&amp;#39;s&lt;/em&gt; special is not the plot, but the characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul and Holly are both damaged people, skirting responsibility and commitment with a fear bordering on phobic. When Paul meets Holly he&amp;#39;s drawn by her fragile nature. The diminutive Hepburn looks the part. Paul longs to swoop in and save Holly. Unlike her other suitors, Paul&amp;#39;s in no position to save anyone, he&amp;#39;s just as wounded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patricia Neal plays the rich, married woman who pays Paul&amp;#39;s rent and keeps him in nice clothes. She makes an impression by underplaying her role. As does Buddy Ebsen as a lovesick figure from Holly&amp;#39;s shadowy past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s this willingness to embrace flawed characters—and not flawed in cute ways, but morally suspect ones—that makes &lt;em&gt;Breakfast at Tiffany&amp;#39;s&lt;/em&gt; stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, we get plenty of soft focus close-ups, Mickey Rooney as a racist caricature meant as comic relief, and a finale set in a rainy, yet well-lit alley, but &lt;em&gt;Breakfast at Tiffany&amp;#39;s&lt;/em&gt; transcends the tropes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest complaint lies with the ending. Holly isn&amp;#39;t a real person, she&amp;#39;s a ghost, drifting in and out of people&amp;#39;s lives, leaving an indelible impression. That Paul could end up with her doesn&amp;#39;t ring true. She&amp;#39;s not the girl you marry, she&amp;#39;s the girl you wonder about years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it&amp;#39;s a great film and Hepburn deserves the kudos showered upon her performance. But it works because Peppard wins us over too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>