<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'><title>Frank's Movie Log</title><subtitle>Quality reviews of films of questionable quality.</subtitle><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/feed.xml' rel='self' /><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com' /><updated>2017-01-30T20:37:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com</id><author><name>Frank Showalter</name></author><entry><title>79. Men Are Such Fools (1938)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/men-are-such-fools-1938//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/men-are-such-fools-1938/</id><updated>2017-01-30</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/men-are-such-fools-1938/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/3FPwrWzQNStn2lXQpbglpZstCqPhhoxtLlX2deGZeMRTD7NGhKANft7glVrrgEO3O1qQQwicVHWz9KxxXuTYsulEDDLfdtarMDMDbjtJK99aJZ9O6UrM7TcaoklxZRFn2i2SAQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two-piece bathing suit isn’t worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, it’s good for a laugh. Seeing Humphrey Bogart shed his terry cloth trench coat to reveal a deep-cut two-piece is comedy gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the movie surrounding this scene? I watched it some years back and thought it awful. Revisiting it for this review reaffirmed my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Priscilla Lane stars as Linda, a secretary in an advertising agency who dreams of climbing the corporate ladder and drawing a salary instead of wages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as her career takes off, she marries Jimmy, played by Wayne Morris. Jimmy is an ex-footballer from Princeton turned ad-man. When Linda works overtime and misses the big Princeton football game, Jimmy demands Linda quit her job. Linda agrees, and several months later they’ve settled into a bland suburban existence with Linda playing the role of dutiful housewife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still ambitious, Linda arranges a promising business venture for Jimmy, but Jimmy turns it down. Furious, Linda leaves Jimmy and resumes her career. Soon, she’s near the top of the ladder, working long nights alongside fellow advertising executive Harry, played by Bogart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despondent, Jimmy throws himself into his work and achieves a large measure of success. As Harry makes his feelings for Linda clear, Linda realizes she’ll have to choose between Harry and Jimmy. She chooses poorly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Romantic comedies require us to like at least one of the leads. In &lt;em&gt;Men Are Such Fools&lt;/em&gt;, I loathed them both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jimmy displays no regard for Linda’s dreams and ambitions, behaving as though he’s entitled to her attention and affection. When Linda cancels a dinner date with Jimmy to sell her boss on an ad campaign, Jimmy crashes the meeting. When a senior executive talks to Linda at a party, Jimmy sulks in a corner rather than join in the conversation. And don’t forget Linda&amp;#39;s near-unforgivable crime of missing the Princeton game with Jimmy and his fraternity buddies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jimmy’s so chauvinistic it’s almost comical. But everyone in the film acts as though his behavior is acceptable. They laugh and chalk it up to young love. That’s when you realize it’s not Jimmy who’s supposed to be funny, but Linda for prioritizing her career over a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings us to Linda, who I loathed even more than Jimmy. You see, she doesn’t endure his behavior, she encourages it. Consider how Jimmy gets her to marry him. They’re at a pool party thrown by one of Linda’s bosses. Linda’s talking to a high level executive. Furious that Linda would dare talk to another man, Jimmy stalks across the party, grabs Linda, pulls her into the pool and demands she marry him. When Linda says no, he pushes her head under water. He waits a beat, then lets her up. As Linda gasps for air, Jimmy repeats his demand. Again she says no. Back under she goes. This repeats—in full view of the guests, most of whom are Linda&amp;#39;s superiors at work—until Linda agrees. And when she does, it’s not with resentment, but with a doe-eyed smile full of adoration for this man who just bullied her into marrying him. Now, I ask you, who’s worse: the ass or the woman who reinforces the behavior?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was going to write something about the ending, and how it lacks a clear message, leaving you wondering just what the film was trying to say, but why bother? There’s only one way to enjoy &lt;em&gt;Men Are Such Fools&lt;/em&gt;: 1. Start the movie. 2. Fast-forward to Bogart’s introduction. 3. Laugh at his outfit. 4. Turn off the movie. Don’t say I didn’t warn you.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>78. Green Room (2015)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/green-room-2015//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/green-room-2015/</id><updated>2017-01-23</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/green-room-2015/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/hayyDsBD5mYl1ENR33mRoFHxFiDsfymKujeodQff-O8iWjBZpcMcpeKNSFcPXpjYZTyzjeHjhlxyXRlJEu65En1Egpzibw8QY3K4lk8bdwyTrRrcqEvdJAWMzEh_Pvva0TU46Q=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Watching &lt;em&gt;Green Room&lt;/em&gt;, I caught myself holding my breath. Twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story concerns a college-aged punk rock band who accept a gig at an out-of-the-way club in the Pacific Northwest. I&amp;#39;ll reveal no more, lest I spoil how writer/director Jeremy Saulnier ratchets up the tension by raising the stakes with each plot twist. Suffice it to say, things get very bad, very fast for the young band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Green Room&lt;/em&gt; is Saulnier&amp;#39;s third film. His debut, &lt;em&gt;Murder Party (2007)&lt;/em&gt;, was a flawed but entertaining black comedy. His follow-up, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/blue-ruin-2013/&quot;&gt;Blue Ruin (2013)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, was a near-perfect revenge thriller. With &lt;em&gt;Green Room&lt;/em&gt;, he delivers one of the more intense horror films I&amp;#39;ve seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the moment the band turns into the club&amp;#39;s parking lot, we feel uneasy. A palpable sense of menace hangs in the air. It grows as the kids make their way inside the club. By the time they take the stage, it&amp;#39;s overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesser horror films force their characters to behave in service of the plot. We spend such films yelling “Get out of the house!” or something similar at the idiots on screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Green Room&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;#39;t do this. Saulnier&amp;#39;s characters behave true to their established personalities. The kids sense something&amp;#39;s off, but they stay anyway. In part because they&amp;#39;re desperate for cash, but more so because they love playing music, and the film conveys the transcendent joy they experience on stage. Later, when things turn bad, the kids continue to react in a plausible and relatable manner. They don&amp;#39;t panic or fall for obvious traps. They play it smart. Except—and here lies the film&amp;#39;s genius—Saulnier paints his villains even smarter. They don&amp;#39;t panic or make stupid mistakes either. It&amp;#39;s all so refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s also gruesome. Saulnier punctuates his plot twists with sudden, brutal bursts of violence driven home with convincing practical effects. It&amp;#39;s not a gore-fest, but it&amp;#39;s not for the squeamish either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s because Saulnier makes sure we care about his characters. Good effects suspend disbelief but good storytelling generates empathy. Saulnier&amp;#39;s prior efforts demonstrated a knack for creating flawed but endearing protagonists and quickly fleshing them out without resorting to awkward exposition or trite visuals. In &lt;em&gt;Green Room&lt;/em&gt;, he gives us a whole band full. He even avoids gender stereotypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that I have not mentioned the cast. They&amp;#39;re all convincing and engaging, but discussing specific performances, or even the casting itself would invite spoilers. That said, I&amp;#39;ll make one exception since the film&amp;#39;s promotional artwork includes him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How I envy the festival audiences who went in knowing little more than the film&amp;#39;s title and director. Patrick Stewart&amp;#39;s reveal as a neo-Nazi gang leader must have been a terrific surprise. He&amp;#39;s an unconventional choice, but he pulls off the part. Granted, he&amp;#39;s not as scary as say, Ben Kingsley in &lt;em&gt;Sexy Beast (2000)&lt;/em&gt; or Stacy Keach in &lt;em&gt;American History X (1998)&lt;/em&gt;, but maybe that&amp;#39;s a good thing. &lt;em&gt;Green Room&lt;/em&gt; is intense enough.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>77. The Big Stampede (1932)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-big-stampede-1932//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-big-stampede-1932/</id><updated>2017-01-16</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-big-stampede-1932/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/l-PM7O98fLUrZmrHCEiHlxJdDh4-4VFo_o3nWx1vfbiOjmWA1VeMZIbBfWFrBscKjMTZvI_UGAHW9OfkVXeY4ePiaBxsdXwg2oJ_3XpohBI0BY8DhcYh4ENGUSGzDLiNpsZdWA=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Big Stampede&lt;/em&gt; has little to recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the third production, following &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/ride-him-cowboy-1932/&quot;&gt;Ride Him, Cowboy (1932)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, under a six-picture contract John Wayne signed with Warner Bros. It&amp;#39;s a remake of &lt;em&gt;The Land Beyond the Law (1927)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Warner Bros. acquired First National Pictures a few years prior, they inherited the rights to several popular silent westerns starring Ken Maynard. These were A-list productions showcasing Maynard&amp;#39;s impressive stunt work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warner Bros. sought to remake the Maynard silents with sound, recycling as much action footage as possible, reshooting only the close-ups and interiors. They just needed an actor who matched Maynard&amp;#39;s build. Enter Wayne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except, &lt;em&gt;The Big Stampede&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;#39;t offer much action. Wayne plays John Steele, a deputy lawman sent to clean up the New Mexico territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He arrives in town and poses as a drunken drifter while sizing up local cattle baron Sam Crew. Then John is on the frontier, befriending a wagon train leader named Cal and making eyes at Cal&amp;#39;s niece Ginger. Then the train comes under attack from Sam Crew&amp;#39;s gang. To apprehend the gang, John recruits Sonora Joe, a Mexican bandit who first tries to rustle the wagon train&amp;#39;s cattle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this sounds disjointed, then I have conveyed the sense of watching this film. The script abandons plot threads with no regard for logic or continuity. It also contains an inordinate number of speaking parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which begs the question: If the point of remaking the Maynard films was to save money, why shoot such a complex and talky script? Casting and shooting so much new footage cost time and money. The only memorable bit of recycled footage is the titular stampede, which provides the film&amp;#39;s climax. The wide shots of rampaging cattle and runaway wagons impress. The spliced in close-ups of Wayne shouting things like “Hoo-ah!” do not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Wayne, like much of the cast, he appears ill at ease. His scenes with Mae Madison, who plays Ginger, are stiff and awkward. Only Luis Alberni, who plays Sonora Joe, acquits himself well; though hardly well enough to recommend this dull mess.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>76. Ocean's Thirteen (2007)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/oceans-thirteen-2007//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/oceans-thirteen-2007/</id><updated>2017-01-09</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/oceans-thirteen-2007/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/N1GXNivZJRmLglTe06LVDoQAEn4eYPzkQUlYco-FITaalte9snfo0fofGvggjw3MIJkOF8cjffsN5c12GkBKXEa8cgxfpkPXByyNcP6trSTVnVRthNlEQl8ZwLZJm9GFk5tudw=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ocean&amp;#39;s Thirteen&lt;/em&gt; resurrects the caper picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a caper? It&amp;#39;s a film centered on an elaborate ruse perpetrated by lovable rogues. The genre peaked with &lt;em&gt;The Sting (1973)&lt;/em&gt;, then gave way to the grittier heist genre. But while heists get bloody, capers are rarely life-and-death scenarios. Today, the caper picture lies largely forgotten, save the occasional farcical comedy. But director Steven Soderbergh proves the old genre has legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This film&amp;#39;s lovable rogues come together to avenge their mentor (Elliott Gould) who&amp;#39;s been double-crossed by casino mogul Willy Bank (Al Pacino).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get even, the group plans to rob Bank&amp;#39;s casino. The film&amp;#39;s joy lies in how they go about it. The casino&amp;#39;s security system offers only a three-and-a-half minute window. To circumvent this obstacle, the group will rig the games to pay out to everyone. The group needn&amp;#39;t win, just for the casino to lose. So, for three-and-a-half minutes, everybody wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, folks don&amp;#39;t leave when they&amp;#39;re running hot and if they stay, they&amp;#39;ll just lose back their winnings. The thieves&amp;#39; solution to this dilemma provides another of the film&amp;#39;s quirky surprises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lesser film might drag under such plotting, but &lt;em&gt;Ocean&amp;#39;s Thirteen&lt;/em&gt; breezes along, thanks to its all-star cast. Opposite Pacino, George Clooney and Brad Pitt star as the lead thieves with Matt Damon as their de facto lieutenant. Bernie Mac, Don Cheadle, Casey Affleck, Scott Caan, Carl Reiner, and Eddie Izzard round out the crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The performers relish the script&amp;#39;s rapid-fire dialogue. Peppered with invented slang and meta references, it&amp;#39;s the film&amp;#39;s biggest treat, and holds up to repeat viewings. The first scene between Clooney and Pacino, with Clooney echoing Pacino&amp;#39;s dialog from &lt;em&gt;The Godfather (1972)&lt;/em&gt; always makes me smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my favorite scene is audacious. It opens with Pitt and Clooney strolling along the Las Vegas Strip, reminiscing. They stop and Clooney gestures off-camera, saying, “I remember when this used to be the Dunes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pitt looks down the street, “The Sands was there, and the Desert Inn…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut to a close-up. Both men stand lost in their memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clooney says, “They built them a lot smaller back then.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pitt, still looking where The Sands once stood, says, almost to himself, “They seemed pretty big.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another beat, then Clooney says, “Towns change,” and Soderbergh cuts to a wide shot reveal of the Bellagio dwarfing Clooney and Pitt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this scene. Such self-indulgence should elicit a groan, but between the crackerjack editing and sheer charisma of his stars, Soderbergh gets away with it. It&amp;#39;s a caper-within-a-caper and I fall for it every viewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: A-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>75. Christmas Evil (1980)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/christmas-evil-1980//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/christmas-evil-1980/</id><updated>2017-01-02</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/christmas-evil-1980/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/W4n2LDAivPJHkQwsVwtvBLtsDJbv21Qdlcj7d51hbsdsiLzulgwy6__BQutqCKcqU9KKOpXbWoARqY4Y-eYS7NfroX9MgkdA1YFAMHCHYeLlBakPx1wb792KLYf0GRgi8kAu5A=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christmas Evil&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;#39;t the sleazy Santa slasher you&amp;#39;d expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film opens on Christmas Eve. A young boy named Harry wanders downstairs and spies his father, dressed as Santa, fondling his half-naked mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I know, I said the film wasn&amp;#39;t sleazy. Stay with me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward thirty years and Harry (now played by Brandon Maggart) has developed an obsession with Santa. His shabby apartment overflows with Christmas knick-knacks and Santa artwork. He spies on the neighborhood children and catalogs their activities in large tomes dedicated to the naughty and nice. He even works in a dingy toy factory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Christmas Eve night, Harry dons his handmade Santa costume. At first, he&amp;#39;s overjoyed as he delivers toys to children in a mental hospital. But then his attention turns to the naughty and his mood darkens. A chance confrontation turns violent and bloody. Harry flees, unsure what went wrong. He finds solace in a neighborhood Christmas party where he&amp;#39;s the delight of the local children. But soon he&amp;#39;s alone again, and the high of the party gives way to another dangerous low. More violence follows, spiraling out of control and leading to an outrageous finale that I dare not reveal, but which casts the film as a bittersweet fable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admit, I went in expecting a cheesy bit of exploitation but I came out impressed. I liked the film&amp;#39;s production. There&amp;#39;s nary a soundstage in sight. Everything is location-based, including the New Jersey exteriors. The worn, lived-in interiors give the film a documentary veneer and added authenticity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most of all, I liked the film&amp;#39;s willingness  to tell a different kind of story. It hit me during the third act, which sees Harry fleeing a mob of torch-wielding neighbors, that writer/director Lewis Jackson wasn&amp;#39;t making a slasher picture at all, he was making a monster movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the similarities to &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein (1931)&lt;/em&gt;. Both serve as cautionary tales. &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt; warned against playing God. &lt;em&gt;Christmas Evil&lt;/em&gt; warns against playing Santa. It&amp;#39;s a laughable notion until you consider it from a child&amp;#39;s perspective. Moral absolutes like naughty and nice don&amp;#39;t work in the adult world, but try explaining that to a child. The film commits to this premise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end, Maggart&amp;#39;s performance makes the film. His character is very much a child trapped in a middle-aged body, and Maggart convinces. The audience I saw the film with offered no snarky chuckles or giggles; they sat transfixed. Much as in &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt;, we come to care about this misunderstood monster. The script helps by ensuring Harry never harms a child. It reserves Harry&amp;#39;s murderous outbursts for the film&amp;#39;s real creeps: the other adults. It&amp;#39;s an important detail that lets the film earn its ending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I think about &lt;em&gt;Christmas Evil&lt;/em&gt;, the more I admire it. Will it hold up to repeat viewings? I&amp;#39;ll let you know next Christmas.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>74. Jack Frost (1997)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/jack-frost-1997//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/jack-frost-1997/</id><updated>2016-12-26</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/jack-frost-1997/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/sDgsisYLTBNCXNTYRP_8YyW1QO2Y2F38NTQO9YUd_iNl42SVTrWRxPggfw078QizjMa-ks4GLJyrDzauoLzJAuDJHCpsoQopIUrgSlMfO0NlSHGtYvMNRXVF5CRdcHHFBPezew=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jack Frost&lt;/em&gt; is bad, even by “movie about a killer snowman” standards. And those are low standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot concerns—well, I’ve already mentioned the killer snowman, yes? Then, for most readers, I have described the plot in sufficient detail. For those still curious, the film opens with Federal agents transporting a serial killer (named Jack Frost, of course) to his execution. The icy conditions cause the paddy wagon to collide with a top-secret government tanker truck. The truck’s contents spray out, melting the killer&amp;#39;s skin and bones. His liquid remains merge with the snow, granting him a second life as a snowman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a reasonable setup. The problem lies in the execution. Had the film played as a straight horror whose antagonist happens to be a snowman, it might have worked. Just imagine the absurdist humor in swapping Michael Myers for a snowman in &lt;em&gt;Halloween (1978)&lt;/em&gt;. But &lt;em&gt;Jack Frost&lt;/em&gt; drowns in a sea of camera winks and awkward comedy bits. It’s not a horror film, it’s a manufactured attempt at “so-bad-it’s-good” schlock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that approach to work, the titular killer snowman needs to be an anti-hero; someone we can perversely root for as he offs the self-centered jerk taking up two parking spaces during the holiday rush, the obnoxious boss who overworks his employees on Christmas Eve, and yes, even the ungrateful kid who’s unhappy with his gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jack Frost&lt;/em&gt; offers no such vicarious thrills. The serial killer turned snowman is out to fulfill a petty revenge pact against the small-town sheriff who arrested him. It’s an uninspired plot for an uninspired film that’s neither scary nor funny; and thus, not worth your time.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>73. Straw Dogs (1971)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/straw-dogs-1971//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/straw-dogs-1971/</id><updated>2016-12-19</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/straw-dogs-1971/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ypTOnjofVKo1mS6s5IGRxWK0rCGIoACFxoTqZk-laP8hnsVfBlsPNZkacAppZ1oqS3biEWAnzRPzsZjeMmZV2cLDTZQ7e_vZuIsFxkLYW7sTqEbq7L76oSnmhYcmsoawq1BIDQ=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sam Peckinpah&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Straw Dogs&lt;/em&gt; is an ugly, brutal, nihilistic, gut-punch of a horror film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horror fans will recognize the plot. A young couple moves to a small, isolated village where they hope to renovate an old house. They ignore repeated warnings to leave and bad things happen, culminating in the young lovers barricading themselves in their home, fighting to keep an unspeakable evil from gaining entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference is in the details. &lt;em&gt;Straw Dogs&lt;/em&gt; takes place in an English village; the quaint sort you see in romantic comedies. But instead of charming, quirky characters, the residents of this hamlet are leering, hard-drinking thugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Into this rural jungle comes mild-mannered American mathematician David (Dustin Hoffman) and his attractive wife Amy (Susan George). They&amp;#39;re fleeing some vague unrest in America and the village is her childhood home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we meet David and Amy, we get our first indication the film will stray from the formula. They aren&amp;#39;t the typical idyllic couple thrust into danger. David&amp;#39;s condescending manner alienates the few locals who would befriend him but he&amp;#39;s too self-absorbed to notice. His intellectual snobbery leads him to treat Amy like a child. Amy&amp;#39;s petulant responses only reinforce the behavior. Their bickering rings true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot kicks in when some local men, including a former boyfriend of Amy&amp;#39;s, named Charlie, worm their way into a job repairing the couple&amp;#39;s garage roof. The men drag out the work. They ogle Amy. One sneaks into the house and steals a pair of Amy&amp;#39;s panties, which he later flaunts at the pub. Things reach a tipping point when David and Amy discover their cat hung in their bedroom closet. When David proves reluctant to confront the men, Amy presses the issue. David snaps at her. She calls him a coward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This conflict between David and Amy sets up the film&amp;#39;s most controversial scene: Charlie raping Amy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a hard scene to watch. I&amp;#39;ve seen the film multiple times, and it doesn&amp;#39;t get any easier. At first, Amy screams and fights back. Charlie slaps her and she crumbles to the floor in slow motion. Resigned to her fate, Amy stops fighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Peckinpah twists the knife. He quick cuts between the present and Amy&amp;#39;s intimate memories of David. Amy&amp;#39;s anger toward David swirls and churns inside her. Her resignation turns to passion as she turns from victim to betrayer and embraces her former lover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, as Amy and Charlie lay entwined, Peckinpah goes for the jugular. One of Charlie&amp;#39;s goon friends enters, holding a shotgun. With some reluctance, Charlie steps aside and watches his friend force himself on Amy at gunpoint. Amy&amp;#39;s shrieks surround us as her violation is absolute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Controversial? Absolutely. Gratuitous? No. The scene is horrifying but necessary. It drives an unspoken wedge between David and Amy, setting up the rest of the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finale sees Charlie and gang laying siege to David and Amy&amp;#39;s house. It&amp;#39;s a familiar scene in horror films; the men could just as easily be zombies or other monsters, and Peckinpah uses lots of low-angle shots and foggy backlighting. But the real horror isn&amp;#39;t what&amp;#39;s trying to get in, it&amp;#39;s what&amp;#39;s coming out between David and Amy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A series of plot-driven coincidences have led to David sheltering a mentally challenged man in the couple&amp;#39;s attic. The mob outside believes this man murdered a local girl earlier that evening. When the attacks start, Amy urges David to acquiesce to the mob&amp;#39;s demands and turn the man over, but David refuses. Bitter that David will stand up for a stranger but not her, Amy refuses to help. This proves the turning point in their relationship. Later, when Amy&amp;#39;s in trouble, she yells for Charlie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s easy to dismiss &lt;em&gt;Straw Dogs&lt;/em&gt; as misogynistic, but that&amp;#39;s short-sighted. This film hates everyone. While Amy is assaulted, David&amp;#39;s out hunting with the very men who attack her. Of course, the trip was just a ruse to lure him away, but David only accepted to buddy-up with alpha-male Charlie. David would label himself a pacifist but behaves as a sycophant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that goes to what makes the film special. It&amp;#39;s violent, sure, but it&amp;#39;s not the violence that stays with you. Rather, it&amp;#39;s the bleak reflection of human nature. Horror movies tend to paint their protagonists as bland, cookie-cutter stereotypes; their misfortune born out of some trespass or bad luck. Not here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The horror of &lt;em&gt;Straw Dogs&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;#39;t that it could &lt;em&gt;happen&lt;/em&gt; to us, it&amp;#39;s that the characters could &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; us. By committing to its bleak vision the film projects authority. By making its protagonists monsters themselves, the film transcends the exploitation genre. It may not be entertaining in the conventional sense, but every viewing stays with me for days. I may not like what &lt;em&gt;Straw Dogs&lt;/em&gt; is saying, but I can&amp;#39;t deny its impact.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: A+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>72. The Getaway (1972)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-getaway-1972//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/the-getaway-1972/</id><updated>2016-12-05</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/the-getaway-1972/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/3H45oFIj7vXiyg8k4jQ31wblut4vMmI4hmwq_h-b17Q6U78pSN1GXsntFrNmU-QCpQNQnGj_9-Pi=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Getaway&lt;/em&gt; is a slick bit of neo-noir exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve McQueen stars as Doc McCoy, an incarcerated bank robber. The opening credit sequence--cut to the staccato rhythm of an industrial loom--hammers home the hellish, regimented existence of prison life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doc finds himself near breaking after his expected parole is denied. When his wife Carol (Ali McGraw) visits him in jail, Doc cuts the visit short, telling her to contact a man named Beynon and tell him “I&amp;#39;m for sale. His price.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beynon (Ben Johnson) is a greasy operator who sits on the parole board. He pulls some strings and Doc is paroled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doc&amp;#39;s reunion with Carol is a touch of genuine sweetness that transcends the film&amp;#39;s exploitative nature. The near-wordless scenes convey the sudden change in their lives. Reunited, the two experience a brief respite before Doc meets with Beynon to repay his debt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job is a local bank. Beynon has already picked the crew. Doc would rather use his own guys, but Beynon won&amp;#39;t budge. With no leverage, Doc agrees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The robbery, of course, goes wrong. One of Beynon&amp;#39;s guys panics. Things get bloody. In his trademark fashion, director Sam Peckinpah renders each fatality in graphic slow motion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirty minutes into the film, the real story begins. Doc and Carol head for Mexico with the loot. The law and Beynon&amp;#39;s gang pursue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love how the film avoids painting Doc as a hero. He kills without hesitation. There&amp;#39;s even a rough scene where smacks Carol. And yet, McQueen&amp;#39;s performance engenders sympathy. You sense Doc&amp;#39;s desire to be a better man but fear he&amp;#39;ll lose the battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s part of the film&amp;#39;s overall sense of dread. In pursuit of Doc, one of Beynon&amp;#39;s gang takes a husband and wife hostage. The wife falls for their captor, degrading herself and humiliating her husband. As Doc and Carol flee, you&amp;#39;re sure they won&amp;#39;t make it. Even when they escape, you&amp;#39;re certain the next close-call will be their last. Chalk that up to Peckinpah&amp;#39;s commitment to grounding the film in a plausible reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sets look worn and dusty. The characters glisten with a perpetual sheen of sweat from the oppressive Texas heat. They eat greasy cheeseburgers, hole up in dingy motels, and travel in oversized cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And those cars make for gripping chase scenes. As characters panic, oversteer, fishtail, and crash, you appreciate the challenge of controlling such large vehicles at high speeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the film&amp;#39;s highlight belongs to an on-foot chase. After a con-man switches locker keys with Carol and snags the loot, Doc engages in a desperate pursuit through a crowded train station. The dialog-free sequence crackles with tension and echoes vintage Hitchcock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scenes like this, along with McQueen&amp;#39;s charisma and Peckinpah&amp;#39;s stylish editing help gloss over the clunky plot. &lt;em&gt;The Getaway&lt;/em&gt; may be little more than pulp, but it&amp;#39;s damn entertaining.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>71. Doctor Strange (2016)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/doctor-strange-2016//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/doctor-strange-2016/</id><updated>2016-11-28</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/doctor-strange-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Fy7FUeNQVfMdLwIj_JHquTJoXwp0DquRwvPVURemABSX3aw-9se2e0xZrv-idwOmD1gjJ8T39OCv=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; offers ephemeral entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set in the Marvel cinematic universe, the film stars Benedict Cumberbatch as Stephen Strange, a hotshot neurosurgeon. After a car accident cripples his hands, Strange’s desperate search for a miracle cure leads him to Nepal. There he meets The Ancient One, played by Tilda Swinton, who trains him in the mystic arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strange proves himself an exceptional student. Good thing, as he’s soon under attack from Kaecilius, the Ancient One’s former star pupil. Kaecilius now serves Dormammu, an ancient entity from the Dark Dimension. Soon, Strange is all that stands between Earth and a horrible (but not well explained) fate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen this story before in countless martial arts films. An acolyte approaches a great master for training, excels against the odds, then clashes with the master’s once favorite student. This film merely substitutes magic for kung-fu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem lies in the homogenized and watered-down execution. Strange’s arc revolves around him overcoming his arrogance. But the film paints him as a brilliant surgeon far ahead of his colleagues. Is that arrogance? Why not paint Strange as a real monster? The film doesn’t seem comfortable making Strange too unlikable. Thus, Cumberbatch’s Strange plays as a less fun version of Robert Downey Jr.’s Tony Stark from the &lt;em&gt;Iron Man&lt;/em&gt; films. The resulting character feels thin and flat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This extends to the villains. Mads Mikkelsen can play a great bad guy but fails to register as Kaecilius. The script gives him no edge. We’ve seen the disgruntled student archetype in countless films before, and &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt; offers nothing new. Even Dormammu, who should rank among the most horrific villains in the Marvel oeuvre, fails to terrify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The special effects also fail to connect. We see cities twisting and folding upon themselves like Rubik’s Cubes, but the film fails to surround these scenes with a compelling story. Watching New York transform into an M.C. Escher style visage is impressive, but not engaging. The effects should serve the story, not substitute for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds like I hated the film. I did not. Though I would have preferred his native British accent, I enjoyed Cumberbatch’s performance. The real star, however, is Tilda Swinton. She takes a throw-away archetype and delivers the film’s most memorable character. And as someone who grew up reading the comics, I loved seeing the sentient Cloak of Levitation, even if it was little more than comic relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, after the obligatory post-credit sequence, I left the theater impressed with &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt;. But in retrospect, I could remember images in the film, but none of my feelings upon seeing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a reoccurring effect in the film where characters enter the Astral Plane. Their ethereal bodies float in the air and pass through solid objects. If they try hard enough, they can bump walls or knock things over. It’s an apt enough metaphor for the film. It looks good, but it’s hollow inside and struggles to connect. When you try to grab it, you discover there’s nothing there.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>70. Sagebrush Trail (1933)</title><link href='https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/sagebrush-trail-1933//' /><id>https://www.franksmovielog.com/reviews/sagebrush-trail-1933/</id><updated>2016-11-21</updated><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/sagebrush-trail-1933/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/t-YlFZzOBSK4QJXy7XZhfQhiwqqlYvXoJF85WXSfOPlWXg3hHjw5PbUBFp96zepLn2A6HWSVaxG3=w1000-l75-rj&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The underwater scenes in &lt;em&gt;Sagebrush Trail&lt;/em&gt; belie its shoestring budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those scenes come early. John Wayne plays a fugitive named John (of course) stowed away aboard a freight train. As the train pulls into the station, lawmen are waiting. After some cat and mouse, John hops a horse and flees into the countryside. The lawmen pursue. John dead-ends at a lake, dismounts, and dives into the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see John underwater, breathing through a reed. It&amp;#39;s not a special effect. I&amp;#39;m not sure how they shot these scenes, but that&amp;#39;s Wayne underwater, breathing through a stick in what looks like a lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After eluding the lawmen, who believe him dead, John surfaces and encounters a gunslinger. The gunslinger, recognizing a fellow desperado, introduces himself as Jones and invites John to join an outlaw gang. John accepts and he and Jones become fast-friends and rivals for the local shopgirl, Sally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, John&amp;#39;s not really a bad guy. He passes notes to Sally warning her of the gang&amp;#39;s intentions. And of course, it was Jones who committed the crime pinned on John. And of course, John doesn&amp;#39;t discover this until the second act&amp;#39;s end. But you know what? I didn&amp;#39;t mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sagebrush Trail&lt;/em&gt; may suffer from predictable plotting, stilted dialog, and fight scenes where the participants punch each other&amp;#39;s shoulders, but I still enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the aforementioned underwater scenes, I liked the location photography and wipe transitions. And the script&amp;#39;s making Jones a flawed but likable character was a nice touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most of all, I liked Wayne. This was his second production for Monogram Pictures, after &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/riders-of-destiny-1933/&quot;&gt;Riders of Destiny (1933)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Though Wayne struggles with the romantic comedy scenes, he&amp;#39;s making strides as a performer. More than ever before, we see flashes of his famous Duke persona. And judging by the underwater scenes, he&amp;#39;s doing some of his own stunts to boot.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade: C-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>